<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/NumericalData/CDPP-Archive/MMS-2/Fields/SCM/MMS_SCM_2_L2_BPSD_SLOW</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>MMS-2 SCM Search Coil Magnetometer Level-2 Onboard Slow Survey Power Spectral Density (CDF)</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/362n-zhyq</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-07-07T14:05:23Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This data sets contains  MMS-2 SCM (search coil magnetometer) calibrated  power spectral density of Magnetic field fluctuations computed by onboard FFTs by the Digital Signal Processor (DSP) from SCM waveforms during slow survey modes between 0 and 8192 Hz. Their nominal time resolution is 16 s, and nominal number of frequency channels is 56 with logarithmic frequency scale.
This product is computed in space from individual components that are not synchronized to the 1 second pulse. Therefore, the timing between channels can be inaccurate by a fraction of a second. The samples times are interval start times taken from the x component.
- SCM1 (spin plane component, -x SCM sensor) component magnetic power spectral density.
- SCM3 (spin axis component, -y SCM sensor) component magnetic power spectral density.
- Omni-directional magnetic power spectral density: square root of the sum of the squares of 2 components (SCM1 and SCM3).</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
        SCM data, as a data set of the MMS-SMART data products, are open to all scientists and the public (Users).
Users should contact the MMS-SMART Principal Investigator (PI) J. L. Burch and O. Le Contel the co-investigator (coI) of the SCM instrument to consult on the appropriate use of instrument data.
Users should acknowledge the sources of data used in all publications, presentations, and reports.
Please send information on the use of these data to:
- PI: J. L. Burch [jburch@swri.edu]
- co-I: O. Le Contel [olivier.lecontel@lpp.polytechnique.fr]
We suggest to add the following lines into the acknowledgments:
The authors acknowledge NASA, CNES (Centre National d'Etudes Spatiales) and, CNRS (Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique) for their support to the MMS/SCM team and the CDPP (Centre de Données de la Physique des Plasmas) for the distribution of the MMS/SCM data.
and if PI/coI are not part of the publication list, then we suggest to add Specifically, we acknowledge J. L. Burch for use of data from the MMS-SMART mission, O. Le Contel and the late A. Roux for use of SCM data.
For more informations about data rights and rules, see https://lasp.colorado.edu/mms/sdc/public/about/
The following paper should also be used to reference:
Le Contel O., Leroy P., Roux A., Coillot C., Alison D., Bouabdellah A., Mirioni L., Meslier L., Galic A., Vassal M. C., Torbert R. B., Needell J., Rau D., Dors I., Ergun R. E., Westfall J., Summers D., Wallace J., Magnes W., Valavanoglou A., Olsson G., Chutter M., Macri J., Myers S., Turco S., Nolin J., Bodet D., Rowe K., Tanguy M., De la Porte B., The Search-Coil Magnetometer for MMS, Space Science Reviews 199 (1) 257-282 (2016)	  
	  </Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/James.L.Burch</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Olivier.Le.Contel</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Malik.Mansour</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Dominique.Alison</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Laurent.Mirioni</PersonID>
        <Role>DataProducer</Role>
      </Contact>            
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://cdpp-archive.cnes.fr</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>CDF</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/MMS-2/Fields/SCM</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2015-03-17T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2021-10-31T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.RadiationBelt</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.EquatorialRegion</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Plasmasphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>MMS-2 SCM1 component  Onboard Slow Survey  magnetic power spectral  density</Name>
      <Description>MMS-2 SCM1 component Onboard Slow Survey magnetic power spectral  density (spin plane component, -x SCM sensor)</Description>
      <Units>nT^2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>1.0e-18&gt;T^2 Hz^-1</UnitsConversion>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <Qualifier>Spectral</Qualifier>
        <Qualifier>Component.I</Qualifier>
        <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <Low>0</Low>
          <High>8192</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>MMS-2 SCM3 component   Onboard Slow Survey magnetic power spectral  density</Name>
      <Description>MMS-2 SCM3 component Onboard Slow Survey magnetic power spectral  density (spin axis component, -y SCM sensor)</Description>
      <Units>nT^2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>1.0e-18&gt;T^2 Hz^-1</UnitsConversion>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <Qualifier>Spectral</Qualifier>
        <Qualifier>Component.J</Qualifier>
        <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <Low>0</Low>
          <High>8192</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>MMS-2 SCM omni-directional   Onboard Slow Survey magnetic power spectral  density</Name>
      <Description>MMS-2 SCM Omni-directional magnetic power spectral density: square root of the sum of the squares of 2 components (SCM1 and SCM3).</Description>
      <Units>nT^2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>1.0e-18&gt;T^2 Hz^-1</UnitsConversion>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <Qualifier>Spectral</Qualifier>
        <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <Low>0</Low>
          <High>8192</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
