<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/Solar_Orbiter/RPW</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>RPW</ResourceName>    
      <AlternateName>Plasma Wave Investigation</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2017-11-27T21:10:13Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>RPW will make key measurements in support of the first three, out of four top-level scientific questions, 
which drive Solar Orbiter overall science objectives:
* How and where do the solar wind plasma and magnetic field originate in the corona?
* How do solar transients drive heliospheric variability?
* How do solar eruptions produce energetic particle radiation that fills the heliosphere?
* How does the solar dynamo work and drive connections between the Sun and the heliosphere?


Here is the summary of the specific RPW Science Objectives:
* Solar and Interplanetary Radio Burst: - What is the role of shocks and flares in accelerating particles near the Sun? - How is the Sun connected magnetically to the interplanetary medium? - What are the sources and the global dynamics of eruptive events? - What is the role of ambient medium conditions on particle acceleration and propagation? - How do variations and structure in the solar wind affect low frequency radio wave propagation? 
* Electron density and temperature measurements with the Quasi-Thermal Noise spectroscopy: - Precise measurement of both the electron density and temperature, with accuracies respectively of a few % and around 10 %, at perihelion. - Study the non-thermal character of the electron distributions at perihelion. 
* Radio emission processes from electron beams:  Langmuir waves and electromagnetic mode conversion: - Measurements for the first time in the Solar Wind of both the electric and magnetic field waveforms at high time resolution (up to 500 kSs). - Study of the mode conversion from Langmuir to electromagnetic waves. - Study of the energy balance between electron beams, Langmuir waves and e.m. radio waves at several radial distances 
* Solar wind microphysics and turbulence: - Measure of the waves associated with the plasma instabilities that are generated by temperature anisotropies in the solar wind. - First DC/LF electric field measurements in the inner heliosphere and over a large radial distance in the solar. 
* Shocks, Reconnection, Current Sheets, and Magnetic Holes: - Identification and study of the reconnection process in current sheets with thickness down to the ion scales and smaller. - Determination of the interplanetary shock structure down to the spatial and temporal scales comparable and smaller than the typical ion scales. - Determination of different particle energisation mechanisms within shocks and reconnection regions. - Distinguish different radio burst generation mechanisms. Interplanetary Dust - Determination, in combination with the EPD instrument, the spatial distribution, mass and dynamics of dust particles in the near-Sun heliosphere, in and out of the ecliptic. 


To cover its specific Science Objectives, RPW will measure magnetic and electric fields at high time 
resolution using a number of sensors, to determine the characteristics of electromagnetic and electrostatic 
waves in the solar wind. More precisely, RPW will: 
* Make the first-ever high accuracy, high-sensitivity and low noise measurements of electric fields at low frequencies (below ~1 kHz) in the inner Heliosphere.
* Measure the magnetic and electric fields of the solar wind turbulence with high sensitivity and dynamic range along the spacecraft trajectory.
* Store high-resolution data from scientifically interesting regions such as in-situ shock crossings, in-situ Type III events and others.
* Measure the satellite potential with high temporal resolution permitting to estimate the density fluctuations in the solar wind and allowing higher accuracy particle instrument measurements.
* Measure the quasi thermal noise and Langmuir waves around the local plasma frequency
* Measure for the first type the high frequency magnetic counterpart of Langmuir waves associated with in-situ Type III bursts
* Observe the solar and interplanetary radio burst
* Observe the radio counterpart of dust particle impacts
* Detect on-board in-situ shock crossings and store the corresponding data
* Detect on-board in-situ Type III events and store the corresponding data</Description>  
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Milan.Maksimovic</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>   
      </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>SearchCoil</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Wave Investigation</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/SolO</ObservatoryID>
    </Instrument>
</Spase>
