<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/UKS/ELX</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ELX</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Electron Instrument</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>6 eV - 25 keV, 8-Sector,5-s Average 3-D Electron Analyzer</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
        The objective of the experiment is to study the distribution of chemicals in the atmosphere based on the electron density distribution in Earth's Ionosphere. The basic measurements made by the lectron instrument on UKS was to count the numbers of incoming electrons simultaneously in each of eight directional sensors.  
        The measurements can be considered as a sequence of measurements of the three dimensional velocity space distributions of the electrons - with one distribution being measured every T seconds, where T is a suitable integration time. T 
        Electron distribution functions were measured using two hemispherical electrostatic analyzers with microchannel plate detectors.  
        The instrument had several operating modes. In its primary mode electron intensities were measured, in 1-s periods,  
        in 24 energy channels covering the range 6 eV to 25 keV within 8 angular sectors spanning 180 deg relative to the spacecraft spin axis.  
        Data from a complete 5-s UKS spin period were needed to measure the three-dimensional distribution function.  
        The geometric factors of the sectors were within the range 0.4 to 1.0 sq mm-sr and the energy bandwidth, delta E/E, was 3%  
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>User will acknowledge the AMPTE/UKS electron analyzer team in any publication resulting from the use of these data.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.S.Hall</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1984-088C-02</URL>
        <Description>NSSDC reference page on the instrument</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>UKS Electron Instrument</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/AMPTE/UKS</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
