<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.5.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://IUGONET/Instrument/NIPR/Aurora/SYO/PAI</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Proton auroral imager (PAI) at Syowa Station, Antarctica.</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2013-05-14T12:00:00</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The proton auroral imager (PAI) is an all-sky imager designed to observe the proton aurora. At Syowa Station, two PAIs (PAI-1 and PAI-2) were installed during JARE51 (the 51st Japanese Antarctic Research Expedition) and JARE54. PAI-1 and PAI-2 are equipped with interference filters with different transparent wavelengths (485.0 nm for Hβ and 480.5 nm for Hβ background). Comparison between the Doppler-broadened Hβ emission line (486.1 nm) and the Hβ background level provides information about dynamical morphology of proton aurora. PAI consists of an optical system, a CCD controller and a control PC. The optical system contains a fish eye lens (Fisheye-Nikkor 16mm, F2.8), a dedicated reduced-size optical system manufactured by Nikon, and a digital CCD camera (Hamamatsu C4742-98-26G02). The HiPic8.3.0 software (Hamamatsu) is used for data acquisition. The exposure time and acquisition interval are respectively 7 sec and 15 sec. The acquisition time is set according to the PC&apos;s internal clock, which is adjusted to the NTP server placed at Syowa Station.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Akira.Kadokura</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Hiroshi.Miyaoka</PersonID>
            <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Yuka.Sato</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Auroral Observation at Syowa Station</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://IUGONET/Observatory/NIPR/misc/SYO</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
