<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_1.xsd">
 <Version>2.3.1</Version>
 <DisplayData>
  <ResourceID>spase://ISWI/DisplayData/AWESOME/VLF/Narrowband/P1D</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>AWESOME receiver system quick-look Narrowband Summary Charts</ResourceName>
   <ReleaseDate>2021-03-02T17:39:48Z</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>The narrowband summary chart shows amplitude and
   phase. The rows represent each transmitter-receiver path, as
   labeled in the top left corner. The four columns represent channel
   0 amplitude (NS), channel 0 phase(NS), channel 1 amplitude(EW), and channel 0
   phase(EW), in that order, over the 24-hour period. The colors simply
   indicate when software reboots took place.  The title of the chart indicates the name of the
   station and the year-month-day of the observation.

   These charts are a quick and easy
   way to evaluate the operation of the receiver and the noise
   environment, but more detailed analysis requires downloading the actual data. 

   These summary charts are derived from the Narrowband data which are
   the amplitudes and phase of specific frequencies, usually
   corresponding to VLF transmitters that are used for communications
   and navigation. Sampling rate is usually either 1 Hz or 50 Hz. They
   are a useful diagnostic of the ionosphere. Most of these
   transmitters use minimum shift keying (MSK) modulation. The
   recording software extracts the amplitude, and the phase is
   calculated by demodulating the MSK modulation.
   
   </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
     DATA USAGE POLICY
The data in the WALDO database have been collected by Stanford
University, the Georgia Institute of Technology, and the University of
Colorado Denver. Funding has been provided by the United States
government under various basic science research grants over many
years. 

To maximize the benefit of those investments, WALDO data are released
without restriction, and can be freely analyzed or published. 

The curators of WALDO are Morris Cohen (Georgia Tech) and Mark
Golkowski (CU-Denver). We request that the following acknowledgement
be added in any publication using data from WALDO 

"VLF data are provided by the WALDO database (https://waldo.world),
operated jointly by the Georgia Institute of Technology, and the
University of Colorado Denver, using data collected from those
institutions as well as Stanford University, and has been supported by
various US government grants from the NSF, NASA, and the Department of
Defense." 

If extensive amounts of WALDO data are used in a publication, the
curators request, but do not require, to be contacted to discuss the
possibility of joint authorship, with the WALDO curators providing
help analyzing and interpreting the large dataset. 
   </Acknowledgement> 
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Morris.Cohen</PersonID>
    <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
   </Contact>
   <InformationURL>
    <Name>Worldwide Archive of Low-Frequency Data and Observations (WALDO)</Name>
    <URL>https://waldo.world</URL>
   </InformationURL>
   <Association>
    <AssociationID>spase://GBO/NumericalData/AWESOME/VLF/PT0.02S</AssociationID>
    <AssociationType>DerivedFrom</AssociationType>
   </Association>
   <PriorID>spase://GBO/DisplayData/AWESOME/VLF/Narrowband/P1D</PriorID>
  </ResourceHeader>
  <AccessInformation>
   <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/WALDO</RepositoryID>
   <AccessURL>
    <Name>Worldwide Archive of Low-Frequency Data and Observations (WALDO) Narrowband Summary Charts</Name>
    <URL>https://waldo.world/summary-and-availability-charts/#NarrowbandSummary</URL>
   </AccessURL>
   <Format>PNG</Format>
  </AccessInformation>
  <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AWESOME/VLF</InstrumentID>
  <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
  <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
  <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservedRegion>
  <InputResourceID>spase://GBO/NumericalData/AWESOME/VLF/PT0.02S</InputResourceID>
 </DisplayData>
</Spase>
