<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
  <Version>2.3.1</Version>
  <DisplayData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/DisplayData/UCLA/Global-MHD-code/mS4-BIF/PT10S</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Characteristics of Reconnection Sites and Fast Flow Channels in an MHD Simulation. Supplementary MHD simulation movie mS4-BIF.mp4 for 14 March 2008.</ResourceName>
	  <DOI>https://doi.org/10.21978/p8rw5g</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-03-16T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Section 4.1 of the text describes our procedure for identifying the locations of x-lines in a map of the neutral surface. 
	  At each value of Y in an interpolated grid, we scan the entire length of the trace of Vx from -10 to -70 Re. A function finds all 
	  intervals of Vx>=250 km/s and Vx less then or equal to -250 km/s.  We call these earthward and tailward fast flow intervals. We define 
	  a bifurcation of fast flow as the point at which Vx changes sign from fast earthward to fast tailward flow. In simple cases, this 
	  transition occurs in about 2 Re (20 grid points). The zero crossing is the location of the x-line at this value of Y. As described 
	  in the text, we process the arrays of zero crossings to define a line in the neutral surface. We display this information as lines 
	  parallel to X at fixed Y. Intervals of fast earthward flow are represented by a thick red line. Fast flow is  a thick blue line. The 
	  zero crossing is a gray circle. After completion of the plot, we add x-lines as colored ropes (yellow with black stripes). Each map is 
	  in a file and subsequently made into a movie. The movie illustrates the formation and evolution of x-lines.
	  
      The movie begins at 04:00 UT with at least five significant x-lines and six earthward flow channels. This is the start of the growth 
	  phase of a substorm. As time advances the locations of the x-lines change as flow channels move away from them. New lines form and 
	  channels merge. When the movie approaches substorm onset at 04:44 UT the x-lines merge into a single long x-line stretching diagonally 
	  across the tail. About 04:35, the nose of the fast earthward flow channel penetrates close to the Earth, and then begins to sweep 
	  westward to earlier local times. At this, time the movie mS02 and the text Figure 13 shows magnetic flux accumulating close to the Earth. 
	  At 04:50 UT, the single channels spawns new channels that flow directly toward Earth rather  than along the diagonal channel.
      </Description>
	  <Acknowledgement>Mostafa El-Alaoui, Raymond J. Walker; Robert L. McPherron</Acknowledgement>	
      <PublicationInfo>
		<Authors>R.L. McPherron; M. El-Alaoui; R.J. Walker; and R.L. Richard</Authors>
		<PublicationDate>2020-08-31T00:00:00Z</PublicationDate>
		<PublishedBy>Journal of Geohysical Research - Space Physics</PublishedBy>
	  </PublicationInfo>
	  <Funding>
		<Agency>NASA</Agency>
		<Project>Substorm current wedge development and evolution using THEMIS observation and simulations</Project>
		<AwardNumber>NNX17AB83G</AwardNumber>
	  </Funding>
      <Funding>
		<Agency>NASA</Agency>
		<Project>Structure and evolution of plasma sheet fast flows using THEMIS observation and global MHD simulations</Project>
		<AwardNumber>NNX15AI63G</AwardNumber>
	  </Funding>
      <Funding>
		<Agency>NSF</Agency>
		<Project>GEM: A Statistical Study of the Substorm Sequence and Phenomena Associated with Expansion Onset</Project>
		<AwardNumber>1602588</AwardNumber>
	  </Funding>
	  <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.L.McPherron</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
	  <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>  
	  <InformationURL>
        <Name>Virtual Magnetospheric Observatory directory containing movies for Journal of Gephysical Research publication.</Name>
        <URL>http://vmo.igpp.ucla.edu/data1/McPherron/Simulation_Movies_and_Data/Simulation_Movies/mS2-Bz.avi</URL>
        <Description>Supplimentary movies for JGR publication</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/UCLA/VMO</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>Virtual Magnetospheric Observatory</Name>
        <URL>http://vmo.igpp.ucla.edu/data1/</URL>
        <Description>Virtual Magnetospheric Observatory</Description>
		<Language>EN</Language>
	  </AccessURL>    
      <Format>AVI</Format>
	  <Acknowledgement>If data downloaded from the VMO Data Repository are used in publication kindly acknowledge the Virtual Magnetospheric Observatory, Earth, Planetary and Space Science Department, University of California, Los Angeles for providing access to the data.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Raw</ProcessingLevel>
	<ProviderName>UCLA M. El-Alaoui MHD Simulation</ProviderName>
	<ProviderResourceName>MHD Simulation Movies</ProviderResourceName>
	<ProviderProcessingLevel>Raw</ProviderProcessingLevel>
	
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/UCLA/Global-MHD-code</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
	
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2008-03-14T04:00:00</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2008-03-14T05:00:00</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <DisplayCadence>PT10S</DisplayCadence>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
	<Keyword>MHD Simulation</Keyword>
	<Keyword>Substorm</Keyword>
	<Keyword>High Speed Earthward Flows</Keyword>
	<Parameter>
	  <Name>MHD simulation movie of GSM X component of position for 14 March 2008</Name>
	  <ParameterKey>X component of position</ParameterKey>
	  <Description>Two dimensional display of this movie of the GSM X component of position is on the original.</Description>
	  <Cadence>PT10S</Cadence>
	  <Units>Re</Units>
	  <CoordinateSystem>
	    <CoordinateRepresentation>Cartesian</CoordinateRepresentation>
		<CoordinateSystemName>GSM</CoordinateSystemName>
	  </CoordinateSystem>
	  <Structure>
	    <Size>3840 1890</Size>
		<Description>Each image is 3840 pixels by 1890 pixels and there are 360 frames in the movie.</Description>
	  </Structure>
	  <ValidMin>-70</ValidMin>
	  <ValidMax>0</ValidMax>
	  <Support>
		  <Qualifier>Direction</Qualifier>
		  <SupportQuantity>Positional</SupportQuantity>
	  </Support>
	</Parameter>
	
	<Parameter>
	  <Name>MHD simulation movie of GSM Y component of position for 14 March 2008</Name>
	  <ParameterKey>Y component of position</ParameterKey>
	  <Description>Two dimensional display of this movie of the GSM Y component of position is on the original.</Description>
	  <Cadence>PT10S</Cadence>
	  <Units>Re</Units>
	  <CoordinateSystem>
	    <CoordinateRepresentation>Cartesian</CoordinateRepresentation>
		<CoordinateSystemName>GSM</CoordinateSystemName>
	  </CoordinateSystem>
	  <Structure>
	    <Size>3840 1890</Size>
		<Description>Each image is 3840 pixels by 1890 pixels and there are 360 frames in the movie.</Description>
	  </Structure>
	  <ValidMin>-20</ValidMin>
	  <ValidMax>20</ValidMax>
	  <Support>
		  <Qualifier>Direction</Qualifier>
		  <SupportQuantity>Positional</SupportQuantity>
	  </Support>
	</Parameter>

	<Parameter>
	  <Name>MHD simulation movie of GSM X component of plasma flow velocity for 14 March 2008</Name>
	  <ParameterKey>Vx component of plasma flow</ParameterKey>
	  <Description>Two dimensional display of this movie of the GSM X component of plasma flow velocity is on the original, not interpolated grid. Red means Vx flows earthward and is greater then or equal to 250 km/s, Blue means Vx flows tailward and is less then or equal to 250 km/s, and white means flows are between -250 and 250 km/s.</Description>
	  <Cadence>PT10S</Cadence>
	  <Units>km/s</Units>
	  <CoordinateSystem>
	    <CoordinateRepresentation>Cartesian</CoordinateRepresentation>
		<CoordinateSystemName>GSM</CoordinateSystemName>
	  </CoordinateSystem>
	  <Structure>
	    <Size>3840 1890</Size>
		<Description>Each image is 3840 pixels by 1890 pixels and there are 360 frames in the movie.</Description>
	  </Structure>
	  <ValidMin>-250</ValidMin>
	  <ValidMax>250</ValidMax>
	  <Support>
		  <Qualifier>Vector</Qualifier>
		  <SupportQuantity>Velocity</SupportQuantity>
	  </Support>
	</Parameter>
	
	<Parameter>
	  <Name>MHD simulation movie of GSM plasma flow velocity for 14 March 2008</Name>
	  <ParameterKey>Vx and Vy components of plasma flow</ParameterKey>
	  <Description>Two dimensional display of this movie of the GSM plasma flow velocity interpolated grid.</Description>
	  <Cadence>PT10S</Cadence>
	  <Units>km/s</Units>
	  <CoordinateSystem>
	    <CoordinateRepresentation>Cartesian</CoordinateRepresentation>
		<CoordinateSystemName>GSM</CoordinateSystemName>
	  </CoordinateSystem>
	  <Structure>
	    <Size>3840 1890</Size>
		<Description>Each image is 3840 pixels by 1890 pixels and there are 360 frames in the movie.</Description>
	  </Structure>
	  <ValidMin>-300</ValidMin>
	  <ValidMax>300</ValidMax>
	  <Support>
		  <Qualifier>Vector</Qualifier>
		  <SupportQuantity>Velocity</SupportQuantity>
	  </Support>
	</Parameter>
 </DisplayData>
</Spase>
