<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/NumericalData/CDPP-Archive/PSP/FIELDS/RFS/LFR/PARKERSP_FIELDS_RFS_SQTN</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>PARKER SOLAR PROBE FIELDS Level 3 Simplified Quasi-Thermal Noise (SQTN) Data (CDF)</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/8t0s-ns96</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-07-04T15:46:58Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This data set contains  Parker Solar Probe FIELDS Level 3 Simplified Quasi-Thermal Noise data, derived from power spectra (10.5 kHz to 1.7 MHz) acquired by the low-frequency receiver (LFR) of the Radio Frequency Spectrometer (RFS) when connected to V1V2 dipole antenna. 
The technique of QTN spectroscopy consists of using the power spectrum of the voltage induced on an electric antenna by the particle quasi-thermal motion, measured by a radio receiver connected to an electric antenna. The signature of the electrons is a line at the electron plasma frequency, which leads to the total electron density (proportionnal to the square of electron plasma frequency), whereas the shape of the line reveals the electron kinetic temperature, as well as its thermal (core) and suprathermal components. 
For more information on the QTN spectroscopy, please see : Moncuquet, M. et al. (2020), First in-situ measurements electron density and temperature from quasi-thermal noise spectroscopy with Parker Solar Probe/FIELDS, The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, Volume 246, p.44, doi:10.3847/1538-4365/ab5a84/
No data available for encounter E11. Due to operational issues, RFS-LFR was stopped from February 23 to February 27 2022, with a perihelion on February 25, so most of the SQTN processing was not possible for this encounter.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
        Please add the following to your acknowledgements when using SQTN data (electron density and core temperature from Simplified Quasi Thermal Noise spectroscopy) :
The authors acknowledge CNES (Centre National d Etudes Spatiales), CNRS (Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique), the Observatoire de PARIS, NASA and the FIELDS/RFS team for their support to the PSP/SQTN data production, and the CDPP (Centre de Donnees de la Physique des Plasmas) for their archiving and provision. The FIELDS experiment on the PSP spacecraft was designed and developed under NASA contract NNN06AA01C.
Other datasets from FIELDS can be found at https://fields.ssl.berkeley.edu/ . For other instruments of Parker Solar Probe, see https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/index.html/

Please cite the following reference papers when using SQTN data :
[1] M. Moncuquet, N. Meyer-Vernet, K. Issautier, M. Pulupa, J. W. Bonnell, S. D. Bale, T. Dudok de Wit, K. Goetz, L. Griton, P. R. Harvey, R. J. MacDowall, M. Maksimovic and D. M. Malaspina (2020), First In Situ Measurements of Electron Density and Temperature from Quasi-thermal Noise Spectroscopy with Parker Solar Probe/FIELDS, Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, 246:44 (2020), doi: 10.3847/1538-4365/ab5a84 [NASA ADS https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020ApJS..246...44M]
[2] M. Pulupa, S. D. Bale, J. W. Bonnell, T. A. Bowen, N. Carruth, K. Goetz, D. Gordon, P. R. Harvey, M. Maksimovic, J. C. Martinez-Oliveros, M. Moncuquet, P. Saint-Hilaire, D. Seitz, D. Sundkvist, The Solar Probe Plus Radio Frequency Spectrometer: Measurement requirements, analog design, and digital signal processing, Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, 122 (2017), 2836-2854. doi: 10.1002/2016JA023345 [NASA ADS https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2017JGRA..122.2836P]	  
	  </Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Thierry.Dudok.De.Wit</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Claire.Revillet</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Michel.Moncuquet</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Stuart.Bale</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://regards.cnes.fr/user/cdpp/modules/1777?sp=DatasetName;q=DatasetName:PARKERSP_FIELDS_RFS_SQTN</URL>
        <Description>Access via CNES Data Archive for CDPP</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>CDF</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <ProviderProcessingLevel>3</ProviderProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/PSP/FIELDS/RFS/LFR</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ElectricField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2018-10-15T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2021-11-29T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Sun.Corona</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Electron  density</Name>
      <Description>The electron density is deduced from the automatic detection of the plasma frequency in RFS spectra with SQTN spectroscopy</Description>
      <Units>cm^-3</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>1e6&gt;m^-3</UnitsConversion>
      <Particle>
        <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
        <Qualifier>Scalar</Qualifier>
        <ParticleQuantity>NumberDensity</ParticleQuantity>
      </Particle>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Electron core temperature</Name>
      <Description>The electron core temperature is deduced from the QTN level below fp in RFS spectra with SQTN spectroscopy</Description>
      <Units>eV</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>11604.447&gt;K</UnitsConversion>
      <Particle>
        <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
        <Qualifier>Scalar</Qualifier>
        <ParticleQuantity>Temperature</ParticleQuantity>
      </Particle>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Uncertainty of electron density</Name>
      <Description>Uncertainty of electron density
electron_density - electron_density_delta[0] &lt; electron_density &lt; electron_density + electron_density_delta[1]</Description>
      <Units>cm^-3</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>1e6&gt;m^-3</UnitsConversion>
      <Support>
        <Qualifier>Uncertainty</Qualifier>
        <SupportQuantity>DataQuality</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
