<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_9.xsd">
   <Version>2.2.9</Version>
   <NumericalData>
      <ResourceID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Omni1/PT12S</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Ulysses Cosmic Ray and Solar Particle Investigation (COSPIN) High Energy Telescope (HET) Full Resolution Proton and Electron Counts and Accumulation Times for Spin-Averaged Counting Rates, OMNI1 H1-H9, 12 s Data</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>A Directory containing Daily FTP downloadable Files containing Readout-by-Readout Listings of the Counts accumulated in the H1-H9 Spin-Averaged Counting Rates. These Counting Rates respond primarily to Protons (H1-H5, H9) in the approximate Energy Ranges 5.4-14, 14-19, 24-31, 34-68, 68-92, and &gt;92 MeV, respectively, and to Electrons (H6-8) in the very approximate Energy Ranges 1-3, 5-10, and 3-5 MeV, respectively. The Naming Convention for the Daily Files is uly_het_full_rat_omni1_YYYDDD.txt, where YYY indicates the three digit Year since 1900 (e.g. YYY=090 for 1990, and YYY=102 for 2002) and DDD indicates the three digit Day of Year (January 1 = 1). In each File, following a detailed Description of the Format, the Data consist of a Listing of Counts accumulated in the H1-H9 Spin-Averaged Counting Rates during the Intervals between successive Readouts, organized into Columns as described below. The first four Columns give the Start Time of the Counting Rate Accumulation Period as Fractional Year (to 12 Decimal Places) and as Year since 1900, Day of Year, and Milliseconds of Day at the Start of the Accumulation, followed by one Column giving the Duration of the Accumulation Period in Milliseconds (it is the same for all nine Rates), and nine Columns giving the Counts accumulated in that Period for each Rate. All Fields except for the Fractional Year are in Integer Format. Each Line contains Data for one single Readout of the Rates H1-H9, and all Readouts where at least one of the Rates has a Non-fill Value are included. Where Fill does occur it is indicated by -1. Since the Accumulation Period for each Readout is forced to include an Integral Number of Spacecraft Spins in order to produce pure Spin-Averaged Measurements, the Lengths of the Accumulation Periods vary in a Cyclic Manner as the Period of the Telemetry Cycle beats with the Spacecraft Spin Period. All Counting Rates in this File are read out twice per Spacecraft Format. At the most common Science Telemetry Bit Rate (2048 bps) this corresponds to an Average Interval between Readouts of 16 s. Thus, with a typical 5 rpm Spacecraft Spin Rate the Accumulation Intervals vary in a repeating Cycle of 12, 12, 24, 12, 12, 24, 12, etc., seconds. At lower Bit Rates the Average Interval is equal to 16 times (2048/BR) seconds and the Cycle automatically adjusts to produce this Average Accumulation. No Noise Removal or Despiking has been done, so Caution must be used in interpreting isolated large Increases or Decreases in the Counting Rates.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the COSPIN HET Lead Investigator and COSPIN PI, R. Bruce McKibben</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.Bruce.McKibben</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            <Role>TeamLeader</Role>
</Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Clifford.Lopate</PersonID>
            <Role>DataProducer</Role>
</Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.Connell</PersonID>
            <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>The Ulysses Cosmic Ray and Solar Particle Investigation, COSPIN</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments</URL>
            <Description>Published Description of the COSPIN Instrumentation, J.A. Simpson et al., Astron. Astrophys. Suppl. Ser. 92, 365-399, 1992. See especially Section 4.3 for a detailed Description of the High Energy Telescopes, HET. An electronic Copy of this Paper is available at http://adsbit.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-iarticle_query?1992A%26AS...92..365S&amp;defaultprint=YES&amp;filetype=.pdf.</Description>
</InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>User Notes for the COSPIN/HET Data Files</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa-sl-server/data-action?PROTOCOL=HTTP&amp;PRODUCT_TYPE=ALL&amp;FILE_NAME=het_usernotes.pdf&amp;FILE_PATH=/ufa/HiRes/doc/cospin</URL>
            <Description>The User Notes File at the Ulysses Final Archive (UFA) describes the Format of the ASCII Data Files for the COSPIN High Energy Telescope, HET</Description>
</InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>COSPIN HET Full Resolution ReadMe Document, Word Format</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa-sl-server/data-action?PROTOCOL=HTTP&amp;PRODUCT_TYPE=ALL&amp;FILE_NAME=ReadMeHETFullRes.doc&amp;FILE_PATH=/ufa/HiRes/COSPIN/HET</URL>
            <Description>Top Level Descriptions of Formats and Contents of the six File Types that make up the COSPIN HET Full Resolution Data Set. Detailed Descriptions of the Formats and Contents are found in Header Lines at the Start of each downloaded Data File. The Data covered by this SPASE Description are described in the ReadMe under the Heading omni1. (*** Note ***: During the Build-up of this Data Set, a few Errors and Omissions have been found in the Header Lines for some of the File Types. These Errors and Omissions are listed in this ReadMe File. Upon Completion of the Data Set, all Errors and Omissions discovered will be corrected in all of the Header Lines of all of the File Types at which time this Note will be removed).</Description>
</InformationURL>
         <Association>
            <AssociationID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Omni2/PT128S</AssociationID>
            <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
</Association>
         <Association>
            <AssociationID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sect1/PT64S</AssociationID>
            <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
</Association>
         <Association>
            <AssociationID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sect2/PT128S</AssociationID>
            <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
</Association>
         <PriorID>spase://VEPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/FullResolution/Rates/Omni1</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/ESA/ESAC/UlyssesFinalArchive</RepositoryID>
         <Availability>Online</Availability>
         <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>Ulysses Final Archive Access to COSPIN/HET Full Resolution Proton and Electron Counts and Accumulation Times for Spin-Averaged Coincidence Counting Rates, OMNI1 H1-H9</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#data</URL>
            <Description>Parent Directory containing FTP downloadable Daily Files with the Format described below</Description>
</AccessURL>
         <Format>Text</Format>
         <Encoding>ASCII</Encoding>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge R. Bruce McKibben, Space Science Center, University of New Hampshire</Acknowledgement>
</AccessInformation>
      <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET</InstrumentID>
      <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
      <TemporalDescription>
         <TimeSpan>
            <StartDate>1990-10-22T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
            <StopDate>2009-06-29T23:59:59.999</StopDate>
</TimeSpan>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
</TemporalDescription>
      <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Interval Start Time</Name>
         <Description>Nominal Start Time for the Average given in Decimal Year, Integer Year, Day of Year, and Milliseconds of Day.</Description>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <Structure>
            <Size>4</Size>
            <Element>
               <Name>Decimal Year</Name>
               <Index>1</Index>
               <ParameterKey>Column_1</ParameterKey>
               <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>0.00000000000</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Year</Name>
               <Index>2</Index>
               <ParameterKey>Column_2</ParameterKey>
               <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>0</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Day of Year</Name>
               <Index>3</Index>
               <ParameterKey>Column_3</ParameterKey>
               <ValidMin>1</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>366</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>0</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Milliseconds of Day</Name>
               <Index>4</Index>
               <ParameterKey>Column_4</ParameterKey>
               <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>86400000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>0</FillValue>
</Element>
</Structure>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
</Support>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Accumulation Period</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_5</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Length of the Accumulation Period</Description>
         <Caveats>None</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <Units>millisecond</Units>
         <ValidMin>10000</ValidMin>
         <ValidMax>150000</ValidMax>
         <FillValue>0</FillValue>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
</Support>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H01</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_6</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H1 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H1 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Protons in the Energy Interval 5.4-14 MeV (Normal Incidence).</Description>
         <Caveats>Heavier Nuclei with similar Penetrating Power to 5.4-14 MeV Protons also produce Counts in H1. However the Intensities of such Heavier Nuclei are usually much lower than the Proton Intensity. The most significant Contributor to such Contamination is usually Helium. During Quiet Times the H1 Counting Rates is dominated by Background Counts induced by Gamma Rays from the Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>5.4</Low>
               <High>14</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H02</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_7</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H2 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H2 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Protons in the Energy Interval 14-19 MeV (Normal Incidence).</Description>
         <Caveats>Heavier Nuclei with similar Penetrating Power to 14-19 MeV Protons also produce Counts in H2. However the Intensities of such Heavier Nuclei are usually much lower than the Proton Intensity. The most significant Contributor to such Contamination is usually Helium. Use of Higher Level Discriminators on the triggered Detectors (D1 and D2) discriminates strongly against Electrons, and thus also against Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator induced Background.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>14</Low>
               <High>19</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H03</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_8</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H3 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H3 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Protons in the Energy Interval 24-31 MeV (Normal Incidence).</Description>
         <Caveats>Heavier Nuclei with similar Penetrating Power to 24-31 MeV Protons also produce Counts in H3. However the Intensities of such Heavier Nuclei are usually much lower than the Proton Intensity. The most significant Contributor to such Contamination is usually Helium. Electrons produced by the Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gammas are excluded by the Coincidence Requirement, which requires greater Range for Electrons than that of the Maximum Energy Electrons that Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gammas can produce. However Higher Energy Electrons of Cosmic Ray, Solar, Magnetospheric or other natural Origin may in some Circumstances make significant Contributions to the Counting Rate.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>24</Low>
               <High>31</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H04</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_9</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H4 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H4 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Protons in the Energy Interval 34-68 MeV (Normal Incidence).</Description>
         <Caveats>Heavier Nuclei with similar Penetrating Power to 34-68 MeV Protons also produce Counts in H4. However the Intensities of such Heavier Nuclei are usually much lower than the Proton Intensity. The most significant Contributor to such Contamination is usually Helium. Electrons produced by the Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gammas are excluded by the Coincidence Requirement, which requires greater Range for Electrons than that of the Maximum Energy Electrons that Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gammas can produce. However Higher Energy Electrons of Cosmic Ray, Solar, Magnetospheric or other natural Origin may in some Circumstances make significant Contributions to the Counting Rate.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>34</Low>
               <High>68</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H05</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_10</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H5 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H5 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Protons in the Energy Interval 68-92 MeV (Normal Incidence).</Description>
         <Caveats>Heavier Nuclei with similar Penetrating Power to 68-92 MeV Protons also produce Counts in H5. However the Intensities of such Heavier Nuclei are usually much lower than the Proton Intensity. The most significant Contributor to such Contamination is usually Helium. Electrons produced by the Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gammas are excluded by the Coincidence Requirement, which requires greater Range for Electrons than that of the Maximum Energy Electrons that Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gammas can produce. However Higher Energy Electrons of Cosmic Ray, Solar, Magnetospheric or other natural Origin may in some Circumstances make significant Contributions to the Counting Rate. During In-Flight-Calibrate (IFC) Sequences, two Ramps of Pulse are fed to the Detector Amplifiers over several Hours. For Part of each Sequence, the Pulses satisfy the H5 Counting Rate Logic. The H5 Counting Rate responds to those Pulses that are so small that they do not trigger the High Level Discriminators on the Detectors. This leads to two small Spikes separated by several Hours (depending on Bit Rate) in the H5 Counting Rate. A clear Example of this Effect (and of the corresponding Effect on H12, which Counts the larger Pulses) can be found on Day 31 of 1991.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>68</Low>
               <High>92</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H06</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_11</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H6 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H6 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Electrons in the Energy Interval from about 1-3 MeV (Normal Incidence). This Counting Rate discriminates strongly against Nuclei by requiring Anti-Coincidence with a Discriminator set slightly slightly above the Energy deposited by Minimum Ionizing Particles in D1, but below the Minimum Energy deposited by a Proton stopping in D2.</Description>
         <Caveats>Because of Scattering of the Electrons in the Telescope, the Energy Range given is very approximate. During Quiet Times, the H6 Counting Rate is dominated by Electrons produced by Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gamma Rays in the Telescope.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>1</Low>
               <High>3</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H07</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_12</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H7 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H7 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Electrons in the Energy Interval from about 5-10 MeV (Normal Incidence). This Counting Rate discriminates strongly against Nuclei by requiring Anti-Coincidence with Discriminators set above the Energy deposited by Minimum Ionizing Particles, but below the Minimum Energy deposited by a Proton stopping in the Telescope.</Description>
         <Caveats>Because of Scattering during Propagation of the Electrons in the Telescope, the Energy Range given is very approximate. The Coincidence Logic for H7 requires a greater Penetration Depth in the Telescope than is possible for Electrons produced by Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gamma Rays, so no Background is induced in this Counting Rate by the Presence of the Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>5</Low>
               <High>10</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H08</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_13</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H8 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H8 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Electrons in the Energy Interval from about 3-5 MeV (Normal Incidence). This Counting Rate discriminates strongly against Nuclei by requiring Anti-Coincidence with Discriminators set above the Energy deposited by Minimum Ionizing Particles, but below the Minimum Energy deposited by a Proton stopping in the Telescope.</Description>
         <Caveats>Because of Scattering during Propagation of the Electrons in the Telescope, the Energy Range given is very approximate. The Coincidence Logic for H8 requires a greater Penetration Depth in the Telescope than is possible for Electrons produced by Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator Gamma Rays, so no Background is induced in this Counting Rate by the Presence of the Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generator.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>3</Low>
               <High>5</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET H09</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Column_14</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Counts accumulated by Counting Rate H9 during the Period of Coverage (Column 5) Starting at the Time defined in Columns 1-4. The H9 Counting Rate normally responds primarily to Protons with Energies greater than about 92 MeV, which completely penetrate the Telescope Detector Stack. Thus it provides a Measure of the Integral Intensity of Energetic Charged Particles with Penetrating Power equal or greater to that of 92 MeV Protons.</Description>
         <Caveats>Because of Proximity of the Low Level Discriminators on several of the Detectors to the expected Energy Deposits by Minimum Ionizing Protons, the Efficiency of Detection decreases somewhat for Minimum Ionizing Particles. Because of the Dependence of the Detector Noise on Temperature, the Decrease in Efficiency depends to some extent on the Telescope Temperature. Since the Particles that trigger H9 completely penetrate the Telescope, both Forward and Backward-going Particles are counted. Backward-going Particles must also penetrate the Spacecraft Structure and Instruments behind the HET before entering the Telescope, so the Energy Threshold for Backward-going Particles is very poorly known. Thus this Counting Rate is more suitable for Study of relative Variations in the Particle Intensity than for Derivation of an accurate Integral Flux.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
         <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>92</Low>
               <High>1.0E+14</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
</NumericalData>
</Spase>
