<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.6.0</Version>
   <Collection>
      <ResourceID>spase://NASA/Collection/THEMIS/Ground/ASI/full_PT3S</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images</ResourceName>
		 <AlternateName>THEMIS-Ground ASF</AlternateName>
		 <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/5jv5-vc55</DOI>
         <ReleaseDate>2023-10-27T00:00:00.00Z</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-10-23T00:00:00.00Z</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Created by JMW.</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
			<RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-10-27T00:00:00.00Z</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Added DOI. JMW.</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.  The ASI stations monitor a 170 degree field of view imaging the auroral oval at kilometer resolution.  The ASI is comprised of a fisheye lens and CCD in a stainless steel enclosure topped with a transparent acrylic dome.  The CCD has a resolution of 256 x 256 pixels.  Exposure control ranges from 5 s to 1 ms although the typical data rate is one image every 3 seconds.  Silicone heaters keep the instrument within the nominal temperature range.  During daylight hours a sun shades deploy to protect the CCD.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>We acknowledge NASA contract NAS5-02099 and V. Angelopoulos for use of data from the THEMIS Mission. Specifically: S. Mende and E. Donovan for use of the ASI data, the Canadian Space Agency (CSA) for logistical support in fielding and data retrieval from the GBO stations, and the Canada Foundation for Innovation.</Acknowledgement>
         <PublicationInfo>
            <Authors>Angelopoulos, V., Mende, S. B., Donovan, E., Frey, H. U., and Spanswick, E. L. </Authors>
            <PublicationDate>2023-01-01T00:00:00</PublicationDate>
            <PublishedBy>University of California, Berkeley</PublishedBy>
         </PublicationInfo>
		 <!--Vassilis Angelopoulos -->
         <Contact>
           <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Vassilis.Angelopoulos</PersonID>
           <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <!--Stephen Mende-->
         <Contact>
           <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Stephen.B.Mende</PersonID>
           <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <!--Eric Donovan-->
         <Contact>
           <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Eric.Donovan</PersonID>
           <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
	     <!--Harald Frey-->
         <Contact>
           <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Harald.U.Frey</PersonID>
           <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
		 <Contact>
           <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Emma.Louise.Spanswick</PersonID>
           <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>  
         <InformationURL>
           <Name>THEMIS Summary Plots</Name>
           <URL>http://themis.ssl.berkeley.edu/gbo/display.py?view_type=summary</URL>
           <Description>Summary plots containing ASI thumbnail images; useful for determining when ASI data exists.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>  
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/UCB/THEMIS</RepositoryID>
         <Availability>Online</Availability>
         <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>THEMIS Web Data</Name>
            <URL>http://themis.ssl.berkeley.edu/data/themis/thg/l1/asi/</URL>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>CDF</Format>
         <Encoding>None</Encoding>
      </AccessInformation>
      <Member>
         <ResourceName>Athabasca THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
         <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Athabasca (54.71 deg GLat, 246.69 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Athabasca/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-01-01T00:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
      <Member>
         <ResourceName>Chibougamau THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Chibougamau (49.81 deg GLat, 285.58 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Chibougamau/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-01-03T07:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Ekati THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Ekati (64.72 deg GLat, 250.67 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Ekati/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-01-15T06:00:00</StartDate>
         <StopDate>2007-04-29T08:00:00</StopDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Fort Simpson THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Fort Simpson (61.76 deg GLat, 238.77 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Fort.Simpson/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-11-11T04:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Fort Smith THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Fort Smith (60.03 deg GLat, 248.07 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Fort.Smith/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-01-01T00:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Fort Yukon THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Fort Yukon (66.56 deg GLat, 214.79 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Fort.Yukon/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-11-28T02:00:00</StartDate>
         <StopDate>2019-03-08T09:00:00</StopDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Gakona THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Gakona (62.39 deg GLat, 214.87 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Gakona/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-09-12T05:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Gillam THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Gillam (56.35 deg GLat, 265.34 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Gillam/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-06-01T04:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Goose Bay THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Goose Bay (53.32 deg GLat, 299.54 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Goose.Bay/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-10-03T07:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Inuvik THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Inuvik (68.41 deg GLat, 226.23 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Inuvik/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-01-01T02:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Kapuskasing THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Kapuskasing (49.39 deg GLat, 277.68 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Kapuskasing/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-05-17T02:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Kiana THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Kiana (66.97 deg GLat, 199.56 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Kiana/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-09-08T07:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Kuujjuaq THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Kuujjuaq (58.10 deg GLat, 291.60 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Kuujjuaq/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2007-10-31T23:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>McGrath THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at McGrath (62.95 deg GLat, 204.40 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/McGrath/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-08-31T04:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Narsarsuaq THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Narsarsuaq (61.16 deg GLat, 314.56 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Narsarsuaq/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2008-10-22T00:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Pinawa THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Pinawa (50.20 deg GLat, 263.96 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Pinawa/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-06-01T04:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Prince George THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Prince George (53.82 deg GLat, 237.17 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Prince.George/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-01-01T01:00:00</StartDate>
         <StopDate>2007-08-31T09:00:00</StopDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Rankin Inlet THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Rankin Inlet (62.82 deg GLat, 267.89 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Rankin.Inlet/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-09-14T02:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Sanikiluaq THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Sanikiluaq (56.54 deg GLat, 280.77 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Sanikiluaq/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-10-31T01:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Snap Lake THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Snap Lake (63.58 deg GLat, 249.13 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Snap.Lake/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2008-10-22T04:00:00</StartDate>
         <StopDate>2013-10-24T11:00:00</StopDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Taloyoak THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Taloyoak (69.54 deg GLat, 266.45 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Taloyoak/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2009-01-15T23:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>The Pas THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at The Pas (53.99 deg GLat, 259.06 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/The.Pas/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2005-11-28T00:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Whitehorse THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at White Horse (61.01 deg GLat, 224.78 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Whitehorse/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2006-01-01T01:00:00</StartDate>
      </Member>
	  <Member>
         <ResourceName>Yellowknife THEMIS Ground-based All Sky Imager; Full Resolution Images.</ResourceName>
		 <Description>THEMIS Ground All Sky Imager at Yellowknife (62.52 deg GLat, 245.69 deg GLong): 256 x 256 pixel full resolution images of auroral oval.</Description>
         <MemberID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/THEMIS/Ground/Yellowknife/ASI/full_PT3S</MemberID>
         <StartDate>2008-03-01T02:00:00</StartDate>
         <StopDate>2008-10-22T04:00:00</StopDate>
      </Member>
   </Collection>
</Spase>
