<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/PSP/epiHi</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>IS⊙IS EPI-Hi</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Energetic Particle Instrument Hi-Energy</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-11-12T16:00:05Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The science objective of the Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun, ISOIS, 
        experiment is to explore the physical mechanisms that produce, accelerate, and transport energetic 
        particles in the inner heliosphere. This will be achieved by observing energetic electrons, protons, 
        and heavy ions in the Sun's atmosphere and inner heliosphere to learn about the origin and seed population 
        of solar energetic particles, how these and other particles are accelerated, and what mechanisms are 
        responsible for transporting the different particle populations into the heliosphere. It will also 
        contribute to tracing the flow of energy that heats and accelerates the solar corona and solar wind, 
        and determining the structure and dynamics of the plasma and magnetic fields at the sources of the solar wind. 
        The Integrated Science Investigation of the Sun consists of two instruments, EPI-Lo and EPI-Hi, mounted on 
        the side of the spacecraft near the back ram-facing side, protected by the heat shield.
        The EPI-Hi instrument system is based on ion-implanted solid-state detectors. It comprises three detector stacks 
        (particle telescopes). One is designated a High Energy Telescope (HET) and two are designated Low-Energy Telescopes (LET1 and LET2). 
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Please Acknowledge the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, NASA</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.J.McComas</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Eric.R.Christian</PersonID>
        <Role>DeputyPI</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Parker Solar Probe Mission Instrument web page, JPL</Name>
        <URL>http://parkersolarprobe.jhuapl.edu/Spacecraft/index.php#Instruments</URL>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Parker Solar Probe Mission Instrument web page, NASA</Name>
        <URL>https://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/parker-solar-probe-instruments/</URL>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>SolidStateDetector</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Parker Solar Probe ISOIS Investigation</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/PSP</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
