<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/PSP/SPC</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>SWEAP SPC</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Solar Probe Cup</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-11-12T16:00:05Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The SPC is a Faraday Cup made of high purity tungsten, niobium, and molybdenum,
        TZM, that is mounted on the edge of the solar shield and looks directly at the Sun to 
        measure ion and electron fluxes and flow angles. It measures fluxes and flow angles as 
        a function of energy from 50 eV/q to 8 keV/q for ions and 50 eV to 2 keV for electrons.
        It has a full width field-of-view of 60 degrees. The SPC consists of a disk-shaped 
        modulator section comprising a ground grid, a high-voltage modulator grid, and a limiting
        aperture ground grid. Behind this is a smaller disk-shaped collector grid housing ground
        grids, a suppressor grid, 4 collector plates, and collector plate outputs. 
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>National Aeronautics and Space Administration, NASA</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Justin.C.Kasper</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instruments webpage</Name>
        <URL>http://sweap.cfa.harvard.edu/SWEAP.html</URL>
        <Description>SWEAP Instrument Web Page</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>FaradayCup</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Parker Solar Probe SWEAP Investigation</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/PSP</ObservatoryID>
    <Caveats>The present SPC dataset contains two types of ion moment calculations, one called "moments" and the other called "fits". 
      The user should be aware that the data in "moments" are derived from straight integration of the SPC ion spectra. 
      It is a basic and generally robust method, albeit with various caveats as provided in the quality flags. The "fits" dataset is by contrast 
      more sensitive to the adjustments and limitations generally associated with the application of multi-component fitting procedures 
      (protons, alphas, and third peak). For those reasons, the unfamiliar user shall use the "moments" data preferentially. 
      If using the "fits" datasets, the user shall carefully check the quality flags and refer to their explanations before using that data.
    </Caveats>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
