<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/PSP/SPE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>SWEAP SPANe</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Solar Probe Analyser (SPAN) electrons</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-11-12T16:00:05Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The SPAN-A module has two ESAs to measure ions and electrons from the ram direction and nadir. SPAN-B consists of a single ESA to measure electrons from the anti-ram direction. SPAN-A is located on the ram direction side of PSP and SPAN-B is on the anti-ram side. Significant savings in mass are realized by combining the electron and ion ESAs, which was a lesson learned from FAST and THEMIS. Electrostatic deflectors extend the narrow planar intrinsic angular field of view, FOV, of each ESA to 240°?120°. Together the SPAN electron sensors provide a nearly 4? sr FOV for electrons only excluding the region of the sky blocked by the heat shield.
	      The SPAN sensors utilize the classic top-hat hemispherical ESA design developed by UCB (Carlson et al. 1983) that affords a uniform response over a planar 360° FOV. Particles entering the analyzer are selected for energy per charge, E/q, by a voltage applied to the inner hemisphere. This voltage is swept from near zero to several kV to measure ion and electron energies as low as a few eV/q to as high as 30 keV/q thus providing excellent energy coverage and resolution. Angular resolution is provided in one plane by discrete segmented anodes and out of that plane by electrostatic deflectors, resulting in a broad instrumental FOV appropriate for a non-spinning spacecraft like PSP.
	      Both ion and electron sensors use microchannel plate, MCP, detectors for particle detection, and discrete anodes for MCP charge collection. The electron sensor uses chevron-pair detectors.Pulse-counting electronics for the electron sensors utilize a multi-channel preamplifier ASIC developed by researchers at the Laboratoire de Physique du Plasmas, LPP, for the Solar Orbiter mission. 
	      SPAN-B measures electrons only and is a near duplicate of the SPAN-A e-analyzer as only the anode patterns are different. SPAN-B is mounted in an orthogonal orientation to SPAN-A and it is on the opposite side of the spacecraft. The ability of SWEAP to use the same design for both SPAN-A and SPAN-B electron sensors provides significant savings in design time and analysis.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Acknowledgement to the NASA Parker Solar Probe Mission and the SWEAP team led by J.Kasper for use of data</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Justin.C.Kasper</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nicola.J.Fox</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>SWEAP Instruments webpage</Name>
        <URL>http://sweap.cfa.harvard.edu/SWEAP.html</URL>
        <Description>SWEAP Instrument Web Page</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Parker Solar Probe SWEAP Investigation</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/PSP</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
