<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/NumericalData/CDPP-Archive/Galileo/PWS/EDR/GALILEO_PWS_EDR</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GALILEO PWS EDR</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/7ykb-ypv3</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-03-22T11:28:57Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This data set includes wideband waveform measurements from the Galileo plasma wave receiver obtained during Venus encounter (1990/02/10), the first Earth encounter (1990/11/08 – 1990/12/16) and the second Earth encounter (1992/11/08 – 1992/12/20).

These measurements are electric or magnetic waveforms obtained by rapidly sampling the potential at the input to the receiver from either the electric dipole antenna or the magnetic search coil antenna.
The sample rates are 201,600 s^-1, 25, 200 s^-1, or 3,150 s^-1 taken through bandpass filters of 80, 10, or 1 kHz, respectively.
Each sample is a 4-bit measurement after an automatic gain control (AGC) amplifier designed to keep the signal amplitude in a range commensurate with the optimal analog-to-digital converter dynamic range with a time constant of about 500 msec.

As such, the measurements are not absolutely calibrated, although it is possible to determine the approximate AGC gain from a digital performance parameter available every 2.667 seconds, assuming the signal amplitude does not vary appreciably over the 2.667 second interval.

Alternately, the sweep frequency receiver (low rate) portion of the instrument can be used to determine the absolute amplitude of waves.

In many cases, the waveform data are used without any calibration for the purposes of identifying characteristic frequencies of the plasma via resonances or cutoffs, observing discrete emissions such as chorus or whistlers, or looking at the detailed form of the waveforms.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
        Users of these data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA, CNES (Centre National d'Etudes Spatiales) and, CNRS (Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique) for their support to the GALILEO-PWS team, and the CDPP (Centre des Données de la Physique des Plasmas) for the distribution of the GALILEO-PWS data, in all publications.

If PI/coI are not part of the publication list, then we suggest to also acknowledge Donald A. Gurnett, the late Alain Roux, Charles Kennel and Scott Bolton for use of GALILEO-PWS data.	  
	  </Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Philippe.Louarn</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/William.S.Kurth</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/CDPP.general.contact</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://regards.cnes.fr/user/cdpp/modules/1777?sp=DatasetName;q=DatasetName:GALILEO_PWS_EDR</URL>
        <Description>Access via CNES Data Archive for CDPP</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Binary</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Uncalibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/Galileo/PWS</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>ElectricField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1990-02-10T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1992-12-14T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>GALILEO PWS EDR electric waveforms raw data</Name>
      <Description>GALILEO PWS EDR uncalibrated    electric  waveforms obtained by rapidly sampling the potential at the input to the receiver from either the electric dipole antenna</Description>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>GALILEO PWS EDR magnetic waveforms raw data</Name>
      <Description>GALILEO PWS EDR uncalibrated    magnetic waveforms obtained by rapidly sampling the potential at the input to the receiver from the magnetic search coil antenna.</Description>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
