<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Neptune/PT12M</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune PLS Derived RDR Ion OutBnd Magshth M_Mode 12-min V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    This data set gives the best available values for ion densities,          
    temperatures, and velocities near Neptune derived from data               
    obtained by the Voyager 2 plasma experiment.  All parameters are          
    obtained by fitting the observed spectra (current as a function of        
    energy) with Maxwellian plasma distributions, using a non-linear          
    least squares fitting routine to find the plasma parameters which,        
    when coupled with the full instrument response, best simulate the         
    data.  The PLS instrument measures energy/charge, so composition is       
    not uniquely determined but can be deduced in some cases by the           
    separation of the observed current peaks in energy (assuming the          
    plasma is co-moving).  In the upstream solar wind protons are fit to      
    the M-long data since high energy resolution is needed to obtain          
    accurate plasma parameters.  In the magnetosheath the ion flux so         
    low that several L-long spectra (3-5) had to be averaged to               
    increase the signal-to-noise ratio to a level at which the data           
    could be reliably fit.  These averaged spectra were fit using 2           
    proton Maxwellians with the same velocity. The values given in the        
    upstream magnetosheath are the total density and the                      
    density-weighted temperature.  In both the upstream solar wind and        
    magnetosheath full vector velocities, densities and temperatures          
    are derived for each fit component.  In the magnetosphere spectra         
    do not contain enough information to obtain full velocity vectors,        
    so flow is assumed to be purely azimuthal.  In some cases the             
    azimuthal velocity is a fit parameter, in some cases rigid                
    corotation is assumed.  In the &apos;outer&apos; magnetosphere (L&gt;5) two            
    distinct current peaks appear in the spectra; these are fit assuming      
    a composition of H+ and N+. In the inner magnetosphere the plasma is      
    hot and the composition is ambiguous, although two superimposed           
    Maxwellians are still required to fit the data.  These spectra are        
    fit using two compositions, one with H+ and N+ and the second with        
    two H+ components.  The N+ composition is preferred by the data           
    provider.  All fit values in the magnetosphere come with one sigma        
    errors. It should be noted that no attempt has been made to account       
    for the spacecraft potential, which is probably about -10 V in this       
    region and will effect the density and velocity values.  In the           
    outbound magnetosheath and solar wind both moment and fit values          
    are given for velocity, density, and thermal speed.  The                  
    signal-to-noise ratio in the M-longs is very low, especially near         
    the magnetopause, which can result in the analysis giving incorrect       
    values.  The L-long spectra have too low an energy resolution to          
    permit accurate determinations parameters in many regions; in             
    particular the temperature and non-radial velocity components may         
    be inaccurate.                                                            
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Parameters                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Derived Parameters                                                        
    ------------------                                                        
                                                                              
      Sampling Parameter Name             : time                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : n/a                               
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : unk                               
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Name             : ion density                       
      Noise Level                         : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : cm**-3                            
                                                                              
      Ion density: A derived parameter equaling the number of ions per        
      unit volume over a specified range of ion energy, energy/charge,        
      or energy/nucleon. Discrimination with regard to mass and or            
      charge state is necessary to obtain this quantity, however, mass        
      and charge state are often assumed due to instrument limitations.       
                                                                              
      Many different forms of ion density are derived. Some are               
      distinguished by their composition (N+, proton, ion, etc.)              
      or their method of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of                
      moments). In some cases, more than one type of density will             
      be provided in a single dataset. In general, if more than one           
      ion species is analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total density       
      will be provided which is the sum of the ion densities. If a            
      plasma component does not have a Maxwellian distribution                
      the actual distribution can be represented as the sum of                
      several Maxwellians, in which case the density of each Maxwellian       
      is given.                                                               
                                                                              
      Sampling Parameter Name             : time                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : n/a                               
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : unk                               
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Name             : ion temperature                   
      Noise Level                         : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : eV                                
                                                                              
      Ion temperature: A derived parameter giving an indication of the        
      mean energy/ion, assuming the shape of the ion energy spectrum to       
      be Maxwellian                                                           
      (i.e. highest entropy shape). Given that the                            
      ion energy spectrum is not exactly                                      
      Maxwellian, the ion temperature can be                                  
      defined integrally (whereby the mean energy                             
      obtained by integrating under the actual ion                            
      energy spectrum is set equal to the integral under a                    
      Maxwellian, where the temperature is a free                     </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-IONMMODE-12MIN-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-IONMMODE-12MIN-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-IONMMODE-12MIN-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-IONMMODE-12MIN-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PLS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-08-26T08:36:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-08-30T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT12M</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
