<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Neptune/PT96S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune PLS Derived RDR Electron Magnetosphere 96-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    The electron spectra are fit using several isotropic Maxwellian           
    distribution functions to find electron parameters.  The spacecraft       
    charge may seriously affect the density measurements. The temperature     
    of each component is, however, independent of the spacecraft potential.   
    To obtain the best estimate of the electron density, the encounter        
    period is divided into four regions and four different analysis methods   
    are used.                                                                 
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Parameters                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Derived Parameters                                                        
    ------------------                                                        
      Sampling Parameter Name             : time                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : n/a                               
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : unk                               
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Name             : electron density                  
      Noise Level                         : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : cm**-3                            
                                                                              
      Electron density: A derived parameter equaling the number of            
      electrons per unit volume over a specified range of electron            
      energy. Different forms of electron density are derived                 
      distinguished by method of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of        
      moments) or by the some selection criteria (i.e., hot electron          
      and cold electron density). In general, if more than one electron       
      component is analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total density         
      will be provided which is the sum of the electron densities. If         
      the electron do not have a Maxwellian distribution the actual           
      distribution can be represented as the sum of several Maxwellians,      
      in which case the density of each Maxwellian is given.                  
                                                                              
      Sampling Parameter Name             : time                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : n/a                               
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : unk                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : unk                               
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Name             : electron temperature              
      Noise Level                         : unk                               
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : eV                                
                                                                              
      Electron temperature: A derived parameter giving an indication of       
      the mean energy/electron, assuming the shape of the electron            
      energy spectrum to be Maxwellian (i.e. highest entropy shape).          
      Given that the electron energy spectrum is not exactly Maxwellian,      
      the electron temperature can be defined integrally (whereby the         
      mean energy obtained by integrating under the actual electron           
      energy spectrum is set equal to the integral under a Maxwellian,        
      where the temperature is a free parameter for which to solve), or       
      differentially (whereby the slopes of the actually electron energy      
      spectrum at various energies are matched to the slopes of a             
      corresponding Maxwellian). The temperature parameter is often           
      qualified with a range of applicable energies. Temperatures can be      
      angularly anisotropic. If the electrons do not have a Maxwellian        
      distribution the actual distribution can be represented as the sum      
      of several Maxwellians, each with a separate temperature.               
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Derived Parameters                                                        
    ------------------                                                        
      Electron Rate: A measured parameter equaling the number of              
      electrons hitting a particle detector per specified accumulation        
      interval. The counted electrons may or may not be discriminated as      
      to their energies (e.g. greater than E1, or between E1 and E2).         
                                                                              
      Electron Current: A measured parameter equaling the rate at which       
      negative charge is collected by a particle detector. The electrons      
      contributing to this current may be restricted by energy.               
      Electrons always have a charge of 1, so this quantity corresponds       
      directly to the electron rate.                                          
                                                                              
                                                                              
  References                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Zhang, M., J. D. Richardson, and E. C. Sittler, Jr.,                      
    Voyager 2 electron observations in the Magnetosphere                      
    of Neptune, J. Geophys. Res., in press, 1991.                             
                                                                              
    J. W. Belcher, H. S. Bridge, et al., Plasma                               
    Observations Near Neptune: Initial Results from                           
    Voyager 2, Science, 246, 1478-1483, 1989.                                 
                                                                              
    Scudder, J. D., E. C. Sittler, Jr. and H. S. Bridge,                      
    A survey of the plasma electron environment of Jupiter:                   
    a view from Voyager,                                                      
    J. Geophys. Res., 86, 8319-8342, 1981.                                    
                                                                              
    Sittler, E. C., Jr., K. W. Ogilvie and R. S. Selesnick,                   
    Survey of electrons in the Uranian magnetosphere: Voyager 2               
    observations, J. Geophys. Res., 92, 15,263-15,281, 1987.</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-ELEMAGSPHERE-96SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-ELEMAGSPHERE-96SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-ELEMAGSPHERE-96SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-ELEMAGSPHERE-96SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PLS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-08-24T14:38:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-08-25T09:23:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT96S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
