<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_3.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.3</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Darwin/Magnetometer</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Darwin Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2017-07-21T17:20:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Darwin Magnetometer station in Darwin, NT, Australia, has a Magnetometer since August 2000. 
      
        30 August, 2000
	---------------
	Installation of magnetometer VM3:
	Magnetometer enclosure was clean and dry. Magnetometer PC was setup under the bench underneath the Comms PC (tried setting up in the corner of the station hut but the ethernet cable wasn't long enough). The monitor didnt work with the magnetometer (rack mount) PC so it the monitor was swapped with the COMMS PC monitor which did work (magnetometer monitor worked with COMMS PC).  The magnetometer recording system PC then tested OK. The GPS unit was attached using an adaptor to a long piece of PVC piping. The piping was secured to the side of the building with the GPS antenna extending up above the roof of the building ~0.5 m's. The cable was run through the pipe and an existing entry point into the building. The entry point was sealed with silastic to stop intruders. The signal from the antenna was connected to the GPS-200 unit and tested to see if the date and time of the PC were being corrected properly. The date/time correction was functioning properly. The magnetometer signal cable was connected into the signal junction box. The bayonet connector was fitted at the enclosure end of the cable and the cable inlet to the enclosure was sealed with silastic. The magnetometer was placed in the enclosureand connected to test if sensible voltages could be measured coming from the instrument, which was found to be the case. The magnetometer was removed from the enclosure and stored in the building overnight. The acquisition software was on the COMMS PC was upgraded to Version 1.1.

	For more information, please read its log file.     
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ASWS Darwin Instrument Fluxgate Magenetometer Log File</Name>
	<URL>ftp://ftp-out.sws.bom.gov.au/wdc/wdc_mag/data/dwn/stn.log</URL>
	<Description>Includes Darwin magnetometer log file.</Description>
	<Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Darwin Magnetometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Darwin</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
