<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/PSP/FIELDS/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>PARKER SOLAR PROBE FIELDS - Fluxgate Magnetometer (MAG) Instrument</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-07-04T18:37:27Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Parker Solar Probe has two triaxial fluxgate magnetometers (MAG) that were developed by the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC) [Bale et al. 2016]. These instruments are similar to the ones flying on MAVEN, the van Allen Probes, STEREO, etc. Both instruments are part of the FIELDS suite and are located on a boom, at respectively 1.9 and 2.7 meters from the spacecraft. Only data from the outboard MAG are publicly available.
The MAG has a bandwidth of approximately 140 Hz and operates almost continuously during the full orbit. The time resolution for the waveforms is 150000 Hz / 2^N. During encounter phases (i.e. during a period of typically two weeks around each perihelion) either N=9, giving 292.969 samples per second or N=10, giving 146.484 samples per second. The measurement dynamic range of MAG is ±65,536 nT with a resolution of 16 bits.
Both the MAG fluxgate magnetometer and the SCM search-coil share the same clock. A merged dataset [Bowen et al, 2020] is also available, in which both measurements are combined into one single product, see SCaM.
Additional data sets from the MAG and data from other FIELDS instruments can be found on the FIELDS Data Center (https://fields.ssl.berkeley.edu/data/).
For further information, contact: Robert MacDowall (GSFC, NASA) robert.macdowall@nasa.gov
References :
FIELDS website: https://fields.ssl.berkeley.edu/
Bale, S. et al. (2016), The FIELDS Instrument Suite for Solar Probe Plus. Measuring the Coronal Plasma and Magnetic Field, Plasma Waves and Turbulence, and Radio Signatures of Solar Transients, Space Science Reviews, Volume 204, Issue 1-4, pp.49-82, doi:10.1007/s11214-016-0244-5
Bowen, T. et al. (2020), A Merged Search-Coil and Fluxgate Magnetometer Data Product for Parker Solar Probe FIELDS, Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, 125(5):e2020JA027813</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Thierry.Dudok.De.Wit</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Claire.Revillet</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Michel.Moncuquet</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Stuart.Bale</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Parker Solar Probe Mission</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/PSP</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
