<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/PWS/Saturn/PT4.0S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 1 Saturn PWS Edited Spectrum Analyzer 4.0-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
      Data Set Overview                                                       
      =================                                                       
                                                                              
      Data Set Description                                                    
      --------------------                                                    
      This data set consists of 4-second edited, wave electric                
      field intensities from the Voyager 1 Plasma Wave Receiver               
      spectrum analyzer obtained in the vicinity of the Jovian                
      magnetosphere. For each 4-second interval, a field strength             
      is determined for each of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels             
      whose center frequencies range from 10 Hertz to 56.2                    
      kiloHertz and which are logarithmically spaced in                       
      frequency, four channels per decade. The time associated                
      with each set of intensities (16 channels) is the time of               
      the beginning of the scan. During data gaps where complete              
      4-second spectra are missing, no entries exist in the file,             
      that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged in any                  
      other way. When one or more channels are missing within a               
      scan, the missing measurements are zero-filled. Data are                
      edited but not calibrated. The data numbers in this data                
      set can be plotted in raw form for event searches and                   
      simple trend analysis since they are roughly proportional               
      to the log of the electric field strength. Calibration                  
      procedures and tables are provided for use with this data               
      set; the use of these is described below.                               
                                                                              
      Use of Voyager PWS Calibration Tables                                   
                                                                              
      The Voyager PWS calibration table is given in an ASCII text             
      file named SA_CL.TAB (for Voyager-1). This provides                     
      information to convert the uncalibrated &apos;data number&apos; output            
      of the PWS 16-channel spectrum analyzer to calibrated antenna           
      voltages for each frequency channel. Following is a brief               
      description of these files and a tutorial in their                      
      application.                                                            
                                                                              
      Descriptive headers have been removed from the calibration              
      table file. The columns included are IDN, ICHAN01, ICHAN02,             
      ICHAN03, ICHAN04, ICHAN05, ICHAN06, ... ICHAN16.                        
                                                                              
      The first column lists an uncalibrated data number followed by          
      the corresponding value in calibrated volts for each of the 16          
      frequency channels of the PWS spectrum analyzer. Each line              
      contains calibrations for successive data number values                 
      ranging from 0 through 255. (Data number 0 actually represents          
      the lack of data since the baseline noise values for each               
      channel are all above that.)                                            
                                                                              
      A data analysis program may load the appropriate table into a           
      data structure and thus provide a simple look-up scheme to              
      obtain the appropriate voltage for a given data number and              
      frequency channel. For example, the following VAX FORTRAN code          
      may be used to load a calibration array for Voyager 1 PWS:              
                                                                              
        real*4 cal (16,0:255)                                                 
        open ( unit=10, file=&apos;SA_CL.TAB&apos;, status=&apos;old&apos; )                      
                                                                              
        do i=0,255                                                            
          read (10,*) idn, (cal(ichan,i),ichan=1,16)                          
        end do                                                                
        close (10)                                                            
                                                                              
      Then, given an uncalibrated data value idn for the frequency            
      channel ichan, the corresponding calibrated antenna voltage             
      would be given by the following array reference:                        
                                                                              
        volts = cal (ichan, idn)                                              
                                                                              
      This may be converted to a wave electric field amplitude by             
      dividing by the effective antenna length in meters, 7.07 m.             
      That is:                                                                
                                                                              
        efield = cal(ichan, idn) / 7.07                                       
                                                                              
      Spectral density units may be obtained by dividing the square           
      of the electric field value by the nominal frequency bandwidth          
      of the corresponding spectrum analyzer channel.                         
                                                                              
        specdens = (cal(ichan,idn)/7.07)**2 / bandwidth(ichan)                
                                                                              
      Finally, power flux may be obtained by dividing the spectral            
      density by the impedance of free space in ohms:                         
                                                                              
        pwrflux = ((cal(ichan,idn)/7.07)**2/bandwidth(ichan))/376.73          
                                                                              
      Of course, for a particular application, it may be more                 
      efficient to apply the above conversions to the calibration             
      table directly.                                                         
                                                                              
      The center frequencies and bandwidths of each PWS spectrum              
      analyzer channel for the Voyager 1 PWS are given below:                 
                                                                              
      VOYAGER 1 PWS SPECTRUM ANALYZER                                         
                                                                              
      Voyager-1                                                               
      Channel    Center Frequency      Bandwidth                              
                                                                              
      1             10.0 Hz             2.16  Hz                              
      2             17.8 Hz             3.58  Hz                              
      3             31.1 Hz             4.50  Hz                              
      4             56.2 Hz            10.7   Hz                      </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-S-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4.0SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-S-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4.0SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-S-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4.0SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-S-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4.0SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1981-08-24T00:00:47.53</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1981-08-31T23:56:46.84</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT4.0S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Saturn</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
