<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/MAG/Heliosphere.Outer/PT1H</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>VOYAGER 1 SOLAR WIND MAGNETIC FIELD HGCOORDS HOUR AVGS V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2014-12-01T10:06:36.89</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
    Data Set Overview                                                         
    =================                                                         
                                                                              
      This data set contains hour averages of the interplanetary magnetic     
      field (IMF) measurements obtained by the triaxial fluxgate magnetometer 
      experiment on Voyager 1. Identical instruments on Voyager 1 and 2 were  
      designed to measure the IMF between  Earth and Saturn (10 AU) during the
      primary Voyager mission. The  design and performance yielded absolute   
      accuracies to better than &lt; 0.1 nT. In general, each component of the   
      hourly average has an uncertainty of up  to (+/- 0.05 nT) in the region 
      beyond 10 AU. More accurate measurements can be  obtained by special    
      processing of the data, but it was not feasible to do this for the      
      entire data set included here. The magnetic field magnitude in nT is    
      provided along with angles of the field vector in the spacecraft-       
      centered Heliographic (HG) coordinate system, also known as RTN.        
                                                                              
    Coordinate System                                                         
    =================                                                         
                                                                              
      Interplanetary magnetic field studies make use of two important         
      coordinate systems, the Inertial Heliographic (IHG) coordinate system   
      and the Heliographic (HG) coordinate system.                            
                                                                              
      The IHG coordinate system is use to define the spacecraft&apos;s position.   
      The IHG system is defined with its origin at the Sun.  There are three  
      orthogonal axes, X(IHG), Y(IHG), and Z(IHG).  The Z(IHG) axis points    
      northward along the Sun&apos;s spin axis.  The X(IHG) - Y(IHG) plane lays in 
      the solar equatorial plane.  The intersection of the solar equatorial   
      plane with the ecliptic plane defines a line, the longitude of the      
      ascending node, which is taken to be the X(IHG) axis.  The X(IHG) axis  
      drifts slowly with time, approximately one degree per 72 years.         
                                                                              
      Magnetic field orientation is defined in relation to the spacecraft.    
      Drawing a line from the Sun&apos;s center (IHG origin) to the spacecraft     
      defines the X axis of the HG coordinate system.  The HG coordinate      
      system is defined with its origin centered at the spacecraft.  Three    
      orthogonal axes are defined, X(HG), Y(HG), and Z(HG).  The X(HG) axis   
      points radially away from the Sun and the Y(HG) axis is parallel to the 
      solar equatorial plane and therefore parallel to the X(IHG)-Y(IHG) plane
      too.  The Z(HG) axis is chosen to complete the orthonormal triad.       
                                                                              
      An excellent reference guide with diagrams explaining the IHG and HG    
      systems may be found in Space and Science Reviews, Volume 39 (1984),    
      pages 255-316, MHD Processes in the Outer Heliosphere, L. F. Burlaga    
      [BURLAGA1984].                                                          
                                                                              
    Data Formats                                                              
    ============                                                              
      field    description (data before 1990)                                 
      -----    ------------------------------                                 
      1. s/c id  (1 = Voyager-1, 2 = Voyager-2)                               
      2. UTC     YY DDD HH where YY=year, DDD=day, and HH=hour                
      3. X      X IHG position component (A.U. - IHG coordinates)             
      4. Y      Y IHG position component (A.U. - IHG coordinates)             
      5. Z      Z IHG position component (A.U. - IHG coordinates)             
      6. Range  Heliocentric range = sqrt(X*X+Y*Y+Z*Z)                        
      7. F1     Field magnitude (nT)  ( avg(F2(48sec)) )                      
      8. F2     Field modulus (nT)  ( norm (B1,B2,B3) )                       
      9. delta  Latitudinal angle (degrees - HG coordinates)                  
     10. lambda Longitudinal angle (degrees - HG coordinates)                 
                                                                              
      field  descriptor (data after 1990)                                     
      -----  ----------------------------                                     
        1.   s/c identification (FLT1=Voyager 1)                              
                                (FLT2=Voyager 2)                              
        2.   Time (UTC) decimal year format (90.00000 is day 1 of 1990)       
        3.   The magnetic field strength,  F1, computed from                  
               high-resolution observations.                                  
        4.   The elevation angle (degrees) in heliographic coordinates.       
        5.   The azimuthal angle (degrees) in heliographic coordinates.       
        6.   The magnetic field strength, F2, computed from hour              
               averages of the components. The components of B can be         
               computed from F2 and the two angles.                           
                                                                              
      MAG field components may be recovered using F2, delta and lambda.       
                                                                              
      BR = F2*COS(lambda)*COS(delta)      Fortran users need to convert       
      BT = F2*SIN(lambda)*COS(delta)      degrees to radians before           
      BN = F2*SIN(delta)                  using trig functions.               
                                                                              
    Contact Information                                                       
    ===================                                                       
                                                                              
      Principal Investigator:                                                 
                                                                              
      Prof. Norman F. Ness                                                    
      Bartol Research Institute                                               
      Univerity of Delaware                                                   
      Newark, Delaware 19716-4793                                             
      Phone: (302) 831-8116                                                   
      Fax: (302) 831-1843                                                     
      Email: norman.ness@mus.udel.edu                                         
                                                                              
      Data Contact:                                                           
                                                                              
      Dr. Len Burlaga                                                         
      Code 612.2                                                              
      NASA Goddard Space Flight Center                                        
      Greenbelt, MD 20771                                                     
      Tel.: 301-286-5956                                                      
      Fax: 301-286-1433                                               </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-1HR-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-1HR-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-1HR-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-1HR-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/MAG</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1977-09-05T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>2004-12-31T01:00:00.000</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT1H</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
