<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/MAG/Heliosphere.Outer/PT48S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>VOYAGER 1 SOLAR WIND MAGNETIC FIELD HGCOORDS 48SEC AVG V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2014-12-01T10:06:37.29</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
    Data Set Overview                                                         
    =================                                                         
                                                                              
      This dataset contains Voyager 1 magnetometer data from the              
      interplanetary cruise averaged to 48 second samples in Heliographic     
      coordinates.                                                            
                                                                              
    Data Processing                                                           
    ===============                                                           
      The high resolution data submitted to the NSSDC has its origins in the  
      original MVS &apos;Summary&apos; data sets formally produced on the NSSC IBM MVS  
      mainframe system.  The original data sets contain a mix of engineering, 
      electron, magnetic field and plasma data.  The Voyager magnetometer     
      (MAG) experiment now resides on a dedicated workstation where only MAG  
      data are processed.                                                     
                                                                              
      All Voyager MAG data submitted to the NSSDC consists wholly of high     
      resolution LFM averages.  These files consist of a set of averages      
      applied across all of the mission&apos;s differing telemetry modes.  In the  
      case of the Magnetometer Experiment, the records contain both           
      1.92 second, 9.6 second and 48 second averages.  1.92 second averages   
      are created from the detail detail data, 9.6 second averages are created
      from 1.92 second averages and 48 second averages are created from the   
      9.6 second averages.                                                    
                                                                              
      All data in this NSSDC data set are interplanetary and in heliographic  
      coordinates (see below). An ASCII formated data set containing key      
      components of the 48 second magnetic field data and ephemeris data has  
      been created allowing more convenient access to high resolution Voyager 
      magnetometer data.                                                      
                                                                              
    Coordinate System                                                         
    =================                                                         
                                                                              
      Interplanetary magnetic field studies make use of two important         
      coordinate systems, the Inertial Heliographic (IHG) coordinate system   
      and the Heliographic (HG) coordinate system.                            
                                                                              
      The IHG coordinate system is use to define the spacecraft&apos;s position.   
      The IHG system is defined with its origin at the Sun.  There are three  
      orthogonal axes, X(IHG), Y(IHG), and Z(IHG).  The Z(IHG) axis points    
      northward along the Sun&apos;s spin axis.  The X(IHG) - Y(IHG) plane lays in 
      the solar equatorial plane.  The intersection of the solar equatorial   
      plane with the ecliptic plane defines a line, the longitude of the      
      ascending node, which is taken to be the X(IHG) axis.  The X(IHG) axis  
      drifts slowly with time, approximately one degree per 72 years.         
                                                                              
      Magnetic field orientation is defined in relation to the spacecraft.    
      Drawing a line from the Sun&apos;s center (IHG origin) to the spacecraft     
      defines the X axis of the HG coordinate system.  The HG coordinate      
      system is defined with its origin centered at the spacecraft.  Three    
      orthogonal axes are defined, X(HG), Y(HG), and Z(HG).  The X(HG) axis   
      points radially away from the Sun and the Y(HG) axis is parallel to the 
      solar equatorial plane and therefore parallel to the X(IHG)-Y(IHG) plane
      too.  The Z(HG) axis is chosen to complete the orthonormal triad.       
                                                                              
      An excellent reference guide with diagrams explaining the IHG and HG    
      systems may be found in Space and Science Reviews, Volume 39 (1984),    
      pages 255-316, MHD Processes in the Outer Heliosphere, L. F. Burlaga    
      [BURLAGA1984].                                                          
                                                                              
    Data Format                                                               
    ===========                                                               
      field  descriptor                                                       
      -----  ----------                                                       
        1.   s/c identification (FLT1=Voyager 1)                              
                                (FLT2=Voyager 2)                              
                                                                              
        2.   coordinate system                                                
                                (HG=heliographic)used for this data set       
                                                                              
        3.   Time (UTC) format  YY DDD HH MM SS MSS                           
                                YY  = year                                    
                                DDD = day of year                             
                                HH  = hour                                    
                                MM  = minute                                  
                                SS  = second                                  
                                MSS = millisecond                             
        4.   field magnitude (nT)                                             
        5.   field component 1 (nT) - HG                                      
        6.   field component 2 (nT) - HG                                      
        7.   field component 3 (nT) - HG                                      
        8.   spacecraft radial distance (AU)                                  
        9.   spacecraft x position (AU) - IHG                                 
       10.   spacecraft y position (AU) - IHG                                 
       11.   spacecraft z position (AU) - IHG                                 
                                                                              
    Contact Information                                                       
    ===================                                                       
                                                                              
      Principal Investigator:                                                 
                                                                              
      Prof. Norman F. Ness                                                    
      Bartol Research Institute                                               
      Univerity of Delaware                                                   
      Newark, Delaware 19716-4793                                             
      Phone: (302) 831-8116                                                   
      Fax: (302) 831-1843                                                     
      Email: norman.ness@mus.udel.edu                                         
                                                                              
    Acknowledgement                                                   </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-SW-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/MAG</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1977-09-05T14:19:47.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-12-31T22:08:33.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT48S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
