<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Neptune/PT0.60S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune PWS Raw Experiment Waveform 60-ms V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    This data set consists of electric field waveform samples from the        
    Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver waveform receiver obtained during          
    the Neptune encounter. The waveforms are collections of 4-bit             
    samples of the electric field measured by the dipole electric antenna     
    at a rate of 28,800 samples per second.  1600 samples are collected       
    in 55.56 msec followed by a 4.44-msec gap. Each 60-msec interval          
    constitutes a line of waveform samples. The data set includes about 271   
    frames of waveform samples consisting of up to 800 lines, each.  The      
    telemetry format for the waveform data is identical to that for           
    images, hence the use of line and frame as constructs in describing       
    the form of the data.  The waveform is sampled through a bandpass         
    filter with a passband of 40 Hz to 12 kHz.  The 4-bit samples             
    provide sixteen digital values of the electric field with a               
    linear amplitude scale, but the amplitude scale is arbitrary              
    because of the automatic gain control used in the waveform                
    receiver.  The instantaneous dynamic range afforded by the 4              
    bit samples is about 23 db, but the automatic gain control allows         
    the dominant signal in the passband to be set at the optimum              
    level to fit within the instantaneous dynamic range.  With the gain       
    control, the overall dynamic range of the waveform receiver               
    is about 100 db.  The automatic gain control gain setting is not          
    returned to the ground, hence, there is no absolute calibration           
    for the data.  However, by comparing the waveform spectrum derived        
    by Fourier transforming the waveform to the spectrum provided by          
    the spectrum analyzer data, an absolute calibration may be                
    obtained in most cases.  The data may be plotted in raw form to           
    show the actual waveform; this is useful for studying events such         
    as dust impacts on the spacecraft.  But the normal method of              
    analyzing the waveform data is by Fourier transforming the samples        
    from each line to arrive at an amplitude versus frequency spectrum.       
    By stacking the spectra side-by-side in time order, a frequency-          
    time spectrogram can be produced.                                         
                                                                              
    Additional information about this dataset and the instrument which        
    produced it can be found elsewhere in this catalog.  An overview of       
    the data in this data set can be found in Gurnett et al. [1989] and       
    a complete instrument description can be found in Scarf and Gurnett       
    [1977].                                                                   
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Parameters                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Derived Parameters                                                        
    ------------------                                                        
                                                                              
      Sampling Parameter Name             : time                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : 0.000034722 seconds               
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : n/a                               
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : n/a                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : 0.000034722 seconds               
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : 0.000034722 seconds               
      Data Set Parameter Name             : plasma wave waveform              
      Noise Level                         : 0.000005                          
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : volt/meter (Data not              
                                                        absolutely            
                                                        calibrated)           
                                                                              
      Plasma wave waveform: A plasma wave waveform is a time series of        
      measurements of the electric or magnetic field component of the         
      wave spectrum taken through a broadband filter.  The temporal           
      sample rate is normally such that samples are made at more than         
      twice the analysis filter bandwidth.  A typical waveform will           
      consist of the order of 1000 contiguous samples of between 4 and        
      12 bits each.  For a 10-kHz analysis bandwidth, the sample rate         
      would normally be approximately 25 kHz or 25,000 samples/second.        
      Once received, the waveforms are typically Fourier transformed in       
      order to provide an amplitude versus frequency spectrum across          
      the analysis bandwidth.  The sample rate, then, is required to be       
      at least a factor of two greater than the filter bandwidth in           
      order to avoid aliasing in the transformed spectrum.  The spectra       
      can be stacked side-by-side in time to build a frequency-time           
      spectrogram (that is, amplitude as a function of time and               
      frequency) in order to identify the temporal and spectral               
      variations in the wave spectrum.  Alternately, the untransformed        
      time series can be used to study the details of the waveform.           
      This has been useful for measuring small-scale structures in the        
      plasma and for identifying the signature of micron-sized dust           
      impact on the spacecraft.                                               
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Measured Parameters                                                       
    -------------------                                                       
      Electric field component: A measured parameter equaling the electric    
      field strength (e.g. in milli-volts per meter) along a particular       
      axis direction.                                                         
                                                                              
      Wave magnetic field intensity: A measured parameter equaling the        
      magnetic field strength in a specific frequency passband (in MKS        
      unit: volts/meter) measured in a single sensor or antenna.              
                                                                              
      Wave electric field intensity: A measured parameter equaling the        
      electric field strength in a specific frequency passband (in MKS        
      unit: volts/meter) measured in a single sensor or antenna.              
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Processing                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
    The data files in this data set were created using the &apos;CDREF&apos;    </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-06-06T14:16:56.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-09-27T17:52:43.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT0.60S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
