<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Neptune/PT4S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune PWS Edited RDR Uncalib Spectrum Analyzer 4-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    This data set consists of 4-second edited, wave electric field            
    intensities from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver (PWS) spectrum        
    analyzer obtained in the vicinity of the Neptunian magnetosphere.         
    For each 4-second interval, a field strength is determined for each       
    of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels whose center frequencies range       
    from 10 Hertz to 56.2 kiloHertz and which are logarithmically             
    spaced in frequency, four channels per decade.  The time associated       
    with each set of intensities (16 channels) is the time of the             
    beginning of the scan.  During data gaps where complete 4-second          
    spectra are missing, no entries exist in the file, that is, the           
    gaps are not zero-filled or tagged in any other way.  When one or         
    more channels are missing within a scan, the missing measurements         
    are zero-filled.  Data are edited but not calibrated.  The data           
    numbers in this data set can be plotted in raw form for event             
    searches and simple trend analysis since they are roughly                 
    proportional to the log of the electric field strength.                   
    Calibration procedures and tables are provided for use with this          
    data set;  the use of these is described below.                           
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Parameters                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Derived Parameters                                                        
    ------------------                                                        
                                                                              
      Sampling Parameter Name             : TIME                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : 4.0 seconds                       
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : N/A                               
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : N/A                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : 4.0 seconds                       
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : 4.0 seconds                       
      Data Set Parameter Name             : plasma wave spectrum              
      Noise Level                         : 0.000005 V/m                      
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : volts/meter                       
                                                                              
      Plasma wave spectrum: A set of derived parameters consisting of         
      wave electric field intensities or electric field spectral              
      densities at various contiguous frequencies over                        
      a range of frequencies. The MKS units are: volts/meter or               
      volts**2/(hertz.meter**2), respectively.                                
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Measured Parameters                                                       
    -------------------                                                       
      Electric field component: A measured parameter equaling the             
      electric field strength (e.g. in milli-volts per meter) along           
      a particular axis direction.                                            
                                                                              
      Wave magnetic field intensity: A measured parameter equaling            
      the magnetic field strength in a specific frequency passband            
      (in MKS unit: volts/meter) measured in a single sensor or antenna.      
                                                                              
      Wave electric field intensity: A measured parameter equaling the        
      electric field strength in a specific frequency passband                
      (in MKS unit: volts/meter) measured in a single sensor or antenna.      
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Processing                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
    The data files in this data set were created using the &apos;CDMAKE&apos;           
    software.                                                                 
                                                                              
    CDMAKE                                                                    
    ------                                                                    
      Node ID                             : PPI-IOWA                          
      Software Release Date               : 1988-08-01                        
      Cognizant Full Name                 : MR. LARRY J. GRANROTH             
                                                                              
      CDMAKE is primarily a data format translation routine which is used     
      to convert Voyager Plasma Wave Spectrometer (PWS) MSF tape files to     
      CD files.  The MSF, or Master Science Files, are produced at the        
      University of Iowa as the primary, ordered, full-information PWS        
      spectrum analyzer data set.  The CD files contain uncalibrated,         
      full-resolution PWS data with minimal ancillary data in a               
      simplified format which may be used in CDROM production.                
                                                                              
      NOTE: SOFTWARE IS NOT AVAILABLE FOR PUBLIC USE.                         
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Use of Voyager PWS Calibration Tables                                     
    -------------------------------------                                     
      The Voyager PWS calibration tables are given in two plain ASCII         
      text files named VG1PWSCL.TAB and VG2PWSCL.TAB (for Voyagers-1 and      
      -2, respectively).  These provide information to convert the            
      uncalibrated `data number&apos; output of the PWS 16-channel spectrum        
      analyzer to calibrated antenna voltages for each frequency channel.     
      These calibration files are always provided with the dataset when       
      the data are extracted from PDS by a user. Following is a brief         
      description of these files and a tutorial in their application.         
                                                                              
      The first column lists an uncalibrated data number followed by the      
      corresponding value in calibrated volts for each of the 16              
      frequency channels of the PWS spectrum analyzer.  Each line             
      contains calibrations for successive data number values ranging         
      from 0 through 255.  (Data number 0 actually represents the lack of     
      data since the baseline noise values for each channel are all above     
      that.)                                                                  
                                                                      </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-08-21T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-08-31T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT4S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
