<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.5.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://IUGONET/Instrument/TohokuU/radio_obs/iit/amateras</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>IPRT/AMATERAS</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2013-07-11T12:00:00</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>A new radio spectropolarimeter for solar radio observation has been developed at Tohoku University and installed on the Iitate Planetary Radio Telescope (IPRT) at the Iitate observatory in Fukushima prefecture, Japan. This system, named AMATERAS (the Assembly of Metric-band Aperture TElescope and Real-time Analysis System), enables us to observe solar radio bursts in the frequency range between 150 and 500 MHz. The minimum detectable flux in the observation frequency range is less than 0.7 SFU with an integration time of 10 ms and a bandwidth of 61 kHz. Both left and right polarization components are simultaneously observed in this system. These specifications are accomplished by combining the large aperture of IPRT with a high-speed digital receiver. Observational data are calibrated and archived soon after the daily observation. The database is available online. The high-sensitivity observational data with the high time and frequency resolutions from AMATERAS will be used to analyze spectral fine structures of solar radio bursts.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Hiroaki.Misawa</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Kazumasa.Iwai</PersonID>
            <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Manabu.Yagi</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <URL>http://pparc.gp.tohoku.ac.jp/data/iprt/</URL>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>IPRT/AMATERAS (Iitate Planetary Radio Telescope / the Assembly of Metric-band Aperture TElescope and Real-time Analysis System)</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://IUGONET/Observatory/TohokuU/radio_obs/iitate</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
