<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/GIOTTO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GIOTTO</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-10-08T10:47:09Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The purpose of the Giotto mission was to study Comet Halley during its closest passage to the Sun (known as perihelion) in 1986.

No-one expected the spacecraft to survive its battering from comet dust during this encounter. However, although Giotto was damaged during the flyby, most of its instruments remained operational. To the scientists' delight, the mission was extended to allow an unprecedented encounter with a second comet, Grigg-Skjellerup. In 1992, after a long hibernation, Giotto was reawakened for the closest ever cometary flyby.

The major objectives of the original mission were to:

    Obtain the first close-up images of a comet nucleus
    Determine the elemental and isotopic composition of ices in the cometary coma
    Study the physical and chemical processes that occur in the comet's atmosphere
    Determine the elemental and isotopic composition of cometary dust particles
    Measure the comet's total gas-production rate
    Measure the amount of dust around the comet and its size/mass distribution
    Determine the relative amounts of dust and gas in the near-comet environment
    Investigate the interaction between the comet and the electrically charged particles of the solar wind</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Christian.Mazelle</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Comet</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
    <OperatingSpan>
      <StartDate>1985-07-02T00:00:00</StartDate>
      <StopDate>1992-07-23T00:00:00</StopDate>
    </OperatingSpan>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
