<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_6_1.xsd">
   <Version>2.6.1</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://ESA/Instrument/SolarOrbiter/PHI</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Polarimetric and Helioseismic Imager (PHI)</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2024-12-23T00:08:46</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2024-12-23T00:08:46</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Metadata created by SY</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The Polarimetric and Helioseismic Imager (PHI) is a solar polarimeter and magnetograph designed to measure the vector magnetic field and line-of-sight velocity in the solar photosphere. The science objectives for PHI are to: investigate the links between the solar surface, corona, and inner heliosphere; explore, at all latitudes, the energetics, dynamics and fine-scale structure of the Sun’s magnetized atmosphere; and probe the solar dynamo by observing the Sun’s high-latitude field, flows and seismic waves.

PHI is a diffraction limited, wavelength tunable, quasi-monochromatic, polarization sensitive imager with two telescopes; a High Resolution Telescope (HRT) and a Full-Disc Telescope (FDT) which alternatively feed a common filtergraph and a 2048 x 2048 pixel focal plane array. The working wavelength is 617.3 nm (Fe spectral line). The instrument is mounted behind the sunshield, with heat-rejecting entrance window apertures for the telescopes. It is made of an aluminum-beryllium alloy and low-expansion carbon-fiber reinforced plastic. The HRT is a decentered Ritchey-Chretien design with a 140mm diameter pupil. It has a field-of-view of 0.28 x 0.28 degrees and a spatial resolution of about 200 km at closest perihelion. The FDT has an entrance pupil diameter of 17.5 mm and an effective focal length of 579 mm. The field-of-view is 2 degrees, resolution at 0.28 AU is 725 km/pixel.

The filtergraph consists of a lithium niobide (LiNbO3) solid-state etalon which can change refractive index as a function of voltage and select passbands of order 100 milliangstroms wide. A Polarization Modulation Package performs polarimetric analysis for each telescope. It comprises two nematic liquid crystal retarders and a linear polarizer analyzer.

For more detailed information on PHI, see:
https://arxiv.org/pdf/1502.03368.pdf</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Solar Orbiter is a mission of international cooperation between the European Space Agency (ESA) and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), operated by ESA.</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Sami.K.Solanki</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Joachim.Woch</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>NASA NSSDCA Master Catalog</Name>
            <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2020-010A-03</URL>
            <Description>NSSDCA Master Catalog Listing for the Solar Orbiter PHI</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>The Solar Orbiter PHI Website</Name>
            <URL>https://www.mps.mpg.de/solar-physics/solar-orbiter-phi</URL>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>The PHI instrument  paper</Name>
            <URL>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/201935325</URL>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Polarimetric and Helioseismic Imager (PHI)</InvestigationName>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2020-02-10T04:03:00</StartDate>
         <Note>The start date and time listed here correspond to when Solar Orbiter was launched</Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://ESA/Observatory/SolarOrbiter</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
