<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_8.xsd">
   <Version>2.6.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://NASA/Instrument/ELFIN/A/EPD</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>The Electron Losses and Fields Investigation (ELFIN) mission Energetic Particle Detector for Electrons</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2024-04-26T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>ELFIN will be flying two energetic particle detectors (EPDs). It has one EPD for ions (EPDI) and one for electrons (EPDE). The EPDE is designed to handle energy in the ranges of 50keV to 4.5MeV while the EPDI is designed for 50 to 300keV.

                      Both of these sensors are designed to have a field of view narrower than the loss cone. As a result, ELFIN will be the first mission to provide pitch-angle resolved, high-energy measurements of relativistic electron fluxes from within the loss cone. No other mission has taken this particular view of the radiation belts and this puts ELFIN in a position to deliver unique science to the community.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge NASA award NNX14AN68G and NSF awards AGS-1242918 and AGS-2019950, V. Angelopoulos for use of EPD/FGM data from the ELFIN Mission.</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Vassilis.Angelopoulos</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>ELFIN mission Energetic Particle Detector for Electrons</Name>
            <URL>https://elfin.igpp.ucla.edu/instruments</URL>
            <Description>Some Information and Details on the Energetic Particle Detector.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
		 <InformationURL>
            <Name>Space Science Review Article on the ELFIN Mission</Name>
            <URL>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11214-020-00721-7</URL>
            <Description>Information and Details on the ELFIN mission and the Energetic Particle Detector.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>SolidStateDetector</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>The Electron Losses and Fields Investigation (ELFIN) mission</InvestigationName>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2018-12-01T00:00:00</StartDate>
		 <StopDate>2022-09-11T23:59:59</StopDate>
      </OperatingSpan>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ELFIN/A</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
