<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/CRS/Jupiter/PT15M</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 1 Jupiter CRS Derived Proton_Ion_Electron Flux Browse V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>

  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Instrument P.I.       : Rochus E. Vogt
    Data Supplier         : National Space Science Data Center
    Data sampling rate    : variable (1 hr for FPHA data, 15 min.
                            for all others)

    Data Set Start Time   : 1979-02-28T00:00:00.000Z
    Data Set Stop Time    : 1979-03-21T23:45:00.000Z

    (The following description has been adapted from
    [NSSDCCRS1979])

    As its name implies, the Cosmic Ray Subsystem (CRS) was
    designed for cosmic ray studies [STONEETAL1977B].  It consists
    of two high Energy Telescopes (HET), four Low Energy Telescopes
    (LET) and The Electron Telescope (TET).  The detectors have
    large geometric factors (~ 0.48 to 8 cm^2 ster) and long
    electronic time constants (~ 24 [micro]sec) for low power
    consumption and good stability.  Normally, the data are
    primarily derived from comprehensive ([Delta]E[1], [Delta]E[2]
    and E) pulse-height information about individual events.
    Because of the high particle fluxes encountered at Jupiter and
    Saturn, greater reliance had to be placed on counting rates in
    single detectors and various coincidence rates.  In inter-
    planetary space, guard counters are placed in anticoincidence
    with the primary detectors to reduce the background from
    high-energy particles penetrating through the sides of the
    telescopes.  These guard counters were turned off in the Jovian
    magnetosphere when the accidental anticoincidence rate became
    high enough to block a substantial fraction of the desired
    counts.  Fortunately, under these conditions the spectra were
    sufficiently soft that the background, due to penetrating
    particles, was small.

    The data on proton and ion fluxes at Jupiter were obtained with
    the LET.  The thicknesses of individual solid-state detectors
    in the LET and their trigger thresholds were chosen such that,
    even in the Jovian magnetosphere, electrons made, at most, a
    very minor contribution to the proton counting rates
    [LUPTON&amp;STONE1972].  Dead time corrections and accidental
    coincidences were small (&lt; 20%) throughout most of the
    magnetotail, but were substantial (&gt; 50%) at flux maxima within
    40 R[J] Of Jupiter.  Data have been included in this package
    for those periods when the corrections are less than ~ 50% and
    can be corrected by the user with the dead time appropriate to
    the detector (2 to 25 [micro]sec).  The high counting rates,
    however, caused some baseline shift which may have raised
    proton thresholds significantly.  In the inner magnetosphere,
    the L[2] counting rate was still useful because it never rolled
    over.  This rate is due to 1.8- to 13-MeV protons penetrating
    L[1] (0.43 cm^2 ster) and &gt; 9-MeV protons penetrating the
    shield (8.4 cm^2 ster).  For an E^-2 spectrum, the two groups
    would make comparable contributions; but in the magnetosphere,
    for the E^-3 to E^-4 spectrum above 2.5 MeV [MCDONALDETAL1979],
    the contribution from protons penetrating the shield would be
    only 3 to 14%.

    The LET L[1]L[2]L[4] and L[1]L[2]L[3] coincidence-
    anticoincidence rates give the proton flux between 1.8 and 8
    MeV and 3 to 8 MeV with a small alpha particle contribution
    (~10^-3).  Corrections are required for dead time losses in
    L[1], accidental L[1]L[2] coincidences and anticoincidence
    losses from L[4].  Data are given only for periods when these
    corrections are relatively small.  In addition to the rates
    listed in the table, the energy lost in detectors L[1], L[2]
    and L[3] was measured for individual particles.  For protons,
    this covered the energy range from 0.42 to 8.3 MeV.  Protons
    can be identified positively by the [Delta]E vs.  E technique,
    their spectra obtained and accidental coincidences greatly
    reduced.  Because of telemetry limitations, however, only a
    small fraction of the events could be transmitted, and
    statistics become poor unless pulse-height data are averaged
    over a period of one hour.

    HET and LET detectors share the same data lines and pulse-
    height analyzers; thus, the telescopes can interfere with one
    another during periods of high counting rates.  To prevent such
    an interference and explore different coincidence conditions,
    the experiment was cycled through four operating modes, each
    192 seconds long.  Either the HETs or the LETs were turned on
    at a time.  LET-D was cycled through L[1] only and L[1]L[2]
    coincidence requirements.  The TET was cycled through various
    coincidence conditions, including singles from the front
    detectors.  At the expense of some time resolution, this
    procedure permitted us to obtain significant data in the outer
    magnetosphere and excellent data during the long passage
    through the magnetotail region.

    Some of the published results from this experiment required
    extensive corrections for dead time, accidental coincidences
    and anticoincidences ([VOGTETAL1979A], [VOGTETAL1979B];
    [SCHARDTETAL1981]; [GEHRELS1981]).  These corrections can be
    applied only on a case-by-case basis after a careful study of
    the environment and many self-consistency checks.  They cannot
    be applied on a systematic basis and we have no computer
    programs to do so; therefore, data from such periods are not
    included in the Data Center submission.  The scientists on the
    CRS team will, however, be glad to consider special requests if
    the desired information can be extracted from the data.


    Description of the Data
    -----------------------
      (1) LD1 RATE gives the nominal &gt; 0.43-MeV proton flux cm^-2
          s^-1 sr^-1. This rate includes all particles which pass
          through a 0.8 mg/cm^2 aluminum foil and deposits more than
          220 keV in a 34.6 [micron] Si detector on Voyager 1 (209
          keV, 33.9 [microns] on Voyager 2) Therefore, heavy ions,
          such as oxygen and sulfur are also detected; however,
          their contribution is believed to be relatively small.
          Only a small percentage of the pulses in this detector are
          larger than the maximum energy that can be deposited by a
          proton.  Heavy ions would produce such large pulses,
          unless their energy spectra were much steeper than the
          proton spectrum. The true flux, F[t], can be calculated
          from the data:

                                      F
                       F[t]  = ----------------
                               1 - 1.26x10^-4 F

           and corrections are small for F &lt; 1000 cm^-2 s^-1.


      (2) LD2 RATE is not suitable for an absolute flux
          determination and is given in counters per s. The detector
          responds to protons and ions that penetrate either (a) 0.8
          mg/cm^2 Al plus 8.0 mg/cm^2 Si and lose at least 200 keV
          in a 35 [micron] Si detector (1.8 to 13 MeV) or (b) pass
          through &gt; 140 mg/cm^2 Al. For an E^-2 proton spectrum, the
          contributions from (a) and (b) would be about equal;
          however, the proton spectrum is substantially softer
          throughout most of the magnetosphere and the detector
          should respond primarily to (a). Dead time corrections
          are given by

                                     R
                      R[t]  = ----------------
                              1 - 2.55x10^-5 R


           where R is the count rate in counts/s. Thus, correction to
           the supplied data are small for R &lt; 4000 c/sec, but become
           80 large in the middle magnetosphere that the magnitude of
           even relative intensity changes becomes uncertain.

      (3) LD L[1].L[2]. L[4]. SL COINCIDENCE RATE gives the total
          proton flux (cm^-2 s^-1 sr^-1) between ~ 1.8 and ~ 8.1 MeV
          with a small admixture of alpha particles. Accidental
          coincidences become subst</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-J-CRS-5-SUMM-FLUX-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-J-CRS-5-SUMM-FLUX-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-J-CRS-5-SUMM-FLUX-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-J-CRS-5-SUMM-FLUX-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/CRS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1979-02-28T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1979-03-21T23:45:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT15M</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
