<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/Galileo/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>MAG</ResourceName>    
      <AlternateName>Galileo Magnetometer</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2014-07-30T21:10:13Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The magnetometer (MAG) on Galileo was used to: 
        * map the configuration of the Jovian magnetosphere and analyze its dynamics; 
        * examine magnetospheric-ionospheric coupling; 
        * measure fluctuations in the ambient magnetic field; 
        * determine whether the Galilean satellites have intrinsic magnetic fields; and, 
        * investigate the nature of the magnetosphere's interaction with the satellites. 
        
        In addition to these primary goals, the magnetometer was also used to make extensive studies of the interplanetary medium, 
        the solar wind interaction with the asteroids Gaspra and Ida, and the Earth's magnetosphere.
        The system consisted of two triaxial fluxgate magnetometers, one placed at the end of a boom 11.03 m from the spacecraft
        spin axis, the other on the same boom but at a distance of 6.87 m from the spin axis. This dual magnetometer configuration,
        used to provide a real-time estimate of the spacecraft-generated magnetic field as well as providing redundancy in the 
        in situ measurements, was similar to that of instruments used on other missions (e.g., Voyager). The outboard sensors
        had dynamic ranges of +/-32 nT and +/-512 nT while those of the inboard sensors were +/-512 nT and +/-16,384 nT.
        This limitation to two ranges for each magnetometer assembly optimized the design to achieve low noise levels and small 
        offsets. In addition, the lower range of the outboard sensors was designed for solar wind and distant Jovian magnetotail 
        measurements whereas the higher range of the inboard sensor was intended for the inner Jovian magnetosphere.
        
        Calibrations for the instrument were performed in-flight using a calibration coil which generated a known magnetic field 
        at a set frequency, thus permitting the signal to be identified even when the ambient field was not entirely quiet. 
        This calibration method also permitted the orientation of the sensors to be well determined.
    </Description>
      <Contact>
              <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Margaret.Galland.Kivelson</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
      </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Galileo Magnetometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/Galileo</ObservatoryID>
    </Instrument>
</Spase>
