<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/Galileo/PLS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>PLS</ResourceName>    
      <AlternateName>Plasma Science</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2017-07-30T21:10:13Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
        The plasma instrumentation (PLS) for the Galileo Mission comprises a nested set of four spherical-plate electrostatic analyzers 
        and three miniature, magnetic mass spectrometers. 
        
        The three-dimensional velocity distributions of positive ions and electrons,  
        separately, are determined for the energy-per-unit charge (E/Q) range of 0.9 V to 52 kV. A large fraction of the 4-pi-steradian 
        solid angle for charged particle velocity vectors is sampled by means of the fan-shaped field-of-view of 160°, multiple sensors, 
        and the rotation of the spacecraft spinning section. 
        
        The fields-of-view of the three mass spectrometers are respectively directed  
        perpendicular and nearly parallel and antiparallel to the spin axis of the spacecraft. These mass spectrometers are used to 
        identify the composition of the positive ion plasmas, e.g., H+, O+, Na+ and S+, in the Jovian magnetosphere. The energy range of 
        these three mass spectrometers is dependent upon the species. The maximum temporal resolutions of the instrument for determining 
        the energy (E/Q) spectra of charged particles and mass (M/Q) composition of positive ion plasmas are 0.5 second. 
        
        Three-dimensional
        velocity distributions of electrons and positive ions require a minimum sampling time of one spacecraft rotation, 
        typically 18.3 to 19.8 seconds. The two instrument microprocessors provide the capability of inflight implementation of operational 
        modes by ground-command that are tailored for specific plasma regimes, e.g., magnetosheath, plasma sheet, cold and hot tori, and 
        satellite wakes, and that can be improved upon as acquired knowledge increases during the tour of the Jovian magnetosphere.
        
        Because the instrument is specifically designed for measurements in the environs of Jupiter with the advantages of previous 
        surveys with the Voyager spacecraft, first determinations of many plasma phenomena can be expected. These observational objectives 
        include field-aligned currents, three-dimensional ion bulk flows, pickup ions from the Galilean satellites, the spatial 
        distribution of plasmas throughout most of the magnetosphere and including the magnetotail, and ion and electron flows to and 
        from the Jovian ionosphere.
    </Description>
      <Contact>
              <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Louis.A.Frank</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instrument home page at University of Iowa</Name>
        <URL>http://www-pi.physics.uiowa.edu/www/pls/</URL>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Particle Plasma Investigation</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/Galileo</ObservatoryID>
    </Instrument>
</Spase>
