<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema   http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.3.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://GBO/NumericalData/SanMarco-DL/EFI/PT0.5S</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>San Marco-DL Electric Field AC and DC Data</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2020-07-03T23:28:58Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This San Marco D/L Electric Field Experiment (EFI) data set was provided 
by the PI team on 12 magnetic tapes in ASCII format and constitutes the 
final EFI archiving product (filename: yymmddhhmm.dc). The data from the
first tape are available online in this directory. The following parameters 
have been archived: (A) DC electric field (8 points per second) along 
the X and Y axes in spacecraft coordinates; (B) Variational (AC) electric 
fields averaged at 0.5 second intervals for all channels of each of the 
three spectrometers; (C) Some orbital parameters such as the altitude of 
the satellite, the geographic longitude and latitude, the local solar 
time and the dip latitude, and a day/night flag for the DC data; (D) Non-
reduced plasma ion densities measured by the Ion Velocity Instrument 
(IVI). The DC portion of the EFI experiment is only valid for non-reduced 
IVI data &gt; 2.5 volts corresponding roughly to an electron density of 10^4 
electrons per cubic centimeter. Note that the AC data is valid at all 
plasma densities. More details can be found in the acformat_sfdu.txt and the 
voldesc_sfdu.txt files. Both of these files are ASCII text files.

Further details about the San Marco spacecraft, experiment, and data sets 
can be found at the San Marco home page, http://crpsm.psm.uniroma1.it/ 
 </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge NASA Space Physics Data Facility, National Space Science Data Center and the Principal Investigator for data usage.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Thomas.L.Aggson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/SanMarco-DL/EFI/PT0.5S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
        <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/san_marco/electric_fields_efi/</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
        <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/san_marco/electric_fields_efi/</URL>
        <Description>In CDF via HTTP from SPDF</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProviderProcessingLevel>CALIBRATED</ProviderProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/SanMarco-DL/EFI</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ElectricField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1988-04-20T00:00:00</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1988-06-19T07:00:00</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT0.5S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Thermosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
