<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Uranus/PT4S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Uranus PWS Edited RDR Uncalib Spectrum Analyzer 4-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>
          This data set consists of 4-second edited, wave electric
          field intensities from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver
          spectrum analyzer obtained in the vicinity of the Uranian
          magnetosphere. For each 4-second interval, a field strength
          is determined for each of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels
          whose center frequencies range from 10 Hertz to 56.2
          kiloHertz and which are logarithmically spaced in
          frequency, four channels per decade. The time associated
          with each set of intensities (16 channels) is the time of
          the beginning of the scan. During data gaps where complete
          4-second spectra are missing, no entries exist in the file,
          that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged in any
          other way. When one or more channels are missing within a
          scan, the missing measurements are zero-filled. Data are
          edited but not calibrated. The data numbers in this data
          set can be plotted in raw form for event searches and
          simple trend analysis since they are roughly proportional
          to the log of the electric field strength. Calibration
          procedures and tables are provided for use with this data
          set; the use of these is described below.

                        Use of Voyager PWS Calibration Tables


          The Voyager PWS calibration tables are given in two plain
          ASCII text files named VG1PWSCL.TAB and VG2PWSCL.TAB (for
          Voyagers-1 and -2, respectively). These provide information
          to convert the uncalibrated `data number&apos; output of the PWS
          16-channel spectrum analyzer to calibrated antenna voltages
          for each frequency channel. Following is a brief
          description of these files and a tutorial in their
          application.

          The first column lists an uncalibrated data number followed
          by the corresponding value in calibrated volts for each of
          the 16 frequency channels of the PWS spectrum analyzer.
          Each line contains calibrations for successive data number
          values ranging from 0 through 255. (Data number 0 actually
          represents the lack of data since the baseline noise values
          for each channel are all above that.)

          A data analysis program may load the appropriate table into
          a data structure and thus provide a simple look-up scheme
          to obtain the appropriate voltage for a given data number
          and frequency channel. For example, the following VAX
          FORTRAN code may be used to load a calibration array for
          Voyager 2 PWS:

           real*4 cal (16,0:255)
           open ( unit=10, file=&apos;vg2pwscl.tab&apos;, status=&apos;old&apos; )
           do i=0,38
            read (10,*) ! skip 38 lines of label info
           end do
           do i=0,255
            read (10,*) idn, (cal(ichan,i),ichan=1,16)
           end do
           close (10)

          Then, given an uncalibrated data value idn for the
          frequency channel ichan, the corresponding calibrated
          antenna voltage would be given by the following array
          reference:

                volts = cal (ichan, idn)


          This may be converted to a wave electric field amplitude by
          dividing by the effective antenna length in meters, 7.07m.
          That is:

                efield = cal(ichan, idn) / 7.07


          Spectral density units may be obtained by dividing the
          square of the electric field value by the nominal frequency
          bandwidth of the corresponding spectrum analyzer channel.

                specdens = (cal(ichan,idn)/7.07)**2 / bandwidth(ichan)


          Finally, power flux may be obtained by dividing the
          spectral density by the impedance of free space in ohms:

           pwrflux=((cal(ichan,idn)/7.07)**2/bandwidth(ichan))/376.73


          Of course, for a particular application, it may be more
          efficient to apply the above conversions to the calibration
          table directly.

          The center frequencies and bandwidths of each PWS spectrum
          analyzer channel for the Voyager 2 PWS are given below:

                 VOYAGER 2 PWS SPECTRUM ANALYZER

                                                  Voyager-2
                 Channel    Center Frequency      Bandwidth

                 1             10.0 Hz             2.16  Hz
                 2             17.8 Hz             3.58  Hz
                 3             31.1 Hz             4.50  Hz
                 4             56.2 Hz            10.7   Hz
                 5            100.  Hz            13.8   Hz
                 6            178.  Hz            28.8   Hz
                 7            311.  Hz            39.8   Hz
                 8            562.  Hz            75.9   Hz
                 9           1.00   kHz           75.9   Hz
                 10          1.78   kHz          151.    Hz
                 11          3.11   kHz          324.    Hz
                 12          5.62   kHz          513.    Hz
                 13         10.0    kHz          832.    Hz
                 14         17.8    kHz         1260.    Hz
                 15         31.1    kHz         2400.    Hz
                 16         56.2    kHz         3800.    Hz

          A failure in the Voyager 2 Flight Data System which occurred
          about 3 months after launch has adversely affected the
          calibration of PWS channels 9 through 16. An algorithm has
          been devised to partially correct for this failure, and has
          proven useful for Voyager 2 Jupiter, Saturn, and Uranus
          encounters, but is not valid for Earth-Jupiter cruise and
          may be modified in the future. The following implementation
          of this correction algorithm in VAX FORTRAN assumes that
          uncalibrated data numbers are stored in a 16-element
          integer array, idn, with the array index equal to the PWS
          channel number:

          real*4 tonl(9:16) ! the old noise level for v2
          data tonl/2.0,1.0,-1.0,-2.0,-3.0,1.0,2.0,1.0/

          do ichan=9,16
           if (idn(ichan).gt.0) then
            if(idn(ichan).lt.64) idn(ichan)=64
            if (idn(ichan).le.72) then
             idn(ichan)=int(tonl(ichan)-530.4+8.6
                            *real(idn(ichan)))
            else
             idn(ichan)=int(tonl(ichan)+20.113+0.99
                            *real(idn(ichan)))
            end if
           end if
          end do

          This correction should not be applied permanently to the
          Voyager 2 calibration table since it is valid for a limited
          time span and may be modified in the future.


          Additional information about this dataset and the
          instrument which produced it can be found elsewhere in this
          catalog. An overview of the data in this data set can be
          found in Gurnett et al. [1986] and a complete instrument
          description can be found in Scarf and Gurnett [1977].

    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_NAME        = TIME
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_RESOLUTION  = 4.000000
    MINIMUM_SAMPLING_PARAMETER     = 197708201553.000000
    MAXIMUM_SAMPLING_PARAMETER     = N/A
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_INTERVAL    = 4.000000
    MINIMUM_AVAILABLE_SAMPLING_INT = 4.000000
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_UNIT        = SECOND
    DATA_SET_PARAMETER_NAME        = PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
    NOISE_LEVEL                    = 0.000005
    DATA_SET_PARAMETER_UNIT        = VOLT/METER



</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-U-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-U-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-U-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-U-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1986-01-23T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1986-01-31T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT4S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Uranus</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
