<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/RSS/Saturn/PT0.00001S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 1 Titan Radio Occultation Raw Data V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                 
                                                                      
    Data Set Overview                                                 
    =================                                                 
      This data set consists of raw data collected during the Titan   
      radio occultation of Voyager 1 in November 1980 plus ancillary  
      files that might be useful in analysis of those data.  The raw  
      data are sampled voltage outputs from receivers tuned to the    
      Voyager carrier frequencies at both S-band and X-band during    
      the occultations.  The data have been reduced to give profiles  
      of atmospheric temperature and pressure as a function of        
      height above the surface on both the ingress and egress sides   
      of Titan [LINDALETAL1983] and to make a marginal detection of   
      an ionosphere  [BIRDETAL1997].                                  
                                                                      
      During the Titan occultation, the Voyager 1 spacecraft          
      provided a coherent, dual-frequency microwave radio signal      
      source.  The signal frequency was derived from a precision,     
      onboard Ultra-Stable Oscillator (USO).  The spacecraft          
      high-gain antenna (HGA) beamed that signal through the          
      atmosphere of Titan.  As the spacecraft moved on its            
      trajectory, the radio signal probed different levels in the     
      atmosphere.  An hour later the signals were received by         
      antennas of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) on Earth.         
                                                                      
      Because the density of Titan&apos;s atmosphere was so poorly known   
      prior to the Voyager encounter, experiment planners did not     
      know how much refractive bending to expect during the           
      observations.  Models predicted a range of behaviors from very  
      little bending to so much that the narrow beam from the         
      spacecraft high-gain antenna (HGA) would be deflected away from 
      Earth and the surface occultation would not be seen.  Timing    
      uncertainties in the motion of the spacecraft with respect to   
      Titan only complicated the problem.  The experiment was         
      implemented with a very small (0.11 deg) fixed HGA offset       
      during the ingress occultation and a large (2.36 deg) offset    
      during egress.  These choices, in retrospect, were very good    
      given the atmosphere that was found.                            
                                                                      
                                                                      
    Parameters                                                        
    ==========                                                        
      The output of the S-band receiver was a sinusoidal carrier      
      signal embedded in noise -- a voltage with bandwidth            
      approximately 50 kHz and sampled at 300000 samples per second.  
      The X-band receiver output was similar; but, because of greater 
      potential for Doppler drift and prediction uncertainty, its     
      bandwidth was 150 kHz and sampling rate was 300000 samples per  
      second.  Voltages typically were in the range +/- 10 volts;     
      but the absolute levels were not calibrated.  In fact, they     
      are generally not needed since it is the frequency (or phase)   
      of the signal (rather than amplitude) that is most useful in    
      inferring properties of a neutral atmosphere or ionosphere.     
                                                                      
      The frequency of the USO was known from monitoring during the   
      Jupiter-Saturn cruise (and from post-Saturn observations).      
      Doppler contributions from motions of the spacecraft, Earth,    
      Titan, and other bodies of the solar system were determined     
      jointly with the Voyager Navigation Team.  Relativistic         
      Doppler contributions could be estimated from proximity to      
      large masses.  Receiver tuning was recorded in POCA             
      (Programmable Oscillator Control Assembly) files, which are     
      included with this archive.                                     
                                                                      
                                                                      
    Processing                                                        
    ==========                                                        
      No processing per se has been carried out on these data.        
      However, because of the high sampling rate, the 8-bit samples   
      were recorded originally on wide-bandwidth analog video tape.   
      The analog tapes were then replayed later at slower speeds and  
      the digital data were extracted and separated onto computer     
      compatible tapes (CCTs) with S-band and X-band data on          
      different sets of tapes.  Because the S-band data had been      
      oversampled originally (300 ksps for a 50 kHz bandwidth), only  
      one of every three samples was saved during the transfer of     
      S-band data to CCTs.  This process, known as &apos;decimation&apos;, meant
      that 300 seconds of data could be stored on an S-band CCT       
      whereas only 100 seconds of X-band data would fit.              
                                                                      
      Because analog recording technology was required to save the    
      high data rate digital samples, there are occasional dropouts   
      in the sample stream.  These can be detected by paying special  
      attention to counter fields in data record headers.             
                                                                      
      Two analog recorders (A and B) were available at each DSN       
      complex.   Because a single recorder could not capture the      
      entire set of Titan occultation activities, the two were run    
      in parallel with staggered start/stop times.  Most data were    
      collected using Recorder A; but Recorder B was used to          
      capture the samples while Recorder A was being reloaded.        
                                                                      
                                                                      
    Data                                                              
    ====                                                              
      Primary data were delivered to Voyager Radio Science Team       
      members in the form of 30 megabyte (MB) CCTs covering           
      300 s (S-band) or 100 s (X-band).  Each tape had  6000          
      records of 5056 bytes (56 bytes of header information           
      and 5000 8-bit samples of receiver output voltage).  Tapes      
      were numbered sequentially as CCTs were generated from the      
      high density video originals.  Tapes with Titan data from       
      Recorder A were numbered VJ6281 through VJ6360; tapes           
      from Recorder B were numbered VJ6361 through VJ6380.  Test      
      and calibration data after the Titan encounter were collected   
      on Recorder A and have numbers VJ6589 through VJ6594.           
                                                                      
      The original tape numbering has been preserved in the current   
      file names, which have the form VJnnnnCC.ODR.  On tapes where   
      one or more records could not be read, the original has been    
      separated into two or more files.  The character &apos;C&apos; indicates  
      the ordering of these file fragments with &apos;A&apos; being first (and  
      the default with no tape reading errors), &apos;B&apos; next, etc.        
                                                                      
      Each Original D</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-SSA-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-SSA-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-SSA-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-SSA-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/RSS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Active</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1980-11-12T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1980-11-12T23:59:59.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT0.00001S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Saturn</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
