<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
 <Version>2.5.0</Version>
 <Repository>
  <ResourceID>spase://CSA/Repository/UCalgary</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>University of Calgary Space Physics Group Data Landing Page</ResourceName>
   <ReleaseDate>2021-10-05T16:04:08</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>
     The repository provides access to ground-based space physics data
     from instruments such as: all sky cameras, magnetometers, photometers, riometers, RISR,
     spectrographs, VLF, and others. These instruments are associated
     with a variety of projects including: ABOVE^2, AuroraMAX,
     CANOPUS, GO-Canada, NORSTAR, RISR-C, THEMIS, TREx, and
     others. Data are available via a Data Landing Page as well as a
     Data Portal. From the Data Portal there is access to archived data,
     real-time data and a data availabilty display.
     
     From the Archive Data Availability page:
(https://data-portal.phys.ucalgary.ca/home_data_avail/)

With about 200TB+ of data across our multiple projects, managing and
keeping track of what we have can be a very difficult task. We use
what are called &quot;Data Availability&quot; plots to know what data
we have in our archives. We display plots for the majority of data
streams (ie. raw data, summary data, post-processed IDLsav files,
etc.). The information displayed on the plots is updated using an
automated schedule which spans no longer than a week (most summary
data plot information is updated at least once per day). 
</Description>
   <Acknowledgement>From the UofC Space Physics Group Data Landing Page:
(https://data.phys.ucalgary.ca) 
Operational funding for our instruments has come primarily from CSA
   and CFI, and funding for the infrastructure from CFI, the Alberta
   Government, the US NSF, and CSA. </Acknowledgement> 
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/C.M.Cully</PersonID>
    <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
   </Contact>
  </ResourceHeader>
  <AccessURL>
   <Name>UofC Space Physics Group Data Landing Page</Name>
   <URL>https://data.phys.ucalgary.ca</URL>
  </AccessURL>
 </Repository>
</Spase>
