<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_9.xsd">
  <Version>2.3.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Saturn/PT96S</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Saturn Plasma Science (PLS) Derived Ion Solar Wind, Version 1.0, 96 s Browse Data</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:16:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>* Data Set Overview
* =================

+-----------------------------------------------------+
| Data Set Characteristics | Value                    |
-------------------------------------------------------
| Instrument P.I.          | JOHN D. RICHARDSON       |
| Data Supplier            | JOHN D. RICHARDSON       |
| Data Sampling Rate       | 96 SECONDS               |
| Data Set Start Time      | 1981-08-19T00:00:09.229Z |
| Data Set Stop Time       | 1981-09-04T02:51:21.885Z |
+-----------------------------------------------------+

This Voyager 2 Data Set contains two Solar Wind Plasma Data, one spanning from August 19th to September 4th of 1981, and near Encounter specific Data covering August 24th and 25th. Moment Parameters are given in the broader Data while the near Encounter Data are more detailed. The Fit Parameters assume a convected isotropic Proton Maxwellian Distribution. Use of Fit Parameters is recommended as these are normally more accurate. Since only the first 72 or last 72 Energy per Charge Channels are telemetered to Earth from each M-Mode Spectra, derived Parameters change significantly only every other Set of Spectra so the effective Time Resolution is 96 s.

* Parameters
* ==========

* Data Set Parameter ION DENSITY
* ==============================

+----------------------------------------------+
| Parameter Characteristics      | Value       |
------------------------------------------------
| Data Set Parameter Name        | ION DENSITY |
| Data Set Parameter Unit        | CM^-3       |
| Sampling Parameter Name        | TIME        |
| Sampling Parameter Unit        | SECOND      |
| Minimum Sampling Parameter     | UNK         |
| Maximum Sampling Parameter     | UNK         |
| Sampling Parameter Interval    | UNK         |
| Minimum Available Sampling Int | UNK         |
| Noise Level                    | UNK         |
+----------------------------------------------+

A derived Parameter equaling the Number of Ions per Unit Volume over a specified Range of Ion Energy, Energy per Charge, or Energy per Nucleon. Discrimination with regard to Mass and or Charge State is necessary to obtain this Quantity, however, Mass and Charge State are often assumed due to Instrument Limitations.

Many different Forms of Ion Density are derived. Some are distinguished by their Composition (N+, Proton, Ion, etc.) or their Method of Derivation (Maxwellian Fit, Method of Moments). In some cases, more than one Type of Density will be provided in a single Data Set. In general, if more than one Ion Species is analyzed, either by Moment or Fit, a total Density will be provided which is the Sum of the Ion Densities. If a Plasma Component does not have a Maxwellian Distribution the actual Distribution can be represented as the Sum of several Maxwellians, in which case the Density of each Maxwellian is given.

* Data Set Parameter ION TEMPERATURE
* ==================================

+--------------------------------------------------+
| Parameter Characteristics      | Value           |
----------------------------------------------------
| Data Set Parameter Name        | ION TEMPERATURE |
| Data Set Parameter Unit        | EV              |
| Sampling Parameter Name        | TIME            |
| Sampling Parameter Unit        | SECOND          |
| Minimum Sampling Parameter     | UNK             |
| Maximum Sampling Parameter     | UNK             |
| Sampling Parameter Interval    | UNK             |
| Minimum Available Sampling Int | UNK             |
| Noise Level                    | UNK             |
+--------------------------------------------------+

A derived Parameter giving an Indication of the Mean Energy per Ion, assuming the Shape of the Ion Energy Spectrum to be Maxwellian. Given that the Ion Energy Spectrum is not exactly Maxwellian, the Ion Temperature can be defined integrally (whereby the Mean Energy obtained by integrating under the actual Ion Energy Spectrum is set equal to the Integral under a Maxwellian, where the Temperature is a free Parameter for which to solve), or differentially (whereby the Slopes of the actual Ion Energy Spectrum at various Energies are matched to the Slopes of a corresponding Maxwellian). The Temperature Parameter is often qualified with a Range of applicable Energies. Temperatures can be angularly anisotropic. If the Ions do not have a Maxwellian Distribution the actual Distribution can be represented as the Sum of several Maxwellians, each with a separate Temperature.

* Data Set Parameter ION THERMAL SPEED
* ====================================

+----------------------------------------------------+
| Parameter Characteristics      | Value             |
------------------------------------------------------
| Data Set Parameter Name        | ION THERMAL SPEED |
| Data Set Parameter Unit        | KM/S              |
| Sampling Parameter Name        | TIME              |
| Sampling Parameter Unit        | SECOND            |
| Minimum Sampling Parameter     | UNK               |
| Maximum Sampling Parameter     | UNK               |
| Sampling Parameter Interval    | UNK               |
| Minimum Available Sampling Int | UNK               |
| Noise Level                    | UNK               |
+----------------------------------------------------+

A Measure of the Velocity associated with the Temperature of the Ions. It is formally defined as the Ion Thermal Speed squared equals two times K (Boltzmann Constant) times T (Ion Temperature) divided by M (Ion Mass). Each Component of a Plasma has a Thermal Speed associated with it.

* Data Set Parameter ION VELOCITY
* ===============================</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
        <Description>The Document describing the Contents of the Collection.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Saturn/PT96S</PriorID>
        <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Saturn/PT96S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0</URL>
        <ProductKey>VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0</ProductKey>
        <Description>This Collection is archived with NASA Planetary Data System.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
      <Acknowledgement>NASA Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the Principal Investigator for the Data.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PLS</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1981-08-19T00:00:09.22</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1981-09-04T02:51:21.88</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT96S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Saturn</ObservedRegion>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
