<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.5.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://IUGONET/Instrument/ISEE/OMTI/SGK/ATP01</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Optical Mesosphere Thermosphere Imagers (OMTI) Airglow Temperature Photometer at Shigaraki, Japan</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2013-11-28T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The Airglow Temperature Photometer (ATP, #1) settled at Shigaraki Observatory, which is a part of the Optical Mesosphere Thermosphere Imagers (OMTIs), measures airglow intensities and rotational temperatures of OH and O2 at the zenith of the sky. It also measures OI (557.7 nm, 630.0 nm, 777.4 nm) lines and Na line intensities in every 5.5 minutes, and 427.8 nm and 486.1 nm line intensities in every 32.5 minutes. The observation at Shigaraki started on 5 July 2010 and it continues till present. The OMTIs were developed at the Institute for Space-Earth Environmental Research, Nagoya University, in order to investigate the dynamics of the upper atmosphere through nocturnal airglow emissions.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please contact the principal investigator (PI) of the OMTIs, Prof. K. Shiokawa (shiokawa at isee.nagoya-u.ac.jp) before using the data.</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Kazuo.Shiokawa</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Yuichi.Otsuka</PersonID>
            <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Akiyo.Yatagai</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/ISEE.Metadata.Management.Group</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Optical Mesosphere Thermosphere Imagers (OMTI)</Name>
            <URL>http://stdb2.isee.nagoya-u.ac.jp/omti/</URL>
            <Description>Detailed description of OMTIs and quick-look data are available. All the plotted data and images are just for browsing purpose and are not fully calibrated. Please do not use the data at any presentations and publications without contacting the PI.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Optical Mesosphere Thermosphere Imagers (OMTI)</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://IUGONET/Observatory/ISEE/OMTI/SGK</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
