<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Saturn/PT96S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Saturn PLS Derived Ion Solar Wind 96-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
      Data Set Overview                                                       
      =================                                                       
      Instrument P.I.       : John D. Richardson                              
      Data Supplier         : John D. Richardson                              
      Data sampling rate    : 96 seconds                                      
      Data Set Start Time   : 1981-08-19T00:00:09.229Z                        
      Data Set Stop Time    : 1981-09-04T02:51:21.885Z                        
                                                                              
      This Voyagers 2 data set contains two solar wind plasma data, one       
      spanning from August 19 to September 4 , 1981, and near encounter       
      specific data covering August 24-25.  Moment parameters are given in    
      the broader data while the near encounter data is more detailed.  The   
      fit parameters assume a convected isotropic proton Maxwellian           
      distribution. Use of fit parameters is recommended as these are normally
      more accurate.  Since only the first 72 or last 72 energy/charge        
      channels are telemetered to Earth from each M-mode spectra, derived     
      parameters change significantly only every other set of spectra so      
      the effective time resolution is 96 second.                             
                                                                              
      Parameters                                                              
      ==========                                                              
                                                                              
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION DENSITY&apos;                                        
      --------------------------------                                        
      Data Set Parameter Name        : ION DENSITY                            
      Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM**-3                                 
      Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME                                   
      Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND                                 
      Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK                                    
      Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK                                    
      Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK                                    
      Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK                                    
      Noise Level                    : UNK                                    
                                                                              
      A derived parameter equaling the number of ions per unit                
      volume over a specified range of ion energy, energy/charge,             
      or energy/nucleon. Discrimination with regard to mass and or            
      charge state is necessary to obtain this quantity, however,             
      mass and charge state are often assumed due to instrument               
      limitations.                                                            
                                                                              
      Many different forms of ion density are derived. Some are               
      distinguished by their composition (N+, proton, ion, etc.) or           
      their method of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of                   
      moments). In some cases, more than one type of density will             
      be provided in a single data set. In general, if more than              
      one ion species is analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total           
      density will be provided which is the sum of the ion                    
      densities. If a plasma component does not have a Maxwellian             
      distribution the actual distribution can be represented as              
      the sum of several Maxwellians, in which case the density of            
      each Maxwellian is given.                                               
                                                                              
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION TEMPERATURE&apos;                                    
      ------------------------------------                                    
      Data Set Parameter Name        : ION TEMPERATURE                        
      Data Set Parameter Unit        : EV                                     
      Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME                                   
      Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND                                 
      Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK                                    
      Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK                                    
      Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK                                    
      Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK                                    
      Noise Level                    : UNK                                    
                                                                              
      A derived parameter giving an indication of the mean                    
      energy/ion, assuming the shape of the ion energy spectrum to            
      be Maxwellian. Given that the ion energy spectrum is not                
      exactly Maxwellian, the ion temperature can be defined                  
      integrally (whereby the mean energy obtained by integrating             
      under the actual ion energy spectrum is set equal to the                
      integral under a Maxwellian, where the temperature is a free            
      parameter for which to solve), or differentially (whereby the           
      slopes of the actually ion energy spectrum at various energies          
      are matched to the slopes of a corresponding Maxwellian). The           
      temperature parameter is often qualified with a range of                
      applicable energies. Temperatures can be angularly                      
      anisotropic. If the ions do not have a Maxwellian distribution          
      the actual distribution can be represented as the sum of                
      several Maxwellians, each with a separate temperature.                  
                                                                              
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION THERMAL SPEED&apos;                                  
      --------------------------------------                                  
      Data Set Parameter Name        : ION THERMAL SPEED                      
      Data Set Parameter Unit        : KM/S                                   
      Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME                                   
      Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND                                 
      Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK                                    
      Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK                                    
      Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK                                    
      Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK                                    
      Noise Level                    : UNK                                    
                                                                              
      A measure of the velocity associated with the temperature of            
      the ions. It is formally defined as the Ion Thermal Speed               
      squared equals two times K (Boltzmann&apos;s constant) times T               
      (temperature of ion) divided by M (ion mass). Each component            
      of a plasma has a thermal speed associated with it.                     
                                                                              
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION VELOCITY&apos;                                       
      ---------------------------------                               </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-S-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-SOLARWIND-96S-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PLS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1981-08-19T00:00:09.22</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1981-09-04T02:51:21.88</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT96S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Saturn</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
