<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.5.0</Version>
   <NumericalData>
      <ResourceID>spase://ISWI/NumericalData/Callisto/FAS/PT0.25S</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>CALLISTO Solar Spectrogram FITS files</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>CALLISTO Frequency-Agile Spectrometer FITS files</AlternateName>
         <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/pmwd-mk15</DOI>
         <ReleaseDate>2023-07-06T16:59:38Z</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-04-09T16:59:38.000</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Added DOI and PublicationInfo, Update URLs, Added to RevisionHistory. JMW</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-05-22T16:59:38.000</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Added PublicationInfo. Added to RevisionHistory. JMW</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-06-29T15:21:24</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Updated Acknowledgment. LNG</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>This dataset contains solar dynamic spectrogram FITS files of the CALLISTO spectrometer data from the e-Callisto network of stations. The FITS file is composed of four parts: the ASCII-format header, the binary spectrum and two BIN tables. One table is for the time axis and the other for the frequency axis. FITSvfiles contain the keyword BUNIT in the primary header. If the BUNIT = &#039;SFU&#039;, then data are calibrated. If the BUNIT = &#039;digits&#039;, then data are raw data without any calibration. The naming convention for each file is of the form: STATION_YYYYMMDD_HHMMSS_CODE.fit.gz where STATION is a variable length station name and following the Date (YYYYMMDD) and UT time (HHMMSS) CODE is a two digit number that is an individual description of the front-end of the system.

From the website http://e-callisto.org - The CALLISTO spectrometer is a programmable heterodyne receiver built in the framework of IHY2007 and ISWI by former Radio and Plasma Physics Group (PI Christian Monstein) at ETH Zurich, Switzerland. The main applications are observation of solar radio bursts and rfi-monitoring for astronomical science, education and outreach. The instrument natively operates between 45 and 870 MHz using a modern, commercially available broadband cable-TV tuner CD1316 having a frequency resolution of 62.5 KHz.  Callisto in addition is dedicated to do radio-monitoring within its frequency range with 13,200 channels per spectrum. The frequency range can be expanded to any range by switching-in a heterodyne up- or a down-converter.  The data obtained from CALLISTO are FITS-files with up to 400 frequencies per sweep. The data are transferred via a RS-232 cable to a computer and saved locally. Time resolution is 0.25 sec at 200 channels per spectrum (800 pixels per second). The integration time is 1 msec and the radiometric bandwidth is about 300 KHz. The overall dynamic range is larger than 50 dB. For convenient data handling several IDL- and Python-routines were written.

Many CALLISTO instruments have been deployed. A complete list of stations is available from the website, please see the InformationURL included below for a link to the PDF file. Through the IHY/UNBSSI and ISWI instrument deployment program, CALLISTO is able to continuously observe the solar radio spectrum for 24h per day all year. All Callisto spectrometers together form the e-Callisto network. Instrument deployment including education and training of observers was financially supported by SNF, SSAA, NASA, Institute for Astronomy and North-South Center of ETH Zurich and a few private sponsors.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge Fachhochschule Nordwestschweiz (FHNW) Campus Brugg/Windisch and Istituto Ricerche Solari (IRSOL) Locarno, Switzerland.</Acknowledgement>
         <PublicationInfo>
            <Authors>Christian Monstein, André Csillaghy, and Arnold O. Benz</Authors>
            <PublicationDate>2023-01-01T00:00:00</PublicationDate>
            <PublishedBy>International Space Weather Initiative (ISWI)</PublishedBy>
         </PublicationInfo>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christian.Monstein</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Leonard.N.Garcia</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>e-Callisto International Network of Solar Radio Spectrometers</Name>
            <URL>https://e-callisto.org</URL>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>List of e-Callisto member stations and their operating status</Name>
            <URL>https://e-callisto.org/Callisto_DataStatus_Vwww.pdf</URL>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </InformationURL>
         <PriorID>spase://VWO/NumericalData/CALLISTO/FAS.PT0.25S</PriorID>
         <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Callisto/FAS/PT0.25S</PriorID>
         <PriorID>spase://GBO/NumericalData/Callisto/FAS/PT0.25S</PriorID>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/IA_ZURICH</RepositoryID>
         <Availability>Online</Availability>
         <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>Callisto QuickLook and Browse</Name>
            <URL>http://soleil.i4ds.ch/solarradio/callistoQuicklooks/</URL>
            <Description>Access to a directory tree (ordered by year/month/day) of PNG format plots for the Callisto network. Within the same directory are the corresponding FITS data files.</Description>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </AccessURL>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>Callisto FITS files</Name>
            <URL>http://soleil80.cs.technik.fhnw.ch/solarradio/data/2002-20yy_Callisto/</URL>
            <Description>Access to a directory tree (ordered by year/month/day) of FITS data files.</Description>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>FITS</Format>
         <Encoding>GZIP</Encoding>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge Fachhochschule Nordwestschweiz (FHNW) Campus Brugg/Windisch and Istituto Ricerche Solari (IRSOL) Locarno, Switzerland.</Acknowledgement>
      </AccessInformation>
      <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CALLISTO/spectrometer</InstrumentID>
      <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
      <MeasurementType>Spectrum</MeasurementType>
      <TemporalDescription>
         <TimeSpan>
            <StartDate>2002-09-07T12:08:00Z</StartDate>
            <RelativeStopDate>-P1D</RelativeStopDate>
         </TimeSpan>
      </TemporalDescription>
      <ObservedRegion>Sun</ObservedRegion>
      <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservedRegion>
   </NumericalData>
</Spase>
