<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/Ephemeris/Jupiter/PT96S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 1 Jupiter Ephemeris System III (1965)Coords Browse V1.1</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                       
                                                                             
  Data Set Overview                                                          
  =================                                                          
                                                                             
    Version 1.1                                                              
    -----------                                                              
      The SEDR based data provided as part of this data set were             
      originally reviewed and archived with the NSSDC and PDS as             
      version 1.0 (DATA_SET_ID = VG1-J-POS-4-48.0SEC).  Version 1.1          
      includes additional columns not present in the previous                
      version, 96 second rather than 48 second time samples, times           
      converted to &apos;PDS Style&apos; or ISO standard, and upgrading of             
      PDS labels and templates to version 3.2.  The SPICE based              
      data that are also part of this data set were not previously           
      archived with the PDS.  This version 1.1 data set replaces             
      previously archived versions.                                          
                                                                             
                                                                             
    Data Set Description                                                     
    --------------------                                                     
      This data set consists of Voyager 1 Jupiter encounter                  
      ephemeris data in System III (1965) left handed coordinates            
      covering the period 1979-03-03 to 1979-03-16.  Two versions,           
      both covering the same time period, but containing slightly            
      different data, are provided.  One version was generated by            
      the Voyager MAG team from Voyager 1 SEDR, the other by the             
      PDS/PPI node using the VG1_JUP.BSP and PCK00003.TCP SPICE              
      kernels.                                                               
                                                                             
      Two versions of the spacecraft ephemeris data are provided as          
      an attempt to correct some of the problems in the Voyager              
      SEDR while preserving the ability to reproduce early results.          
      The original SEDR data has a variety of problems which may             
      affect the knowledge of the spacecraft position, or                    
      conversely, the timing associated with certain events such as          
      ring plane crossings.  The SPICE SPK kernel provided on this           
      disk includes corrections to some, but not all, of the                 
      problems associated with the Voyager SEDR.  The Navigation             
      and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) at JPL may issue a           
      new Voyager SPK kernel in the future that will further                 
      improve the knowledge of the spacecraft location in inertial           
      space.                                                                 
                                                                             
      There are other differences in the in the two versions of              
      ephemeris data that are the result of improvements in the              
      knowledge of some of the physical constants associated with            
      Jupiter and its moons.  Since the Voyager era, there have              
      been updates to the orientation of the jovian spin axis right          
      ascension and declination, the radius of Jupiter, as well as           
      the orbital characteristic and other physical parameters of            
      many of the moons of Jupiter.  These changes affect the                
      stated position of the spacecraft in jovigraphic coordinate            
      systems like System III without changing the position of the           
      spacecraft in inertial space.  The spin rate of Jupiter is             
      not changed from the System III (1965) rate of 9h 55m                  
      29.71sec (870.536 deg/day).  The SPICE planetary constants             
      kernel (PCK) contains both the current IAU definitions of the          
      physical constants for the bodies within in the jovian system          
      (as data) as well as the older IAU definitions (as comments).          
      This is an ASCII text file (PCK00003.TCP) and users of the             
      ephemeris data are encouraged to review it.                            
                                                                             
                                                                             
    SEDR generated ephemeris                                                 
    ------------------------                                                 
      Instrument P.I.       : N/A                                            
      Data Supplier         : NSSDC (Voyager MAG Team)                       
      Data sampling rate    : 96 seconds                                     
      Data Set Start Time   : 1979-03-03T00:00:35.978Z                       
      Data Set Stop Time    : 1979-03-16T23:59:08.185Z                       
                                                                             
                                                                             
    SPICE generated ephemeris                                                
    -------------------------                                                
      Instrument P.I.       : N/A                                            
      Data Supplier         : S. Joy                                         
      Data sampling rate    : 48 seconds                                     
      Data Set Start Time   : 1979-03-03T00:00:35.978Z                       
      Data Set Stop Time    : 1979-03-16T23:59:56.185Z                       
                                                                             
                                                                             
  Parameters                                                                 
  ==========                                                                 
                                                                             
    SEDR generated ephemeris                                                 
    ------------------------                                                 
      PARAMETER  RESOLUTION/  DESCRIPTION                                    
      NAME       UNITS                                                       
                                                                             
      time       96.0 Sec     time of the sample (UT) in the format          
                               yyyy-mm-ddThh:mm:ss.sssZ                      
                                                                             
      m65536     counts       spacecraft clock counts                        
      mod60      counts                                                      
      fds_line   counts                                                      
                                                                             
      sc_x       R[J]         jovicentric (System III) cartesian             
      sc_y       R[J]         cartesian position vectors: X, Y, and          
      sc_z       R[J]         Z                                              
                                                                             
      vel_x      km/s         jovicentric X, Y, and Z spacecraft             
      vel_y      km/s         velocity components                            
      vel_z      km/s                                                        
              </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-J-POS-6-SUMM-S3COORDS-V1.1</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-J-POS-6-SUMM-S3COORDS-V1.1/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-J-POS-6-SUMM-S3COORDS-V1.1</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-J-POS-6-SUMM-S3COORDS-V1.1</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/Ephemeris</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Ephemeris</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1979-03-03T00:00:35.97</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1979-03-16T23:59:56.18</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT96S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
