<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.6.0.xsd">
   <Version>2.6.0</Version>
   <Software>
      <ResourceID>spase://CCMC/Software/Kamodo</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>CCMC Kamodo Software</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2023-09-28T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-09-28T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Initial submission of metadata written by Chiu Wiegand 20230801, reviewed and revised LFB 20230928</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>Kamodo is an official NASA open-source project written in python that is built upon the functionalization of datasets. It is a CCMC developed and maintained software tool for access, interpolation, and visualization of space weather models and data. Kamodo allows model developers to represent simulation results as mathematical functions which may be manipulated directly by end users. Kamodo handles unit conversion transparently and supports interactive science discovery through jupyter notebooks with minimal coding. All Kamodo tools are accessible through python, and all source code is publicly available on the Kamodo NASA GitHub repositories.

Note: Kamodo does not generate model outputs. Users need to acquire the desired model outputs before they can be functionalized by Kamodo.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Masha.Kuznetsova</PersonID>
            <Role>ProgramManager</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>CCMC Kamodo Page</Name>
            <URL>https://ccmc.gsfc.nasa.gov/tools/kamodo/</URL>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://NASA/Repository/NASA-GitHub</RepositoryID>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>NASA Open Source Kamodo GitHub Link</Name>
            <URL>https://github.com/nasa/Kamodo</URL>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>Binary</Format>
      </AccessInformation>
      <CodeLanguage>Python</CodeLanguage>
      <Prerequisites>Refer to NASA Kamodo documentation on the GitHub site, https://nasa.github.io/Kamodo/</Prerequisites>
      <ExecutionEnvironment>
         <OperatingSystem>Mac, Linux, Window</OperatingSystem>
         <Installer>
            <Availability>Offline</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <Acknowledgement>For tracking purposes for our government sponsors, we ask that you notify the CCMC whenever you use any CCMC tools/software systems in any scientific publications and/or presentations.</Acknowledgement>
            <URL>https://ccmc.gsfc.nasa.gov/publication-policy/</URL>
         </Installer>
      </ExecutionEnvironment>
   </Software>
</Spase>
