<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <Version>2.2.8</Version>
    <DisplayData>
        <ResourceID>spase://VSPO/DisplayData/STEREO/SSC/DailyBrowsePlots</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>STEREO Science Center Daily Browse Plots</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2016-11-16T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>
Daily browse plots from the STEREO in situ (IMPACT, PLASTIC) and radio (S/WAVES) instruments are available on the STEREO Science Center (SSC) website.  The in situ data are derived from the low cadence space weather telemetry and are not publishable quality.  The S/WAVES time-frequency plots are taken from the S/WAVES website, and are based on the actual science data--these are delayed by one or more days depending on availablity.

The daily in situ browse pages are split up into three sections.  At the top is a plot of solar wind magnetic field data from IMPACT/MAG, and solar wind proton density, velocity, and ion temperature from PLASTIC.  Data from STEREO Ahead is plotted in red, and data from STEREO Behind is plotted in blue.  Also overplotted in brown is the equivalent data from either ACE or DSCOVR depending on the date.  The second section shows solar energetic particle fluxes from IMPACT in various energy ranges.  STEREO Ahead data are plotted on one side, and STEREO Behind data are plotted on the other, with the order depending on whether or not the date is before or after solar conjunction.  The third section shows the S/WAVES time-frequency plots.

Upon entering the daily browse tool, one is initially taken to the browse page for the most recent day.  From there, one can navigate by day, week, or solar rotation (28 days).  One can also enter in a specific date in the format YYYYMMDD, e.g. 20161103 for November 3, 2016.  Alternative pages exist for three and seven day spans centered on the target--these pages do not include the S/WAVES radio data.  It is also possible to move back and forth between the pages for SECCHI browse images and for in situ browse plots for any given date.
	    </Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.T.Thompson</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
            </Contact>
	</ResourceHeader>
	<AccessInformation>
	  <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/STEREO_SC</RepositoryID>
	  <Availability>Online</Availability>
	  <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
	  <AccessURL>
	    <Name>STEREO SSC Daily Browse Plots</Name>
	    <URL>https://stereo-ssc.nascom.nasa.gov/browse/insitu.shtml</URL>
	  </AccessURL>
	  <Format>HTML</Format>
	</AccessInformation>
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STEREO-A/IMPACT</InstrumentID>
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STEREO-B/IMPACT</InstrumentID>
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STEREO-A/PLASTIC</InstrumentID>
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STEREO-B/PLASTIC</InstrumentID>
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STEREO-A/SWAVES</InstrumentID>
	<InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STEREO-B/SWAVES</InstrumentID>
	<MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
	<MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
	<MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
	<MeasurementType>Waves</MeasurementType>
	<TemporalDescription>
	  <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>2006-12-22T00:00:00</StartDate>
                <RelativeStopDate>-PT1H</RelativeStopDate>
	  </TimeSpan>
	</TemporalDescription>
        <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Remote1AU</ObservedRegion>
    </DisplayData>
</Spase>	
