<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_1.xsd">
 <Version>2.3.1</Version>
 <DisplayData>
  <ResourceID>spase://ISWI/DisplayData/SipleExperiment/VLF/Broadband/P1D</ResourceID>
  <ResourceHeader>
   <ResourceName>Siple Experiment VLF Data Quick-look Broadband Summary Charts</ResourceName>
   <ReleaseDate>2021-03-02T17:39:48Z</ReleaseDate>
   <Description>The broadband summary chart stitches together the
   first second of each hour in the day. For VLF data  (100 kHz
   sampling), the spectrogram will display from 0.3 kHz to 50
   kHz. Note, these are not 24-hour-long spectrograms, but rather only
   the first second of each hour (if available) is displayed. This
   provides a quick and easy way to evaluate the operation of the
   receiver and the noise environment, but more detailed analysis
   requires downloading the actual data. 

   Each chart consists of two plots, the upper plot displays magnetic
   field output from the North-South antenna, the lower plot displays
   the magnetic field output from the East-West antenna. These are 24
   Hour plots. The title of the chart indicates the name of the
   station and the year-month-day of the observation.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
     DATA USAGE POLICY
The data in the WALDO database have been collected by Stanford
University, the Georgia Institute of Technology, and the University of
Colorado Denver. Funding has been provided by the United States
government under various basic science research grants over many
years. 

To maximize the benefit of those investments, WALDO data are released
without restriction, and can be freely analyzed or published. 

The curators of WALDO are Morris Cohen (Georgia Tech) and Mark
Golkowski (CU-Denver). We request that the following acknowledgement
be added in any publication using data from WALDO 

"VLF data are provided by the WALDO database (https://waldo.world),
operated jointly by the Georgia Institute of Technology, and the
University of Colorado Denver, using data collected from those
institutions as well as Stanford University, and has been supported by
various US government grants from the NSF, NASA, and the Department of
Defense." 

If extensive amounts of WALDO data are used in a publication, the
curators request, but do not require, to be contacted to discuss the
possibility of joint authorship, with the WALDO curators providing
help analyzing and interpreting the large dataset. 
   </Acknowledgement> 
   <Contact>
    <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Morris.Cohen</PersonID>
    <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
   </Contact>
   <InformationURL>
    <Name>Worldwide Archive of Low-Frequency Data and Observations (WALDO)</Name>
    <URL>https://waldo.world</URL>
   </InformationURL>
   <Association>
    <AssociationID>spase://ISWI/NumericalData/SipleExperiment/VLF/PT0.00004S</AssociationID>
    <AssociationType>DerivedFrom</AssociationType>
   </Association>
  </ResourceHeader>
  <AccessInformation>
   <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/WALDO</RepositoryID>
   <AccessURL>
    <Name>WALDO Quick-Look Plots</Name>
    <URL>https://waldo.world/summary-and-availability-charts/#BroadbandSummary</URL>
   </AccessURL>
   <Format>PNG</Format>
  </AccessInformation>
  <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/SipleExperiment/VLF</InstrumentID>
  <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
   <TemporalDescription>
     <TimeSpan>
       <StartDate>1973-01-01T00:00:00</StartDate>
       <StopDate>1988-01-01T00:00:00</StopDate>
     </TimeSpan>
     <Cadence>P1D</Cadence>
   </TemporalDescription>
   <DisplayCadence>P1D</DisplayCadence>
   <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
  <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservedRegion>
  <InputResourceID>spase://ISWI/NumericalData/SipleExperiment/VLF/PT0.00004S</InputResourceID>
 </DisplayData>
</Spase>
