<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/PWS/Jupiter/PT1H</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>VG1 J/S/SS PWS RESAMP SPECTRUM ANALYZER HOUR AVG V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2014-12-01T10:06:23.90</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    This data set consists of electric field spectrum analyzer data from      
    the Voyager 1 Plasma Wave Subsystem obtained during the entire            
    mission.  Data after 2013-12-31 will be added to the archive on subsequent
    volumes.  The data set encompasses all spectrum analyzer                  
    observations obtained in the cruise mission phases before, between,       
    and after the Jupiter and Saturn encounter phases as well as those        
    obtained during the two encounter phases.                                 
                                                                              
    The Voyager 1 spacecraft travels from Earth to beyond 90 AU over the      
    course of this data set.  To provide some guidance on when some key       
    events occurred during the mission, the following table is provided.      
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Date         Event                                                        
    1977-09-05   Launch                                                       
    1979-02-28   First inbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter                  
    1979-03-22   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter                  
    1980-11-11   First inbound bow shock crossing at Saturn                   
    1980-11-16   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Saturn                   
    1981-02-20   10 AU                                                        
    1983-08-30   Onset of first major LF heliospheric radio event             
    1984-06-19   20 AU                                                        
    1987-04-08   30 AU                                                        
    1990-01-09   40 AU                                                        
    1992-07-06   Onset of second major LF heliospheric radio event            
    1992-10-10   50 AU                                                        
    1995-07-14   60 AU                                                        
    1998-04-18   70 AU                                                        
    2001-01-25   80 AU                                                        
    2002-11-01   Onset of third major LF heliospheric radio event             
    2003-11-05   90 AU                                                        
    2004-12-16   Termination shock crossing                                   
    2006-08-16   100 AU                                                       
    2009-05-31   110 AU                                                       
    2012-03-16   120 AU                                                       
    2015-01-01   130 AU                                                       
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Data Sampling                                                               
  =============                                                               
    This data set consists of average and peak wave electric field            
    intensities accumulated over 1-hour intervals from the Voyager 1          
    Plasma Wave Receiver spectrum analyzer obtained during the entire         
    mission.  For each 1-hour time interval squares of the calibrated         
    electric field measurements obtained during each hour-long                
    interval in each of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels are summed          
    and then divided by the number of measurements.  The square root          
    of the resulting value is obtained and stored as the average              
    electric field strength for the respective channel.  During the           
    same hour-long interval, the maximum electric field strength              
    acquired in each of the 16 channels is also recorded and stored as        
    the peak electric field strength for the respective channel.              
    Hence, for each hour, an average and peak electric field spectrum         
    from 10 Hz to 56.2 kHz is obtained.  The 16 spectrum analyzer             
    channels have center frequencies that range from 10 Hertz to 56.2         
    kiloHertz and are logarithmically spaced in frequency, four               
    channels per decade.  The time associated with each peak and              
    average spectrum is the time of the beginning of the averaging            
    interval.  Given variations in the sweep rate of the instrument           
    (from a minimum of 4 seconds/sweep to a maximum of 96                     
    seconds/sweep) the maximum number of samples in an hour-long              
    interval can range from 900 to 38.  Data gaps within the interval         
    can further reduce the number of samples.                                 
                                                                              
    During data gaps where complete spectra are missing, no entries           
    exist in the file, that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged        
    in any other way.                                                         
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Data Processing                                                             
  ===============                                                             
    The spectrum analyzer data are a continuous (where data are               
    available) low resolution data set which provides wave intensity          
    as a function of frequency (16 log-spaced channels) and time (one         
    spectrum per time intervals ranging from 4 seconds to 96 seconds          
    in the full-resolution data set, depending on telemetry mode.)            
    This data set includes one-hour average and peak values for each          
    channel.  The data are typically plotted as amplitude vs. time for        
    one or more of the channels in a strip-chart like display, or can         
    be displayed as a frequency-time spectrogram using a gray- or             
    color-bar to indicate amplitude.  With only sixteen channels, it          
    is usually best to stretch the frequency axis by interpolating            
    from one frequency channel to the next either linearly or with a          
    spline fit.  One must be aware if the frequency axis is stretched         
    that more resolution may be implied than is really present.               
                                                                              
    The measurements provided in the average and peak electric field          
    spectra included in this data set are in units of electric field          
    (volts/meter).                                                            
                                                                              
    Spectral density units may be obtained by dividing the square of          
    the electric field value by the nominal frequency bandwidth of the        
    corresponding spectrum analyzer channel.                                  
                                                                              
      specdens = (efield(ichan))**2 / bandwidth(ichan)                        
                                                                              
    Finally, power flux may be obtained by dividing the spectral              
    density by the impedance of free space in ohms:                           
                                                                      </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-J/S/SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-J-S-SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?id=pds://PPI/VG1-J_S_SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-J/S/SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1977-09-05T14:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>2014-01-01T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT1H</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
