<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.7.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <MetadataRightsList>
    <Rights>
      <SchemeURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/</SchemeURI>
      <RightsIdentifierScheme>SPDX</RightsIdentifierScheme>
      <RightsIdentifier>CC0-1.0</RightsIdentifier>
      <RightsURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC0-1.0.html</RightsURI>
      <RightsName>Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal</RightsName>
      <Note>CC0 1.0 Universal is the Creative Commons license applicable to all publicly available SPASE metadata descriptions</Note>
    </Rights>
  </MetadataRightsList>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Uranus/PT0.06S</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>NASA</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>NumericalData</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Uranus Plasma Wave Spectrometer (PWS) Raw Experiment Waveforms, Version 1.0, 60 ms Data</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:32:42Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:16:01Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:32:42Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added MetadataRightsList. Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Updated to 2.7.1. Changed http to https in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Fixed version number separator in top-level schemaLocation attribute. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>* Data Set Overview
* =================

This Data Set consists of Electric Field Waveform Samples from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver Waveform Receiver obtained during the Uranus Encounter. The Waveforms are Collections of 4-bit Samples of the Electric Field measured by the Dipole Electric Antenna at a Rate of 28,800 samples per second. A Set of 1600 Samples are collected in 55.56 ms followed by a 4.44 ms Gap. Each 60 ms Interval constitutes a Line of Waveform Samples. The Data Set includes about 271 Frames of Waveform Samples consisting of up to 800 Lines, each. The Telemetry Format for the Waveform Data is identical to that for Images, hence the use of Line and Frame as constructs in describing the Form of the Data. The Waveform is sampled through a Bandpass Filter with a Passband of 40 Hz to 12 kHz. The 4-bit Samples provide sixteen digital Values of the Electric Field with a linear Amplitude Scale, but the Amplitude Scale is arbitrary because of the Automatic Gain Control used in the Waveform Receiver. The instantaneous Dynamic Range afforded by the 4 bit Samples is about 23 db, but the Automatic Gain Control allows the dominant Signal in the Passband to be set at the optimum Level to fit within the instantaneous Dynamic Range. With the Gain Control, the overall Dynamic Range of the Waveform Receiver is about 100 db. The Automatic Gain Control Gain Setting is not returned to the Ground, hence, there is no absolute Calibration for the Data. However, by comparing the Waveform Spectrum derived by Fourier transforming the Waveform to the Spectrum provided by the Spectrum Analyzer Data, an absolute Calibration may be obtained in most Cases. The Data may be plotted in raw Form to show the actual Waveform; this is useful for studying Events such as Dust Impacts on the Spacecraft. But the normal Method of analyzing the Waveform Data is by Fourier transforming the Samples from each Line to arrive at an Amplitude versus Frequency Spectrum. By stacking the Spectra side-by-side in Time Order, a Frequency-Time Spectrogram can be produced. Additional Information about this Data Set and the Instrument which produced it can be found elsewhere in this Catalog. An Overview of the Data in this Data Set can be found in (Gurnett et al., 1986) and a complete Instrument Description can be found in (Scarf and Gurnett, 1977).

+-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------+
| Parameter Characteristics           | Value                                       |
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
| Sampling Parameter Name             | TIME                                        |
| Sampling Parameter Resolution       | 0.000034722 SECONDS                         |
| Minimum Sampling Parameter          | N/A                                         |
| Maximum Sampling Parameter          | N/A                                         |
| Sampling Parameter Interval         | 0.000034722 SECONDS                         |
| Minimum Available Sampling Interval | 0.000034722 SECONDS                         |
| Data Set Parameter Name             | PLASMA WAVE WAVEFORM                        |
| Noise Level                         | 0.000005                                    |
| Data Set Parameter Unit             | VOLT/METER (DATA NOT ABSOLUTELY CALIBRATED) |
+-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------+</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>VG2-U-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-U-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
        <Description>The Document describing the Contents of the Collection.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Uranus/PT0.6S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Uranus/PT0.60S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Uranus/PT0.06S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-U-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</URL>
        <ProductKey>VG2-U-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</ProductKey>
        <Description>This Collection is archived with NASA Planetary Data System.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
      <Acknowledgement>NASA Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the Principal Investigator for the Data.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1985-11-08T07:04:08.64</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1986-02-22T20:41:34.18</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT0.06S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Uranus</ObservedRegion>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
