<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.4.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://NSF/Instrument/Ground/MLSO/K-Cor</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>MLSO K-Coronagraph</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>K-Cor</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2022-04-20T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2022-04-20T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Initial SPASE XML resource description registration. Metadata submitted by the MLSO instrument team on 2022-04-19, reviewed and revised by LFB</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The COronal Solar Magnetism Observatory, COSMO, K-coronagraph, K-Cor, is one of three proposed instruments in the COSMO facility suite. It is specifically designed to study the formation and dynamics of coronal mass ejections and the evolution of the density structure of the low corona. The K-Cor records the polarization brightness, pB, formed by Thomson scattering of photospheric light by coronal free electrons. The National Center for Atmospheric Research, NCAR, via the National Science Foundation, NSF, provided full funding for the COSMO K-Cor, which was deployed to the Mauna Loa Solar Observatory, MLSO, in Hawaii in September 2013, replacing the aging MLSO Mk4 K-coronameter.

The COSMO K-Coronagraph design was driven by the science goals of understanding the formation of CMEs and the structure and evolution of the low corona. Basic features of the K-Cor design include:

* Internally occulted refractive coronagraph
* Field-of-view (FOV): 1.05 to 3 solar radii
* Aperture: 20 cm uncoated singlet objective lens
* Focal Length: 2 m (f/10)
* Pass band: ~720 nm to 750 nm
* Out-of-band rejection
* Lyot Stop
* 4-state polarization modulation
* Dual beam polarization, two cameras simultaneously record polarization states
* 5.5 arcsec pixels
* Nominal cadence: 15 s, can run faster in campaign mode</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Courtesy of the Mauna Loa Solar Observatory, operated by the High Altitude Observatory, as part of the National Center for Atmospheric Research, NCAR. NCAR is supported by the National Science Foundation, NSF.</Acknowledgement>
         <Funding>
            <Agency>National Science Foundation</Agency>
            <Project>MLSO K-Coronagraph</Project>
         </Funding>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Joan.Burkepile</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            <StartDate>2013-09-30T00:00:00</StartDate>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alfred.de.Wijn</PersonID>
            <Role>InstrumentLead</Role>
            <StartDate>2013-09-30T00:00:00</StartDate>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>MLSO K-Coronagraph Instrument website</Name>
            <URL>https://www2.hao.ucar.edu/mlso/instruments/mlso-kcor-coronagraph</URL>
            <Description>COronal Solar Magnetism Observatory, COSMO, K-coronagraph website hosted by the High Altitude Observatory</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>MLSO K-Coronagraph Instrument paper</Name>
            <URL>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.926511</URL>
            <Description>de Wijn, A.G., J.T. Burkepile, S. Tomczyk, P.G. Nelson, P. Huang, and D. Gallagher, Stray light and polarimetry considerations for the COSMO K-Coronagraph, SPIE Astronomical Telescopes + Instrumentation, 2012, Amsterdam, Netherlands, Proceedings Volume 8444, Ground-based and Airborne Telescopes IV, 84443N (2012)</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <Association>
            <AssociationID>spase://NSF/Observatory/Ground/MLSO</AssociationID>
            <AssociationType>PartOf</AssociationType>
         </Association>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
      <InstrumentType>Coronograph</InstrumentType>
      <InstrumentType>Photopolarimeter</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>COSMO K-Cor at MLSO</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ground/MaunaLoaSO</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
