<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <NumericalData>
        <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/CRRES/MAG/PT10H</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>CRRES magnetic field orbital data</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2025-05-01T21:14:30Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>The magnetic field files (CRnnnn.FPM) contains magnetic field components converted from the CRRES tri-axial fluxgate magnetometer sensor output.  This data set, however, is different from the ones on the Aerospace agency tapes.  The experimenter magnetic field files (which had neither the full time resolution nor the magnetic field intensity resolution of the original magnetometer outputs) were converted to field components in magnetometer sensor coordinates using the software and final calibration coefficient files provided by the magnetometer PI (Dr. Howard Singer, SEL).  The original magnetic field files for orbits 6-350 were not readilly available, but the converted files were, so for the sake of uniformity, it was decided to provide the converted files
instead of the originals.  For those who might wish to get back to the original data, the source code (MAGMPC5.FOR) and calibration files (MAGnn.CAL)
which were used to generate the .FPM files are provided.  The original CR0237.MAG file is available on CD-8 for comparison with any results of an
inversion program written by the user.  A program which dumps the CRnnnn.FPM files is also provided on CD-35 (FPMTEST.EXE).  This program prints out the
UT, three magnetic field components in magnetometer coordinates, total B, and the pitch-angle calculated for the MEA (or a user-selected set of direction
cosines).  The source code, FPMTEST.FOR, is also provided.</Description>
            <Acknowledgement>The National Space Science Data Center; Department of Defense-Department of the Air Force (United States); AFRL; Dr. Howard J. Singer; Dr. E. Gary Mullen</Acknowledgement>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
             </Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>CRRES Fluxgate Magnetometer Instrument</Name>
                <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A-19</URL>
                <Description>NASA NSSDC CRRES fluxgate magnetometer experiment details</Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <Association>
                <AssociationID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</AssociationID>
                <AssociationType>ObservedBy</AssociationType>
            </Association>
            <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/P_CRRES_HDR_MAG_DATA</PriorID>
            <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/CRRES/MAG/PT10H</PriorID>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <AccessInformation>
            <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF</RepositoryID>
            <Availability>Online</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
                <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/crres/magnetic_field/data/</URL>
            </AccessURL>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
                <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/crres/magnetic_field/data/</URL>
            </AccessURL>
            <Format>Binary</Format>
        </AccessInformation>
        <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
        <ProviderResourceName>CRRES MAG Tri-axial fluxgate magnetometer</ProviderResourceName>
        <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/MAG</InstrumentID>
        <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>1990-10-11T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
                <StopDate>1991-10-13T00:00:00.000</StopDate>
            </TimeSpan>
            <Cadence>PT10H</Cadence>
        </TemporalDescription>
		<ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservedRegion>
        <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.RadiationBelt</ObservedRegion>
</NumericalData>
</Spase>