<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/Cluster-3/FGM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Each Cluster spacecraft carries an identical FGM (Fluxgate Magnetometer) to measure the magnetic field. Each instrument, in turn, consists of two triaxial fluxgate magnetometers and an onboard data processing unit. The magnetometers are similar to many previous instruments flown in Earth-orbit and on other, planetary and interplanetary missions. In order to minimise the magnetic background of the spacecraft, one of the magnetometer sensors (the outboard, or OB sensor) is located at the end of one of the two 5.2 m radial booms of the spacecraft, the other (the inboard, or IB sensor) at 1.5 m inboard from the end of the boom. In flight, either sensor can be designed as the Primary Sensor, for acquiring the main data stream of the magnetic field vectors. In the default configuration, the OB sensor is used as the Primary Sensor. Every sensor has a spare ADCADC) which normally will only be used in the event of failure of the normal ADC. 
Five operating ranges are used on the Cluster magnetometers: (2) -64 to +63.992 nT, (3) -256   to   +255.97 nT, (4) -1024 to +1023.9 nT, (5) -4096 to +4095.5  and  (7) -65536 to +65528 nT.
The three components of the magnetic field vector measured by the Primary Sensor are sampled at a constant rate of 201.75 Hz and subsequently digitally filtered to match the transmitted rate, according to the operating modes of the instrument and the telemetry rate allocated to it. 
This description has been obtained from Section 3.5 of the ''Users Guide to the Cluster Science Data System'', DS-MPA-TN-0015.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Elizabeth.Lucek</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) on Cluster-3</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/Cluster-3</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
