<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema   http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.3.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Cluster-Tango/EDI/CSA/PT0.0625S</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cluster-Tango Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) Data at the ESA Cluster Science Archive</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Cluster 2 Tango Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) Data at the ESA Cluster Active Archive</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-02-12T20:40:18Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) data products from the Cluster spacecraft in three main categories: (1) Electron enegergies measured between 0.5 and 1.0 keV for the Windshield Wiper mode: time series of the three components of the electron drift velocity and of the three components of the electric field in Cartesian GSE coordinate system (corrected for spacecraft motion) with different qualities and time resolution at 1-4 sec (PP, PPP, MPD); (2) Ambient electron measurements at fixed enegeris of 0.5 or 1.0 keV: time series of electron counts normally at 16 ms for the three pitch angles 0 deg, 90 deg, 180 deg, the detector look direction in the spacecraft frame and in GSE and the status for AE mode; and (3) Overview plot of the main parameters for both modes for every 3 h for one reference spacecraft (usually Cluster III).  Besides the main products, there also are raw data and auxiliary data. Raw data consist of merged science files (MSF) that are obtained by merging the housekeeping and science (burst (BM) and normal (NM) mode) telemetry files. They are in binary format.  Auxiliary are either data used internally by the main data production software or data dedicated to intercalibration or time-interval lists of the EDI operation modes. For more details, see "The Cluster Active Archive: Studying the Earth's Space Plasma Environment", edited by Dr. Harri Laakso, Matthew G. T. T. Taylor, C. Philippe Escoubet, from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Goetz Paschmann and the Cluster Active Archive</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Goetz.Paschmann</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Melvyn.L.Goldstein</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog listing for Cluster II Tango Electron Drift Instrument (EDI)</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-045B-03</URL>
        <Description>This site provides information concerning the Cluster II Tango  Electron Drift Instrument.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Cluster Science Archive (CSA) Documentation</Name>
        <URL>https://www.cosmos.esa.int/?project=CLUSTER&amp;page=caa_documentation</URL>
        <Description>CAA Instrument User Guides, Calibration Reports and ICDS.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <Association>
        <AssociationID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Tango</AssociationID>
        <AssociationType>ObservedBy</AssociationType>
</Association>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Cluster-Tango/EDI/CSA/PT0.0625S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://ESA/NumericalData/Cluster-Tango/EDI/CSA/PT0.0625S</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/CSA</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>Access to files at the Cluster Science Archive (CSA)</Name>
        <URL>https://www.cosmos.esa.int/</URL>
        <Description>Cluster II Tango Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) data; open access but registration is required.</Description>
</AccessURL>
      <Format>CEF</Format>
</AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Tango/EDI</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ElectricField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2001-01-30T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
        <RelativeStopDate>-P3M</RelativeStopDate>
</TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT0.0625S</Cadence>
</TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.RadiationBelt</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.AuroralRegion</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Plasmasphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.PolarCap</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <Caveats>The measured electron drift velocity cannot always be separated into the electric-field and magnetic gradient induced parts; in such cases the computed electric fields are subject to contamination by magnetic gradient effects. The raw-data counts have to be corrected for the angular dependence of the efficiency. The status byte and the AEC-files must be used as described above. Ambient electron data are available since October 2004 on C1, C2 and C3, see CLIST files for time intervals. The EDI instrument on C2 is working only in ambient mode.</Caveats>
</NumericalData>
</Spase>
