<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_6_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.6.1</Version>
  <Service>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/Service/SPDF/DataService/HDO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Heliophysics Digital Observatory</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/7amg-2875</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2024-08-23T16:12:05</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
	<RevisionEvent>
	  <ReleaseDate>2024-09-30T17:26:15</ReleaseDate>
	  <Note>Updated author list in PublicationInfo. LNG</Note>
	</RevisionEvent>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2025-02-24T12:34:56.789Z</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Standardized lower case usage in DOI. LFB 20250224</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>Heliophysics research often requires the use of
	a variety of observational and model artifacts to study
	processes relating to mass and energy transfer across
	different heliophysics domains. The Heliophysics Digital
	Observatory (HDO) unifies several legacy discipline-oriented
	heliophysics virtual observatories via a more streamlined and
	intuitive middleware system that takes advantage of the Space
	Physics Archive Search and Extract (SPASE) metadata and focuses on
	delivering higher-level data search and discovery
	capabilities beyond those of existing data services. SPASE
	metadata enables HDO to search/discover, locate and access
	multi-disciplinary data and model artifacts simultaneously
	from distributed repositories. The HDO functionalities
	supporting the NASA Heliophysics science goals are summarized below:
	
	1) Search, locate, and access multi-disciplinary heliophysics digital
	resources (observational and model artifacts) to support research. 
	
	2) Support systems science research by providing simultaneous access
	to multi-disciplinary resources for multiple time intervals based 
	on (a) solar wind and geomagnetic conditions, (b) observing platform
	locations, and (c) phenomenon-based event lists. 
	
	3) The HDO built-in magnetospheric-state query system (MSQS) allows
	resource searching by solar wind, IMF and geomagnetic conditions,
	extreme or otherwise.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
	Please make the following acknowledgement in any resulting publication:
	"This research has made use of data provided by the Heliophysics Data Observatory (HDO)."
      </Acknowledgement>
      <PublicationInfo>
	<Authors>Fung, Shing F., Dolan, Charles F. and Garcia, Leonard N.</Authors>
	<PublicationDate>2024-09-19T18:03:40</PublicationDate>
	<PublishedBy>NASA Space Physics Data Facility</PublishedBy>
      </PublicationInfo>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Shing.F.Fung</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.F.Dolan</PersonID>
        <Role>Developer</Role>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>	
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Leonard.N.Garcia</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
	<Name>
	  Fung, Shing F., Charles F. Dolan and Leonard N. Garcia
	  (2021), The Heliophysics Digital Observatory (HDO): Providing
	  Enhanced High-Level Data Search Capabilities, SH44C-07,
	  presented at the AGU Fall Meeting 2021, New Orleans, December
	  13-17.
	</Name> 
	<URL>https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2021AGUFMSH44C..07F/abstract</URL>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
	<Name>
	  Fung, S. F., C. F. Dolan, and L. N. Garcia (2022), The
	  Nascent Heliophysics Digital Observatory (HDO): A
	  Follow-on to the Heliophysics VxOs, presented at the 44th
	  COSPAR Scientific Assembly,  
	  Athens, Greece, July 16-24.
	</Name>
	<URL>https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2022cosp...44.3485F/abstract</URL>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
	<Name>
	  Fung, Shing F.,  Hyunju K. Connor, Lan K. Jian,
	  Guiping Liu, Charles F. Dolan, and Leonard N. Garcia
	  (2024), The Heliophysics Digital Observatory (HDO): A
	  Service for Supporting Cross-Disciplinary Heliophysics
	  Research Community, presented at the 45th COSPAR Scientific
	  Assembly, Busan, South Korea, July 13-21.
	</Name>
	<URL>https://app.cospar-assembly.org/2023/browser/presentation/34768</URL>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessURL>
      <URL>https://msqs.gsfc.nasa.gov/hdo/public</URL>
      <Description>
	The HDO Query Builder interface enables access to data
	products via a time-range selection;
	users may alternatively choose to upload an event list
	of time ranges. The resultant time ranges may be filtered
	by domain resource type (Solar, Heliospheric,
	Magnetospheric, ITM and Wave), magnetospheric state (MSQS) 
	and/or by spacecraft location (via access to the SPDF/Satellite Situation
	Center). The resultant data products may be further filtered by
	resource type (Numerical, Display, Catalog, etc.). The main
	panel displays the available products and provides download
	access while the left sidebar captures all user selections and filters.
      </Description>
    </AccessURL>
  </Service>
</Spase>
