<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/NumericalData/CDPP-Archive/THEMIS-E/SCM/THEMIS_SCM_THE_L1_SCW</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>THEMIS-E SCM Search Coil Magnetometer Wave Burst Level-1 (CDF)</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/9jqm-w0sp</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-01-21T08:24:18Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This data set contains THEMIS-E Search Coil Magnetometer raw magnetic field in sensor coordinates, ADC units, Wave Burst Mode.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
        SCM data, as a data set of the THEMIS data products, are open to all scientists and the public (Users).

Users should contact the THEMIS Principal Investigator (PI) V. Angelopoulos and O. Le Contel the co-investigator (CoI) of the SCM instrument to consult on the appropriate use of instrument data.

Users should acknowledge the sources of data used in all publications, presentations, and reports.
Please send information on the use of these data to:

- PI: V. Angelopoulos [vassilis@ucla.edu]

- co-I: O. Le Contel [olivier.lecontel@lpp.polytechnique.fr]

We suggest to add the following lines into the acknowledgments:

The authors acknowledge NASA, CNES (Centre National d'Etudes Spatiales), CNRS (Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique) for their support to the THEMIS/SCM team and the CDPP (Centre de Données de la Physique des Plasmas) for the distribution of the THEMIS/SCM data.

and if PI/coI are not part of the publication list, then we suggest to add Specifically, we acknowledge V. Angelopous for use of data from the THEMIS mission, O. Le Contel and the late A. Roux for use of SCM data.
For more informations about data policy and credits, see http://themis.ssl.berkeley.edu/roadrules.shtml

The following papers should also be used to reference:

Roux, A., O. Le Contel, C. Coillot, A. Bouabdellah, B. de la Porte, D. Alison, S. Ruocco, and M.C. Vassal (2008), The search coil magnetometer for THEMIS, Space Sci. Rev., doi: 10.1007/s11214-008-9371-y.

Le Contel, O., A. Roux, P. Robert, C. Coillot, A. Bouabdellah, B. de la Porte, D. Alison, S. Ruocco, V. Angelopoulos, K. Bromund, C.C. Chaston, C. Cully, H.U. Auster, K.H. Glassmeier, W. Baumjohann, C.W. Carlson, J.P. McFadden, and D. Larson (2008), First results of the THEMIS search coil magnetometers, Space Sci. Rev., doi:10.1007/s11214-008-9371-y.	  
	  </Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Vassilis.Angelopoulos</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Olivier.Le.Contel</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/CDPP.general.contact</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://regards.cnes.fr/user/cdpp/modules/1777?sp=DatasetName;q=DatasetName:THEMIS_SCM_THE_L1_SCW</URL>
        <Description>Access via CNES Data Archive for CDPP</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>CDF</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Raw</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/THEMIS-E/SCM</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2007-02-24T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2020-03-31T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Raw Magnetic field B in XYZ Sensor Coordinates, ADC units, Wave Burst Mode</Name>
      <Description>Raw Magnetic field B in XYZ Sensor Coordinates, ADC units, Wave Burst Mode</Description>
      <Units>ADC</Units>
      <Field>
        <Qualifier>Vector</Qualifier>
        <FieldQuantity>Magnetic</FieldQuantity>
      </Field>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
