<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/NumericalData/CDPP-Archive/ISGI/Geomagnetic-Indices/Dst-index/INDICE_EQUATORIAL</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Equatorial Dst index</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/k8f1-b2xt</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-06-06T14:31:22Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This data set contains the Equatorial Dst index.

The Equatorial Dst index (Dst) is now prepared and issued in three steps. In the first step, a near real-time Dst, or quick-look Dst, is derived using data from any number of observatories of the five designated Dst observatories beginning with a 12-hour delay and updated on a daily basis. As in the case of the quick-look AE index, no quality check is made on the data used for the quick-look Dst index. Therefore it is recommended that the quick-look Dst index is used only for diagnostic purposes. It should not be used for scientific analyses. The second stage product is the provisional Dst index which is now being made available on a monthly basis with approximately 2 months delay. Beginning January 1997 th provisional Dst index is derived using data from 5 observatories including Alibag. The Dst index derived by the third step is the final Dst index published annually, normally with several months delay.

Recent index which is not yet validated is provisional Dst and indicated in the data files with a provisional  flag.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Michel.Menvielle</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/CDPP.general.contact</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://cdpp-archive.cnes.fr</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Binary</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/ISGI/Geomagnetic-Indices</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>ActivityIndex</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1975-01-01T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2002-12-31T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Dst index</Name>
      <Description>Dst index (hourly equatorial index horizontal component disturbances) used to monitor the axis-symmetric magnetic signature of magnetosphere currents, including mainly the ring current, the tail currents and also the magnetopause Chapman-Ferraro current.</Description>
      <Units>nT</Units>
      <UnitsConversion>10^-9&gt;T</UnitsConversion>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
