<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Jupiter/PT96.0S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Jupiter PLS Plasma Derived Ion Moments 96.0-s V1.1</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Data Set Overview                                                       
      =================                                                       
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Version 1.1                                                             
      -----------                                                             
      This version 1.1 data set replaces the version 1.0 data set             
      (DATA_SET_ID = VG2-J-PLS-5-ION-MOM-96.0SEC) previously                  
      archived with the PDS.  This data set was given a new DATA_SET_ID       
      and intentionally marked as V1.0.                                       
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Data Set Description                                                    
      --------------------                                                    
      This data set contains the best estimates of the total ion              
      density from Voyager 2 at Jupiter in the PLS voltage range              
      (10-5950 eV/Q). It is calculated using the method of                    
      [MCNUTTETAL1981] which to first order consists of taking the            
      total measured current and dividing by the collector area and           
      plasma bulk velocity. This method is only accurate for high             
      mach number flows directly into the detector, and may result            
      in underestimates of the total density of a factor of 2 in the          
      outer magnetosphere. Thus absolute densities should be treated          
      with caution, but density variations in the data set can be             
      trusted. The low resolution mode density is used at all times           
      except day 190 2100-2200 when the larger of the high and low            
      resolution mode densities in a 96 sec period is used.                   
      Corotation is assumed inside L=17.5, and a constant velocity            
      component of 200 km/s into the D cup is used outside of this.           
      These are the densities given in the [MCNUTTETAL1981] paper             
      corrected by a factor of 1.209 (.9617) for densities obtained           
      from the side (main) sensor. This correction is due to a                
      better calculation of the effective area of the sensors. Data           
      format: column 1 is time (yyyy-mm-ddThh:mm:ss.sssZ), column 2           
      is the moment density in cm^-3. Each row has format (a24, 1x,           
      1pe9.2). Values of -9.99e+10 indicate that the parameter could          
      not be obtained from the data using the standard analysis               
      technique. Additional information about this data set and the           
      instrument which produced it can be found elsewhere in this             
      catalog. An overview of the data in this data set can be found          
      in [MCNUTTETAL1981] and a complete instrument description can           
      be found in [BRIDGEETAL1977].                                           
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Processing Level Id            : 5                                      
      Software Flag                  : Y                                      
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Parameters                                                              
      ==========                                                              
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Ion Density                                                             
      -----------                                                             
      Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME                                   
      Data Set Parameter Name        : ION DENSITY                            
      Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 96.000000                              
      Sampling Parameter Interval    : 96.000000                              
      Minimum Available Sampling Int : 96.000000                              
      Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM^-3                                  
      Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND                                 
                                                                              
                                                                              
      A derived parameter equaling the number of ions per unit                
      volume over a specified range of ion energy, energy/charge, or          
      energy/nucleon. Discrimination with regard to mass and or               
      charge state is necessary to obtain this quantity, however,             
      mass and charge state are often assumed due to instrument               
      limitations.                                                            
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Many different forms of ion density are derived. Some are               
      distinguished by their composition (N+, proton, ion, etc.) or           
      their method of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of                   
      moments). In some cases, more than one type of density will be          
      provided in a single data set. In general, if more than one             
      ion species is analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total               
      density will be provided which is the sum of the ion                    
      densities. If a plasma component does not have a Maxwellian             
      distribution the actual distribution can be represented as the          
      sum of several Maxwellians, in which case the density of each           
      Maxwellian is given.                                                    
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Source Instrument Parameters                                            
      ============================                                            
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2                                   
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION DENSITY                           
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION RATE                              
                                        ION CURRENT                           
                                        PARTICLE MULTIPLE PARAMETERS          
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1 (for all parameters)                
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Processing                                                              
      ==========                                                              
                                                                              
                                                                              
      Processing History                                                      
      ------------------                                              </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PLS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1979-07-04T12:02:47.82</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1979-07-10T11:59:35.44</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT96.0S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
