<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/LECP/Uranus/PT12M48S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Uranus LECP Resampled RDR Stepping Sector 12.8-min V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                       
This data consists of resampled data from the Low Energy
Charged Particle (LECP) Experiment on the Voyager 2 Spacecraft
for the period when Voyager 2 was in the vicinity of the planet
Uranus.  The period covered is 1989/day 24/0000 SCET to
1989/day 27/0000 SCET.  This data gives scan plane angle
distributions for those periods when the LECP instrument was
mechanically scanning.  There are periods when the instrument
was not scanning, and the corresponding data does not appear
here with this Step data.  Another data set that is available,
the so called Scan data, contains data for these not stepping
periods as well as angle averaged data for the stepping periods.
The instrument samples 8 directional sectors during a single
scan, and thus this Step data contains 8 particle intensity
numbers for each channel of data utilized (a ninth sector
corresponds to accumulations for which the sector is unknown).
 
   Two scanning situations occurred during the time of this
data. They are: 1) continuous 48 sec stepping (48 seconds for
each of 8 look directions for a total of 6.4 minutes per scan;
note that sector 8 is shielded with 2 mm Al), and 2) a special 
Uranus scan cyclic with the following sequence: 7, scan, scan,
7, scan, scan, repeat; where the 7 represents a 10.4 minute
period when the instrument is fixed in sector 7, and where the
word scan represents a period of scanning (6 sec stepping
for a total scan time of 48 sec).  For this Uranus Scan data
the two adjacent scans within the Uranus scan cyclic (Mode 2 
above) have been averaged together into a single, 96 sec record.
The records of the 48 sec stepping mode (mode 1 above) are for 6.4
minutes.  The schedule of mode changes is as follows:
 
     prior to day 24/ 0420 SCET:    Mode (1)
 
     24/0420 to 25/1357:            Mode (2)
 
     after 25/1357:                 Mode (1)
 
Please note that the change-over between modes is not 
instantaneous, and that for a few minutes the state of
the scanning is not regular.  Note also that there were
brief interruptions to, and changes in time phase in, the
mode (2) scan cyclic during the transitions into and out of
the movable block period that bracketed the close approach
position (not shown above).
 
     Obviously these stepping mode changes, and the angle sample
switching that occurs during stepping mode (2), gives the data
a disjointed appearance.
 
     The LECP channels utilized with this data set are:
 
       EB01:          electrons,  22 to  35 keV
       EB02:          electrons,  35  to  61 keV
       EB03:          electrons,  61 to  112 keV
       EB04:          electrons, 112 to 183 keV
       EG06-EG07:     electrons, 252 to 480 keV
       EG07-EG08:     electrons, 480 to 853 keV
       EG08-EG09:     electrons, 853 to 1200 keV
       PL01:          ions,       28 to  43  keV
       PL02:          ions,       43 to  80  keV
       PL03:          ions,       80 to 137  keV
       PL04:          ions,      137 to 215  keV
       PL05:          ions,      215 to 540  keV
       PL06:          ions,      540 to 990  keV
       PL07:          ions,      990 to 2140 keV
       PL08:          ions,     2140 to 3500 keV
 
Please note that 3 of the electron channels are derived from
4 of the instrumental channels by taking differences between
adjacent (in energy) channels.
 
     The channel data is given in units of intensity:
counts/(cm^2.sec.str.keV).  For the ions, it has been assumed
that they consist only of protons.  Intensity is derived from
the raw count rates via the relation:
 
                    I  =  CR/(eG.(E2-E1),
 
where eG is geometric factor times detector efficiency, and
(E2-E1) is the band pass of the channel in energy.  The proton
values of these parameters were used in deriving the intensities
for this data set.  To obtain the Intensities under the assumption
that some other mass species dominates, one must convert back
to count rate (CR) utilizing the proton parameters, and then 
convert to intensity using the parameters corresponding to the
mass species in question.  The parameters can be found in
Table 1 of Krimigis et al. (Journal of Geophysical Research,
V. 86, page 8227, 1981).  The corresponding parameters for electrons
can be found in Mauk et al. (Journal of Geophysical Research,
V. 92, page 15283, 1987).  Prior to the conversion to intensity,
the count rates have been corrected for: (1) Background, 
(2) electron contamination of the lower energy ion channels, and
(3) solar UV contamination of the lowest energy ion channel.
 
     The uncertainty parameters given with the data associated with
each channel (expressed as a percent) is the largest of the
two quantities: (i) one standard deviation Poisson statistical
error, and (ii) a percentage assigned by the data supplier
based on the amount of contamination correction that has been 
performed on each data channel.
 
     Also supplied with each record of this data set is the
fraction of the data accumulations that correspond to each
of the 8 angle sectors.  A sector 9 has also been defined
corresponding to those accumulations with no known sector 
assignment.
 
    Additionally supplied for each data channel is a one bit code
that tells whether that channel had any accumulations at
all associated with it (1 = yes; 0 = no).  This code must be
used to distinguish between accumulations that yielded no counts
and situations where the channel simply had no accumulations
(results in Intensity = 0.0).

Processing Level Id            : 4      
Software Flag                  : N      
Processing Start Time          : 1991-07-24      
Processing Stop Time           : 1991-07-25      

Parameters    
==========       

Data Set Parameter &apos;PARTICLE FLUX INTENSITY&apos;      
--------------------------------------------        
The channel data is given in units of intensity:        
counts/(cm^2.sec.str.keV).  For the ions, it has been assumed        
that they consist only of protons.  Intensity is derived from        
the raw count rates via the relation:                           

                    I = CR/(eG.(E2-E1),         

where eG is geometric factor times detector efficiency, and        
(E2-E1) is the band pass of the channel in energy.  The        
proton values of these parameters were used in deriving the        
intensities for this data set.  To obtain the Intensities        
under the assumption that some other mass species dominates,        
one must convert back to count rate (CR) utilizing the proton        
parameters, and then convert to intensity using the        
parameters corresponding to the mass species in question.        
The parameters can be found in Table 1 of Krimigis et al.        
(Journal of Geophysical Research, V.  86, page 8227, 1981).        
The corresponding parameters for electrons can be found in        
Mauk et al.  (Journal of Geophysical Research, V.  92, page        
15283, 1987).  Prior to the conversion to intensity, the        
count rates have been corrected for: (1) Background, (2)        
electron contamination of the lower energy ion channels, and        
(3) solar UV contamination of the lowest energy ion channel.         

Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME        
Data Set Parameter Name        : PARTICLE FLUX INTENSITY        
Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 768.000000        
Sampling Parameter Interval    : 768.000000        
Minimum Available Sampling Int : 6.000000        
Data Set Parameter Unit        :                          
                   COUNTS/(CM**2*SECOND*STERRADIAN*KEV)        
Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND      S

Source Instrument Parameters    
============================      
Instrument Host ID              : VG2      
Data Set Parameter Name         : PARTICLE FLUX INTENSITY      
Instrument Parameter Name       : PARTICLE MULTIPLE PARAMETERS      
Important Instrument Parameters : 1      

Processing    
==========       
   Processing History      
   ----------------</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-U-LECP-4-RDR-STEP-12.8MIN-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-U-LECP-4-RDR-STEP-12.8MIN-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-U-LECP-4-RDR-STEP-12.8MIN-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-U-LECP-4-RDR-STEP-12.8MIN-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/LECP</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1986-01-24T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1986-01-27T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT12M48S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Uranus</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
