<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <Version>2.2.2</Version>
    <NumericalData>
        <ResourceID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Pioneer11/PLS/PT60M</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Pioneer 11 Plasma 1-hr data</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2020-07-03T23:28:58Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>This data set consists of hourly resolution data in ASCII format from the Pioneer 11 Plasma Analyzer. It contains five types of data:
'REDR' and EDR data, Spectral' data, 'summary' (high resolution) parameter data, hourly averaged parameter data, and trajectory data. The plasma bulk parameters (bulk velocity, proton number density, proton temperature, and flow angles) were obtained using one of three processing schemes described in the data set documentation. Hourly averaged data files were created by averaging every valid parameter in each hour, regardless of the processing scheme used to derive it. Each plasma data file contains a header followed by data records. The filename format is p10_XX_YYh.asc where XX and YY are the start and end years of data in the file. Each data record contains the spacecraft ID (SCID), year, day of year, and time of day in hours, followed by the bulk velocity, number density, temperature, and where appropriate, the flow angles. Speeds are given in km/s, number densities are given in #/cc, temperatures are given in K, and flow angles are given in degrees. Prior to day Jan. 31, 1989, all directions are given in a spacecraft-centered ecliptic system, in which the E/W angle is positive in the direction of planetary rotation while a N/S angle of zero means that the solar wind flow is parallel to the plane of the ecliptic. After Jan. 31, 1989 the flow directions are given with respect to a RTN heliographic system for which the R component is radially outward from the Sun, T is in the direction of planetary orbital motion around the Sun, and N is orthogonal (RxT) to R and T.
</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.R.Gazis</PersonID>
                <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
            </Contact>
            <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/P_PION11_HDR_PLASMA_1HR</PriorID>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <AccessInformation>
            <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF</RepositoryID>
            <Availability>Online</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
                <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/pioneer/pioneer11/plasma/hour/</URL>
            </AccessURL>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
                <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/pioneer/pioneer11/plasma/hour/</URL>
                <Description>In CDF via HTTP from SPDF</Description>
            </AccessURL>
            <Format>Text</Format>
        </AccessInformation>
        <ProviderProcessingLevel>CALIBRATED</ProviderProcessingLevel>
        <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Pioneer11/PLS</InstrumentID>
        <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>1973-04-06T00:00:00</StartDate>
                <StopDate>1976-12-31T00:00:00</StopDate>
            </TimeSpan>
            <Cadence>PT60M</Cadence>
        </TemporalDescription>
        <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
    </NumericalData>
</Spase>