<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/Ephemeris/Neptune/PT48S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune Trajectory Derived Summary Heliographic Coords 48-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
     This dataset contains Voyager 2 position vectors relative to the Sun     
     in both cartesian and spherical Heliographic coordinates for the time    
     period when Voyager was near Neptune but not within its magnetosphere.   
     The magnetospheric gap in this dataset occurs                            
     from 1989-08-25 02:00 -&gt; 1989-08-26 00:00. Spacecraft position           
     vectors are given in Neptune Longitude System (NLS) coordinates in       
     this interval. The position vectors are given every 48 seconds. The      
     units of the vector components are Au and degrees.  Vectors are stored   
     as 4-byte floating point values.                                         
                                                                              
     The Heliographic coordinate system is defined in the reference epoch of  
     1950. The unit vectors which define the coordinate system are as follows:
     X points away from the Sun toward the ascending node, in the             
     solar equatorial plane, Z points along                                   
     the Sun&apos;s spin axis, positive above the equatorial plane, and Y          
     completes the right handed set.                                          
                                                                              
  Parameters                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Sampling parameter name             : time                                
    Sampling parameter resolution       : 96.0 seconds                        
    Minimum sampling parameter          : n/a                                 
    Maximum sampling parameter          : n/a                                 
    Sampling parameter interval         : 48.0 seconds                        
    Minimum available sampling interval : 48.0 seconds                        
    Data set parameter name             : position vector                     
    Noise level                         : n/a                                 
    Data set parameter unit             : AU or degrees                       
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Coordinates                                                                 
  ===========                                                                 
                                                                              
    MEAN INERTIAL HG 1950                                                     
    ---------------------                                                     
     COORDINATE_SYSTEM_CENTER_NAME = SUN                                      
     COORDINATE_SYSTEM_REF_EPOCH   = UNK /* 09-23-1950 */                     
                                                                              
      The Heliographic coordinate system is defined in the reference          
      epoch of 1950. The unit vectors which define the coordinate             
      system are as follows: X points away from the Sun towards the           
      ascending node, in the solar equatorial plane, Z points along           
      the Sun&apos;s spin axis, positive above the equatorial plane,               
      and Y completes the right handed set.                                   
                                                                              
      Position is given in terms of the following:                            
                                                                              
      RANGE (R)      - The range or R component of the spherical              
                       Heliographic coordinate system is the distance         
                       from the Sun&apos;s position at the reference epoch         
                       to the spacecraft measured in AU.                      
      LATITUDE (LAT) - The latitude component of the spherical                
                       Heliographic coordinate system is the angle            
                       between the solar equatorial plane of the              
                       reference epoch measured in the plane that             
                       contains the solar spin axis of that epoch.            
      LONGITUDE (LONG) - The longitude component of the spherical             
                       Heliographic coordinate system is zero in the          
                       direction of the ascending node at the                 
                       reference epoch (X direction) and increases            
                       for a body orbiting the Sun as the Earth does.         
                                                                              
      X              - The X component of the Heliographic coordinate         
                       system points away from the Sun, towards the           
                       ascending node, and lies in the solar equatorial       
                       plane.                                                 
      Y              - The Y vector of the Heliographic coordinate            
                       system is formed by the righthanded cross              
                       product of the X and Z unit vectors. It lies in        
                       the solar equatorial plane and it points away          
                       from the Sun, but does not extend in the               
                       direction of any particular body.                      
      Z              - The Z component of the Heliographic coordinate         
                       system is parallel to the Sun&apos;s spin axis,             
                       taken as positive above the equatorial plane of        
                       the Sun.</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-POS-5-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-POS-5-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-POS-5-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-POS-5-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/Ephemeris</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Ephemeris</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-08-22T00:00:47.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-08-29T23:59:58.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT48S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
