<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Jupiter/PT0.60S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>VG2 J/S/U/N/SS PLASMA WAVE SPECTROMETER RAW WFRM 60MS V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2014-12-01T10:16:14.26</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    This data set consists of electric field waveform samples from            
    the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Subsystem waveform receiver obtained            
    during the entire mission.  Data after 2006-03-07 will be added to the    
    archive on subsequent volumes.  The data set encompasses all              
    waveform observations obtained in the cruise mission phases               
    before, between, and after the Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and               
    Neptune encounter phases as well as those obtained during the             
    four encounter phases.                                                    
                                                                              
    The Voyager 2 spacecraft travels from Earth to beyond 80 AU over          
    the course of this data set.  To provide some guidance on when            
    some key events occurred during the mission, the following table          
    is provided.                                                              
                                                                              
    Date         Event                                                        
    1977-08-20   Launch                                                       
    1979-07-02   First inbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter                  
    1979-08-03   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter                  
    1981-08-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Saturn                   
    1981-08-31   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Saturn                   
    1982-04-26   10 AU                                                        
    1983-08-30   Onset of first major LF heliospheric radio event             
    1986-01-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Uranus                   
    1986-01-29   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Uranus                   
    1986-05-26   20 AU                                                        
    1989-08-07   30 AU                                                        
    1989-08-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Neptune                  
    1989-08-28   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Neptune                  
    1992-07-06   Onset of second major LF heliospheric radio event            
    1993-05-08   40 AU                                                        
    1996-10-10   50 AU                                                        
    2000-01-27   60 AU                                                        
    2002-11-01   Onset of third major LF heliospheric radio event             
    2003-04-21   70 AU                                                        
    2006-07-01   80 AU                                                        
    2009-09-03   90 AU                                                        
    2012-11-04   100 AU                                                       
                                                                              
  Data Sampling                                                               
  =============                                                               
    The waveform is sampled at 4-bit resolution through a bandpass            
    filter with a passband of 40 Hz to 12 kHz.  1600 samples are              
    collected in 55.56 msec (at a rate of 28,800 samples per second)          
    followed by a 4.44-msec gap.  Each 60-msec interval constitutes           
    a line of waveform samples.  The data set includes frames of              
    waveform samples consisting of up to 800 lines, or 48 seconds,            
    each.  The telemetry format for the waveform data is identical            
    to that for images, hence the use of line and frame as                    
    constructs in describing the form of the data.                            
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Data Processing                                                             
  ===============                                                             
    Because there is no direct method for calibrating these data and          
    because the raw format of packed, 4-bit samples is                        
    space-efficient, these data are not processed for archiving.              
    The data may be plotted in raw form to show the actual waveform;          
    this is useful for studying events such as dust impacts on the            
    spacecraft.  But the normal method of analyzing the waveform              
    data is by Fourier transforming the samples from each line to             
    arrive at an amplitude versus frequency spectrum.  By stacking            
    the spectra side-by-side in time order, a frequency-time                  
    spectrogram can be produced.                                              
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Data                                                                        
  ====                                                                        
    The waveforms are collections of samples of the electric field            
    measured by the dipole electric antenna at a rate of 28,800               
    samples per second.  The 4-bit samples provide sixteen digital            
    values of the electric field with a linear amplitude scale, but           
    the amplitude scale is arbitrary because of the automatic gain            
    control used in the waveform receiver.  The instantaneous                 
    dynamic range afforded by the 4 bit samples is about 23 dB, but           
    the automatic gain control allows the dominant signal in the              
    passband to be set at the optimum level to fit within the                 
    instantaneous dynamic range.  With the gain control, the overall          
    dynamic range of the waveform receiver is about 100 dB.  The              
    automatic gain control gain setting is not returned to the                
    ground, hence, there is no absolute calibration for the data.             
    However, by comparing the waveform spectrum derived by Fourier            
    transforming the waveform to the spectrum provided by the                 
    spectrum analyzer data, an absolute calibration may be obtained           
    in most cases.                                                            
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Ancillary Data                                                              
  ==============                                                              
    None                                                                      
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Coordinates                                                                 
  ===========                                                                 
    The electric dipole antenna detects electric fields in a dipole           
    pattern with peak sensitivity parallel to the spacecraft x-axis.          
    However, no attempt has been made to correlate the measured               
    field to any particular direction such as the local magnetic              
    field or direction to a planet.  This is because the spacecraft           
    remains in a 3-axis stabilized orientation almost continuously,   </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-J/S/U/N/SS-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-J-S-U-N-SS-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?id=pds://PPI/VG2-J_S_U_N_SS-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-J/S/U/N/SS-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1979-04-28T07:59:16.71</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>2006-03-07T08:48:51.579</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT0.60S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
