<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Jupiter/PT0.132S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>VG2 J/S/U/N/SS PWS EDITED SPECTRUM ANALYZER FULL RES V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2014-12-01T10:16:14.76</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>

  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set consists of electric field spectrum analyzer data
    from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Subsystem obtained during the
    entire mission.  Data after 2013-12-31 will be added to the archive      
    on subsequent volumes.  The data set encompasses all spectrum
    analyzer observations obtained in the cruise mission phases
    before, between, and after the Jupiter and Saturn encounter phases
    as well as those obtained during the two encounter phases.

    The Voyager 2 spacecraft travels from Earth to beyond 80 AU over
    the course of this data set.  To provide some guidance on when
    some key events occurred during the mission, the following table
    is provided.

    Date         Event
    1977-08-20   Launch
    1979-07-02   First inbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter
    1979-08-03   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter
    1981-08-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Saturn
    1981-08-31   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Saturn
    1982-04-26   10 AU
    1983-08-30   Onset of first major LF heliospheric radio event
    1986-01-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Uranus
    1986-01-29   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Uranus
    1986-05-26   20 AU
    1989-08-07   30 AU
    1989-08-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Neptune
    1989-08-28   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Neptune
    1992-07-06   Onset of second major LF heliospheric radio event
    1993-05-08   40 AU
    1996-10-10   50 AU
    2000-01-27   60 AU
    2002-11-01   Onset of third major LF heliospheric radio event
    2003-04-21   70 AU
    2006-07-01   80 AU
    2009-09-03   90 AU
    2012-11-04   100 AU


  Data Sampling
  =============
    This data set consists of full resolution edited, wave electric
    field intensities from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver spectrum
    analyzer obtained during the entire mission.  For each time
    interval, a field strength is determined for each of the 16
    spectrum analyzer channels whose center frequencies range from 10
    Hertz to 56.2 kiloHertz and which are logarithmically spaced in
    frequency, four channels per decade.  The time associated with
    each set of intensities (16 channels) is the time of the beginning
    of the scan.  The time between spectra in this data set vary by
    telemetry mode and range from 4 seconds to 96 seconds.  During
    data gaps where complete spectra are missing, no entries exist in
    the file, that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged in any
    other way.  When one or more channels are missing within a scan,
    the missing measurements are zero-filled.  Data are edited but not
    calibrated.  The data numbers in this data set can be plotted in
    raw form for event searches and simple trend analysis since they
    are roughly proportional to the log of the electric field
    strength.  Calibration procedures and tables are provided for use
    with this data set; the use of these is described below.

    For the cruise data sets, the timing of samples is dependent upon
    the spacecraft telemetry mode.  In principle, one can determine
    the temporal resolution between spectra simply by noting the
    difference in time between two records in the files.  In some
    studies, more precise timing information is necessary.  Here, we
    describe the timing of the samples for the PWS low rate data as a
    function of telemetry mode.

    The PWS instrument uses two logarithmic compressors as detectors
    for the 16-channel spectrum analyzer, one for the bottom (lower
    frequency) 8 channels, and one for the upper (higher frequency) 8
    channels.  For each bank of 8 channels, the compressor
    sequentially steps from the lowest frequency of the 8 to the
    highest in a regular time step to obtain a complete spectrum.  At
    each time step, the higher frequency channel is sampled 1/8 s
    prior to the lower frequency channel so that the channels are
    sampled in the following order with channel 1 being the lowest
    frequency channel (10 Hz) and 16 being the highest (56.2 kHz): 9,
    1, 10, 2, 11, 3, ...  15, 7, 16, 8.  The primary difference
    between the various data modes is the stepping rate from one
    channel to the next (ranging from 0.5 to 12 s, corresponding to
    temporal resolutions between complete spectra of 4 s to 96 s).

    In the following table, we present the hexadecimal id for the
    various telemetry modes, the mode mnemonic ID, the time between
    frequency steps, and the time between complete spectra.  We also
    provide the offset from the beginning of the instrument cycle (one
    complete spectrum) identified as the time of each record&apos;s time
    tag to the time of the sampling for the first high-frequency
    channel (channel 9) and for the first low-frequency channel
    (channel 1).

                                    Time
                        Frequency   Between      High Freq.  Low Freq.
  MODE (Hex)  MODE ID   Step (s)    Spectra (s)  offset (s)  offset (s)
     01         CR-2    0.5              4.0         0.425     0.4325
     02         CR-3    1.2              9.6         1.125     1.1325
     03         CR-4    4.8             38.4         0.425     0.4325
     04         CR-5    9.6             76.8         0.425     0.4325
     05         CR-6    12.             96.0         0.9275    0.935
     06         CR-7    NOT IMPLEMENTED
     07         CR-1    0.5              4.0         0.225     0.2325
     08         GS-10A  SAME AS GS-3
     0A         GS-3    0.5              4.0         0.425     0.4325
     0C         GS-7    SAME AS GS-3
     0E         GS-6    SAME AS GS-3
     16         OC-2    SAME AS GS-3
     17         OC-1    SAME AS GS-3
     18       **CR-5A   0.5              4.0         0.425     0.4325
     19         GS-10   SAME AS GS-3
     1A         GS-8    SAME AS GS-3
     1D       **UV-5A   SAME AS CR-5A

    **In CR-5A and UV-5A, the PWS is cycled at its 0.5 sec/frequency
    step or 4 sec/spectrum rate, but 4 measurements are summed on
    board in 10-bit accumulators and these 10-bit sums are downlinked.
    On the ground, the sums are divided by 4, hence providing, in a
    sense, 16-second averages.  One of every 12 sets of sums is
    dropped on board in order to avoid LECP stepper motor
    interference.


  Data Processing
  ===============
    The spectrum analyzer data are a continuous (where data are
    available) low resolution data set which provides wave intensity as
    a function of frequency (16 log-spaced channels) and time (one
    spectrum per time intervals ranging from 4 seconds to 96 seconds,
    depending on telemetry mode).  The data are typically plotted as
    amplitude vs. time for one or more of the channels in a strip-chart
    like display, or can be displayed as a frequency-time spectrogram
    using a gray- or color-bar to indicate amplitude.  With only sixteen
    channels, it is usually best to stretch the frequency axis by
    interpolating from one frequency channel to the next either linearly
    or with a spline fit.  One must be aware if the frequency axis is
    stretched that more resolution may be implied than is really
    present.  The Voyager PWS calibration table is given in an ASCII
    text file named VG2PWSCL.TAB (for Voyager-2).  This provides
    information to convert the uncalibrated &apos;data number&apos; output of the
    PWS 16-channel spectrum analyzer to calibrated antenna voltages for
    each frequency channel.  Following is a brief description of this
    file and a tutorial in its application.

    Descriptive headers have been removed from this file.  The columns
    included are IDN, ICHAN01, ICHAN02, ICHAN03, ICHAN04, ICHAN05,
    ICHAN06, ... ICHAN16.

    The first column lists an uncalibrated data number followed by the
    corresponding value in calibrated volts for each of the 16
    frequency channels of the PWS spectrum analyzer.  Each line
    contains calibrations fo</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-J/S/U/N/SS-PWS-2-RDR-SAFULL-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-J-S-U-N-SS-PWS-2-RDR-SAFULL-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?id=pds://PPI/VG2-J_S_U_N_SS-PWS-2-RDR-SAFULL-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-J/S/U/N/SS-PWS-2-RDR-SAFULL-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1977-08-20T15:53:34.88</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>2014-01-01T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT0.132S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
