<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Jupiter/PT1H</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>VG2 J/S/U/N/SS PWS RESAMP SPECTRUM ANALYZER HOUR AVG V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2014-12-01T10:16:15.22</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>

  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set consists of electric field spectrum analyzer data from
    the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Subsystem obtained during the entire
    mission.  Data after 2013-12-31 will be added to the archive on          
    subsequent volumes.  The data set encompasses all spectrum analyzer      
    observations obtained in the cruise mission phases before, between,
    and after the Jupiter and Saturn encounter phases as well as those
    obtained during the two encounter phases.

    The Voyager 2 spacecraft travels from Earth to beyond 75 AU over the
    course of this data set.  To provide some guidance on when some key
    events occurred during the mission, the following table is provided.

    Date         Event
    1977-08-20   Launch
    1979-07-02   First inbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter
    1979-08-03   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Jupiter
    1981-08-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Saturn
    1981-08-31   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Saturn
    1982-04-26   10 AU
    1983-08-30   Onset of first major LF heliospheric radio event
    1986-01-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Uranus
    1986-01-29   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Uranus
    1986-05-26   20 AU
    1989-08-07   30 AU
    1989-08-24   First inbound bow shock crossing at Neptune
    1989-08-28   Last outbound bow shock crossing at Neptune
    1992-07-06   Onset of second major LF heliospheric radio event
    1993-05-08   40 AU
    1996-10-10   50 AU
    2000-01-27   60 AU
    2002-11-01   Onset of third major LF heliospheric radio event
    2003-04-21   70 AU
    2006-07-01   80 AU
    2009-09-03   90 AU
    2012-11-04   100 AU


  Data Sampling
  =============
    This data set consists of average and peak wave electric field
    intensities accumulated over 1-hour intervals from the Voyager 2
    Plasma Wave Receiver spectrum analyzer obtained during the entire
    mission.  For each 1-hour time interval squares of the calibrated
    electric field measurements obtained during each hour-long interval
    in each of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels are summed and then
    divided by the number of measurements.  The square root of the
    resulting value is obtained and stored as the average electric field
    strength for the respective channel.  During the same hour-long
    interval, the maximum electric field strength acquired in each of
    the 16 channels is also recorded and stored as the peak electric
    field strength for the respective channel.  Hence, for each hour, an
    average and peak electric field spectrum from 10 Hz to 56.2 kHz is
    obtained.  The 16 spectrum analyzer channels have center frequencies
    that range from 10 Hertz to 56.2 kiloHertz and are logarithmically
    spaced in frequency, four channels per decade.  The time associated
    with each peak and average spectrum is the time of the beginning of
    the averaging interval.  Given variations in the sweep rate of the
    instrument (from a minimum of 4 seconds/sweep to a maximum of 96
    seconds/sweep) the maximum number of samples in an hour-long
    interval can range from 900 to 38.  Data gaps within the interval
    can further reduce the number of samples.

    During data gaps where complete spectra are missing, no entries
    exist in the file, that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged
    in any other way.


  Data Processing
  ===============
    The spectrum analyzer data are a continuous (where data are
    available) low resolution data set which provides wave intensity as
    a function of frequency (16 log-spaced channels) and time (one
    spectrum per time intervals ranging from 4 seconds to 96 seconds in
    the full-resolution data set, depending on telemetry mode.) This
    data set includes one-hour average and peak values for each channel.
    The data are typically plotted as amplitude vs. time for one or more
    of the channels in a strip-chart like display, or can be displayed
    as a frequency-time spectrogram using a gray- or color-bar to
    indicate amplitude.  With only sixteen channels, it is usually best
    to stretch the frequency axis by interpolating from one frequency
    channel to the next either linearly or with a spline fit.  One must
    be aware if the frequency axis is stretched that more resolution may
    be implied than is really present.

    The measurements provided in the average and peak electric field
    spectra included in this data set are in units of electric field
    (volts/meter).

    Spectral density units may be obtained by dividing the square of the
    electric field value by the nominal frequency bandwidth of the
    corresponding spectrum analyzer channel.

      specdens = (efield(ichan))**2 / bandwidth(ichan)

    Finally, power flux may be obtained by dividing the spectral density
    by the impedance of free space in ohms:

      pwrflux = (efield(ichan))**2 / bandwidth(ichan) / 376.73

    The center frequencies and bandwidths of each PWS spectrum analyzer
    channel for each Voyager spacecraft are given below:

      VOYAGER 2 PWS SPECTRUM ANALYZER
      Voyager-2
      Channel    Center Frequency      Bandwidth
          1          10.0  Hz           2.16 Hz
          2          17.8  Hz           3.58 Hz
          3          31.1  Hz           4.50 Hz
          4          56.2  Hz          10.7  Hz
          5         100.   Hz          13.8  Hz
          6         178.   Hz          28.8  Hz
          7         311.   Hz          39.8  Hz
          8         562.   Hz          75.9  Hz
          9           1.00 kHz         75.9  Hz
         10           1.78 kHz        151.   Hz
         11           3.11 kHz        324.   Hz
         12           5.62 kHz        513.   Hz
         13          10.0  kHz        832.   Hz
         14          17.8  kHz       1260    Hz
         15          31.1  kHz       2400    Hz
         16          56.2  kHz       3800    Hz


    A failure in the Voyager 2 Flight Data System which occurred about 3
    months after launch has adversely affected the calibration of PWS
    channels 9 through 16.  An algorithm has been devised to partially
    correct for this failure, and has proven useful for Voyager 2
    Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune encounters, but is not valid
    for Earth-Jupiter cruise and may be modified in the future.  The
    following implementation of this correction algorithm in FORTRAN
    assumes that uncalibrated data numbers are stored in a 16-element
    integer array, idn, with the array index equal to the PWS channel
    number:

      c     &apos;the old noise level&apos; for vg2 pws

            real tonl(9:16) /2.0, 1.0, -1.0, -2.0, -3.0, 1.0, 2.0, 1.0/

            do ichan = 9, 16
              if (idn(ichan) .gt. 0) then
                if (idn(ichan) .lt. 64) idn(ichan) = 64
                if (idn(ichan) .le. 72) then
                  idn(ichan) = int (tonl(ichan) - 530.4 +
           &amp;                   8.6 * float (idn(ichan)))
                else
                  idn(ichan) = int (tonl(ichan) + 20.113 +
           &amp;                   0.99 * float (idn(ichan)))
                end if
              end if
            end do

    This correction has been applied to the appropriate data in this
    data set.

    Additional information about this data set and the instrument which
    produced it can be found elsewhere in this catalog.  A complete
    instrument description can be found in [SCARF&amp;GURNETT1977].


  Data
  ====
    The average and peak spectrum analyzer data are a continuous (where
    data are available) low resolution data set which provides wave
    intensity as a function of frequency (16 log-spaced channels) and
    time (one spectrum per hour).  Each sample is a floating point
    electric field strength in units of volts/meter.


  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    None


  Coordinates
  ===========
    The electric dipole antenna detects electric fields </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-J/S/U/N/SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-J-S-U-N-SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?id=pds://PPI/VG2-J_S_U_N_SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-J/S/U/N/SS-PWS-4-SUMM-SA1HOUR-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1977-08-20T07:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>2014-01-01T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT1H</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
