<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Jupiter/PT1S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Jupiter Plasma Wave Spectrometer Density 1-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>

  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set consists of ASCII formatted plasma wave frequency
    and electron plasma density measurements as measured by the Plasma
    Waves Science instrument and calculated from the equations of cold 
    plasma theory.  These frequency measurements were taken from 
    Voyager 2 electric field waveform samples from Voyager 2 Plasma 
    Wave Science (PWS) waveform receiver obtained during its Jupiter 
    flyby.  The data set includes select measurements from spacecraft
    event time (SCET) 1979-07-04T23:44:47.500Z to 
    1979-07-11T23:58:22.500Z.  The data are separated into day files
    and the individual data points are taken every 1-second.  As will
    be explained in more detail below, the frequency measurements and 
    therefore the density measurements in this data set are measured 
    from high-resolution wideband plasma wave spectra.  To learn more 
    about these spectra and their specific submitted volumes, see the 
    Related PDS Products section in the AAREADME files found in the 
    root directory of this volume. 
  
  Parameters
  ==========
    While the data essential to this volume are the electron plasma
    densities, there are a number of other plasma parameters included 
    with this data.  The data set consists of ASCII files with one
    record per time step, occurring in 1-second increments.  Each
    record includes the time, magnetic field strength (obtained from
    the Voyager 2 magnetometer), the electron cyclotron frequency (if
    available), the frequency of the cutoff or resonance measured, a 
    code indicating the name of the frequency measured, the calculated
    electron density, and a set of position coordinates for the 
    spacecraft at the time of the observation.  Also included in each
    record are the electron plasma frequency fpe, extraordinary mode 
    cutoff frequency fR=0, ordinary mode cutoff frequency fL=0, upper
    hybrid resonance frequency fUH, and a quality index.  One of these
    four frequencies is just a copy of the measured cutoff or resonance
    frequency while the remaining frequencies are calculated using the
    magnetic field data and the equations of cold plasma theory.  
    Different files are used for each day.

  Processing
  ==========
    The ASCII density data files produced in this volume were derived
    from measuring the characteristic frequencies from the local plasma.
    The density was calculated from these data, along with cyclotron
    frequency data derived from magnetic field data, using the equations
    of cold plasma theory. 
    
    In order to measure these characteristic frequencies, this work 
    utilizes a new program that allows the operator to highlight the 
    general vicinity of the cutoff or resonance on a frequency-time 
    spectrogram.  Then, an algorithm finds the cutoff or resonance in 
    the region and records the frequency at 1 second intervals.  Hence,
    the automated procedure has a high temporal resolution (1 second) 
    and requires a relatively low level of both manual effort and
    subjective judgment by the operator.
  
    There are two different algorithms used: one for cutoff detection
    and one for resonance or peak detection.  The cutoff detection 
    algorithm is controlled by a small number of parameters that can 
    be set by the operator.  The first parameter is the cutoff level.  
    In determining possible cutoff candidates, the algorithm scans the 
    region highlighted by the operator and records two separate points,
    one above the cutoff level and one below.  The closer the two points
    are, temporally, the steeper the slope will be.  Therefore, the 
    operator can change the location of the cutoff level to manipulate 
    where the algorithm looks for cutoffs within the highlighted region
    of interest.  The next parameter is the slope magnitude, which 
    designates the minimum magnitude of the finite difference slope 
    where the cutoff must reside.  The operator may raise the slope 
    level in order to scan only for sharp cutoffs, or lower it in order
    to accommodate less steep slopes, depending on the quality of the 
    spectrum data.  When there is more than one possible cutoff, the 
    detection program will display them as cutoff candidates.  The 
    cutoff level, slope magnitude and cutoff candidates are displayed by
    the program for viewing by the operator.  While the algorithm 
    chooses the lowest frequency cutoff by default, the operator may 
    override the algorithm and choose any of the possible cutoffs to be
    recorded.
    
    While most of the characteristic frequencies are, by definition, 
    the cutoff of propagating wave modes, there are certain 
    circumstances when the characteristic frequency is denoted as the
    peak of a wave mode in the spectrum.  Because of this, there is an
    algorithm specifically for resonance or peak detection.  Many 
    spectra of interest to this study include Z-mode radiation, which 
    has a low-frequency cutoff at fL=0.  Barbosa et al. 
    [BARBOSAETAL1990B] demonstrated that taking the peak of the Z-mode
    as fL=0 yields the highest consistency in the determination of 
    fpe.  Hence, when the Z-mode is enhanced, we utilize the peak 
    detection algorithm to identify fL=0 from which fpe and the 
    electron density can be derived.  This algorithm can also be used 
    to determine fUH when an enhancement at that frequency is present 
    in the spectrum.  In order to measure this resonance or spectral 
    peak, the peak detection algorithm fits a Gaussian curve to the 
    highest peak within the region specified by the program operator.  
    The algorithm then records the frequency of the Gaussian&apos;s peak 
    as the peak frequency in the spectrum.  The algorithm displays 
    the spectrum and a darker line which is the Gaussian.  Because 
    there may be noise which exhibits a large peak in the highlighted 
    spectrum, the spectrum is displayed along with the Gaussian curve 
    and a vertical line designating where the peak was measured.  
    The operator always has the ability to manually change the peak&apos;s 
    location and alter the measurement in such cases.  
     
    While the operator utilizes a color spectrogram to guide the cutoff
    and peak detectors, we emphasize that this is only used as a means
    of identifying the appropriate range in frequency for the algorithm
    to search.  The direct use of color spectrograms tends to mislead 
    an operator to perceive a cutoff that is not equivalent to the 
    cutoff in the actual power spectrum [BARBOSAETAL1990B]. Because
    this may lead to a systematic error in the data, the algorithm 
    utilizes the spectrum itself, and does not depend on a color scale 
    to determine the characteristic frequencies. This should reduce 
    systematic error and lead to more accurate results.
    
  Data Coverage
  =============
    This data set does not provide complete coverage of the time
    intervals when Voyager 2 was within Jupiter&apos;s magnetosphere.  Two 
    criteria were necessary in order for density measurements to be 
    obtained.  First, wideband waveform data must exist.  These data are
    waveforms sampled at 4-bit resolution and have a frequency range 
    from 40 Hz to 12 kHz.  1600 samples are collected for 55.56-msec 
    at a rate of 28,800 samples per second, and are then followed by a 
    4.44-msec gap.  These 60-msec intervals make up one line of 
    waveform samples.  The spectrograms then consist of 48-second 
    &apos;frames&apos;, consisting of up to 800 lines or 48 seconds each.  Because
    these data compete with Voyager imaging data for the downlink 
    resource, data is available only a fraction of the time.  Plasma 
    wave spectra data can be either continuous, periodic (such as one 
    48-second frame out of every four such frames), or simply present 
    sporadically.  Second, spectral features which exhibit a c</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-J-PWS-5-DDR-PLASMA-DENSITY-1S-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-J-PWS-5-DDR-PLASMA-DENSITY-1S-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-J-PWS-5-DDR-PLASMA-DENSITY-1S-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-J-PWS-5-DDR-PLASMA-DENSITY-1S-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1979-07-04T23:44:47.50</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1979-07-11T23:58:22.50</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT1S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
