<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_2.xsd">
<Version>2.3.2</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/NumericalData/Magnetometer/Clg_Magnetometer</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Australian Space Weather Services Culgoora Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-03-29T17:14:50Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
	  The magnetometer data provides a measure of variations of the Earth's magnetic field in 2 or 3 orthogonal directions, typically in the geomagnetic north-south and east-west directions as well as vertically. Space Weather Services archives digital magnetometer data recorded from a number of field installations, some of which are collaborative installations with other organizations. Magnetometer data is used to derive a number of indices relevant to specific industry groups as well drive space weather warnings and alerts. Magnetometer data and its derived products are also used in Space Weather Services reports and products as well for space weather forecasting and geomagnetic storm monitoring. A geomagnetic storm is a temporary disturbance of the Earth's magnetosphere caused by its interaction with transient features of the solar wind. Geomagnetic storms may be hazardous to critical infrastructure such as power networks and long pipelines as well as interfere with mineral exploration surveys and directional drilling. Geomagnetic storms also modulate hazardous environments for satellites and lead to ionospheric disturbances that cause degraded HF radio communications, radar scintillation, and compromise GNSS precision navigation systems. Geomagnetic data is used to derive products that are used in Space Weather Services' reports and alerts primarily in the form of geomagnetic indices. The Fluxgate Magnetometer in Culgoora is owned and operated by Bom since 18/09/2003. In 05/04/2007, an ICSWSE magnetometer was installed at Culgoora. Its data is only available in SWS WDC Intranet. Culgoora station was stopped since 29/08/2019 due to power outage.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>We are thankful to the Space Weather Network of the Bureau of Meteorology, Australia for the observations of Culgoora Magnetometer data.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact> 
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Documentation</Name>
        <URL>https://www.sws.bom.gov.au/World_Data_Centre/2/3/</URL>
        <Description>includes descriptions of station logfiles, data formats and examples and hardware</Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/SWS</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Offline</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights> 
	<AccessURL>
        <Name>Real Time Information</Name>
        <URL>https://www.sws.bom.gov.au/Geophysical</URL>
	<Style>Overview</Style>	
        <Description>Online viewer of real time magnetograms data, indices, maps, alerts and warnings, and reports and forecasts. Culgoora stopped since 29/08/2019 due to power outage.</Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>GIF</Format>
      <Encoding>None</Encoding>
    </AccessInformation>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/SWS</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>     
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>World Data Centre: Data Display and Download: Magnetometer</Name>
        <URL>https://www.sws.bom.gov.au/World_Data_Centre/1/2</URL>
	<Style>Search</Style>	
        <Description>includes browse display interface, button to get daily data file and link to data availability chart</Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>FTP access to raw magnetometer data (not with most browsers)</Name>
        <URL>ftp://ftp-out.sws.bom.gov.au/wdc/wdc_mag/data/clg/</URL>
	<Style>Listing</Style>	
        <Description>FTP access to the station log file and raw magetometer data of Culgoora </Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text</Format>
      <Encoding>GZIP</Encoding>
    </AccessInformation>
	<ProviderProcessingLevel>The original magnetometer data are raw data and are uncalibrated.</ProviderProcessingLevel>  
    <InstrumentID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Culgoora/Magnetometer</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2003-09-18T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <RelativeStopDate>-P1D</RelativeStopDate>
        <Note>The earliest magnetometer data since 18/09/2003. Digital magnetometer data are current to within a day.</Note>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
	<ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <!-- Keywords pertaining to the data presentation -->
    <Keyword>Magnetometer</Keyword>
    <Keyword>Geomagnetic Storm</Keyword>
    <Keyword>Magnetosphere</Keyword>
    <Keyword>Earth's Magnetic Field</Keyword>
    <!-- Keywords pertaining to the physical phenomena appearing in magnetometer --> 
    <Parameter>
      <Name>h</Name>
      <Description>Represents the magnetic field strength in roughly the direction of the north magnetic pole. A positive x-value means that part of the magnetic field is pointing north. A negative x-value means that part of the magnetic field is pointing south.</Description>
      <Cadence>PT1S</Cadence>
      <Units>nT</Units>
	  <Field>
	    <FieldQuantity>Magnetic</FieldQuantity>
	  </Field>
	</Parameter>
    <Parameter>
	  <Name>d</Name>
      <Description>Represents the magnetic field strength 90 degrees from the x-direction in the “magnetic east” direction. A positive y-value means that part of the magnetic field is pointing towards magnetic east. A negative y-value means that part of the magnetic field is pointing towards magnetic west.</Description>
      <Cadence>PT1S</Cadence>
      <Units>nT</Units>
	  <Field>
	    <FieldQuantity>Magnetic</FieldQuantity>
	  </Field>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
	  <Name>z</Name>
      <Description>represents the magnetic field strength in the local nadir direction (vertically down).</Description>
      <Cadence>PT1S</Cadence>
      <Units>nT</Units>
	  <Field>
	    <FieldQuantity>Magnetic</FieldQuantity>
	  </Field>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
