<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd" lang="en">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/Galileo</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Galileo</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Galileo Orbiter</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2016-09-27T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Galileo mission consists of two spacecraft: an orbiter and an atmospheric probe.
The orbiter is the sixth spacecraft to explore the Jovian magnetosphere, but the first to be placed into orbit around the giant planet.
Scientific objectives addressed by the orbiter are to:
* investigate the circulation and dynamics of the Jovian atmosphere;
* investigate the upper Jovian atmosphere and ionosphere;
* characterize the morphology, geology, and physical state of the Galilean satellites;
* investigate the composition and distribution of surface minerals on the Galilean satellites;
* determine the gravitational and magnetic fields and dynamic properties of the Galilean satellites;
* study the atmospheres, ionospheres, and extended gas clouds of the Galilean satellites;
* study the interaction of the Jovian magnetosphere with the Galilean satellites;
* characterize the vector magnetic field and the energy spectra, composition, and angular distribution of energetic particles and plasma to a distance of 150 Rj.

Venus flyby: Feb. 10, 1990, at altitude of 16,000 km

Earth flybys: Dec. 8, 1990, at altitude of 960 km; Dec. 8, 1992 at altitude of 303 km

Asteroid Gaspra flyby: Oct. 29, 1991, at 1,601 km

Comet Shoemaker-Levy 9: Impacts of comet fragments into Jupiter observed while en route in July 1994

Asteroid Ida flyby: Aug. 28, 1993, at 2.4.1 km 

Number of Jupiter orbits during entire mission: 34

Number of flybys of Jupiter moons: Io 7, Callisto 8, Ganymede 8, Europa 11, Amalthea 1
        </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Torrence.V.Johnson</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraftDisplay.do?id=1989-084B</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Galileo Orbiter mission</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location> 
      <ObservatoryRegion>Jupiter</ObservatoryRegion>   
      <ObservatoryRegion>Asteroid</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
    <OperatingSpan> 
      <StartDate>1989-10-18T12:00:00</StartDate>
       <StopDate>2003-09-21T12:00:00</StopDate>
      <Note>Jupiter arrival : 1995-12-07</Note>  
    </OperatingSpan>  
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
