<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.7.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <MetadataRightsList>
    <Rights>
      <SchemeURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/</SchemeURI>
      <RightsIdentifierScheme>SPDX</RightsIdentifierScheme>
      <RightsIdentifier>CC0-1.0</RightsIdentifier>
      <RightsURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC0-1.0.html</RightsURI>
      <RightsName>Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal</RightsName>
      <Note>CC0 1.0 Universal is the Creative Commons license applicable to all publicly available SPASE metadata descriptions</Note>
    </Rights>
  </MetadataRightsList>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sect1/PT64S</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>NASA</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>NumericalData</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ulysses Cosmic Ray and Solar Particle Investigation (COSPIN) High Energy Telescope (HET) Full Resolution Electron Counts and Accumulation Times for Eight-Sectored Coincidence Counting Rates, SECT1 H7S, 64 s Data</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:32:09Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:15:40Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-11-14T16:03:04Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added PublicationInfo. Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Changed http to https in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Fixed version number separator in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Matched version number in schemaLocation attribute to updated value in Version tag. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:32:09Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added MetadataRightsList. Updated to 2.7.1. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>A Directory containing Daily FTP downloadable Files containing Readout-by-Readout Listings of the Counts accumulated in each Spin Sector of the Eight-Sectored H7S Counting Rate. Aside from its Division of Counts into Spin Sectors, H7S is a Coincidence Counting Rate with Coincidence Logic Requirements identical to the Spin-Averaged Counting Rate H7. Therefore both the H7 and the H7S Counting Rates respond primarily to Electrons in the very approximate Energy Range from about 5-10 MeV. The Naming Convention for the Daily Files is uly_het_full_rat_sect1_YYYDDD.txt, where YYY indicates the three digit Year since 1900 (e.g. YYY=090 for 1990, and YYY=102 for 2002) and DDD indicates the three digit Day of Year (January 1 = 1). In each File, following a detailed Description of the Format, the Data consist of a Readout by Readout Listing of Counts accumulated in the eight 45° Spin Sectors of the Sectored Counting Rate H7S during the Intervals between successive Readouts, organized into Columns as described below. The first four Columns give the Start Time of the Counting Rate Accumulation Period for Sector 7 of the Rate as Fractional Year (to 12 Decimal Places) and as Year since 1900, Day of Year, and Milliseconds of Day at the Start of the Accumulation, followed by one Column (labeled cov) giving the Duration of the total Accumulation Period for all eight Sectors in Milliseconds. Thus the Accumulation Period in each of the Sectors is the Value given in the "cov" Column divided by eight. The Accumulation in each of the successive Sectors 7,8,1,2,3,4,5, and 6 starts cov/8 Milliseconds after the Start of the Accumulation in the previous Sector. Columns 6-13 then give the Counts accumulated in each of the eight Sectors during the Accumulation Period. Each Line contains Data for one single Readout Accumulation of the eight Sectors of H7S. Since the Accumulation Period for each Readout is forced to include an Integral Number of Spacecraft Spins in order to produce equal Coverage in all Sectors, the Lengths of the Accumulation Periods vary in a Cyclic Manner as the Period of the Telemetry Cycle beats with the Spacecraft Spin Period. The H7S Counting Rate is fully read out every 64 s at the most common Science Telemetry Bit Rate (2048 bps). Thus, with a typical 5 rpm Spacecraft Spin Rate the Accumulation Intervals vary in a repeating Cycle of 60, 60, 72, 60, 60, 72, 60, etc., seconds. At lower Bit Rates the Average Interval is equal to 64 times (2048/BR) seconds and the Cycle automatically adjusts to produce this Average Accumulation. The Spin Plane of the Ulysses Spacecraft, in which the Sectors are defined, is normal to the Spin Axis (Spacecraft +Z Axis), which is maintained within one to 2° of Earth pointing at all Times. Viewed from Earth the Spacecraft spins Counter Clockwise. The Start of Sector 1 is defined by the Spacecraft Generated Sun Pulse, which is issued when the Sun crosses the +X/+Z Quadrant of the X/Z Plane. The HET Telescope Axis is parallel to the +X Axis and normal to the Z Axis. No Noise Removal or Despiking has been done, so Caution must be used in interpreting isolated large Increases or Decreases in the Counting Rates.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the COSPIN HET Lead Investigator and COSPIN PI, R. Bruce McKibben</Acknowledgement>
      <PublicationInfo>
        <Authors>McKibben, R. B.; Connell, James</Authors>
        <PublicationDate>2025-11-14T16:03:04Z</PublicationDate>
        <PublishedBy>Planetary Data System; Space Physics Data Facility; European Space Astronomy Centre</PublishedBy>
      </PublicationInfo>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.Bruce.McKibben</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
        <Role>TeamLeader</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Clifford.Lopate</PersonID>
        <Role>DataProducer</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.Connell</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>The Ulysses Cosmic Ray and Solar Particle Investigation, COSPIN</Name>
        <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments</URL>
        <Description>Published Description of the COSPIN Instrumentation, J.A. Simpson et al., Astron. Astrophys. Suppl. Ser. 92, 365-399, 1992. See especially Section 4.3 for a detailed Description of the High Energy Telescopes, HET. An electronic Copy of this Paper is available at http://adsbit.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-iarticle_query?1992A%26AS...92..365S&amp;defaultprint=YES&amp;filetype=.pdf.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>User Notes for the COSPIN/HET Data Files</Name>
        <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa-sl-server/data-action?PROTOCOL=HTTP&amp;PRODUCT_TYPE=ALL&amp;FILE_NAME=het_usernotes.pdf&amp;FILE_PATH=/ufa/HiRes/doc/cospin</URL>
        <Description>The User Notes File at the Ulysses Final Archive (UFA) describes the Format of the ASCII Data Files for the COSPIN High Energy Telescope, HET</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>COSPIN HET Full Resolution ReadMe Document, Word Format</Name>
        <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa-sl-server/data-action?PROTOCOL=HTTP&amp;PRODUCT_TYPE=ALL&amp;FILE_NAME=ReadMeHETFullRes.doc&amp;FILE_PATH=/ufa/HiRes/COSPIN/HET</URL>
        <Description>Top Level Descriptions of Formats and Contents of the six File Types that make up the COSPIN HET Full Resolution Data Set. Detailed Descriptions of the Formats and Contents are found in Header Lines at the Start of each downloaded Data File. The Data covered by this SPASE Description are described in the ReadMe under the Heading sect1. (*** Note ***: During the Build-up of this Data Set, a few Errors and Omissions have been found in the Header Lines for some of the File Types. These Errors and Omissions are listed in this ReadMe File. Upon Completion of the Data Set, all Errors and Omissions discovered will be corrected in all of the Header Lines of all of the File Types at which time this Note will be removed).</Description>
      </InformationURL>
      <Association>
        <AssociationID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Omni1/PT12S</AssociationID>
        <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
      </Association>
      <Association>
        <AssociationID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Omni2/PT128S</AssociationID>
        <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
      </Association>
      <Association>
        <AssociationID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sect2/PT128S</AssociationID>
        <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
      </Association>
      <PriorID>spase://VEPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/FullResolution/Rates/Sect1</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sect1/PT64S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/ESA/ESAC/UlyssesFinalArchive</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>Ulysses Final Archive Access to COSPIN/HET Full Resolution Electron Counts and Accumulation Times for Eight-Sectored Coincidence Counting Rates, SECT1 H7S</Name>
        <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#data</URL>
        <Description>Parent Directory containing FTP downloadable Daily Files with the Format described below</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text</Format>
      <Encoding>ASCII</Encoding>
      <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge R. Bruce McKibben, Space Science Center, University of New Hampshire</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1990-10-22T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2009-06-29T23:59:59.999</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Interval Start Time</Name>
      <Description>Nominal Start Time for the accumulation of counts in Sector 7, given in decimal year, integer year, Day of Year, and Milliseconds of Day.</Description>
      <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
      <Structure>
        <Size>4</Size>
        <Element>
          <Name>Decimal Year</Name>
          <Index>1</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_1</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>0.00000000000</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>Year</Name>
          <Index>2</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_2</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>0</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>Day of Year</Name>
          <Index>3</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_3</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>1</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>366</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>0</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>Milliseconds of Day</Name>
          <Index>4</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_4</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>86400000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>0</FillValue>
        </Element>
      </Structure>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Accumulation period</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Column_5</ParameterKey>
      <Description>Length of the summed accumulation periods for all 8 sectors in milli-seconds. This represents an integral number of spacecraft spin periods, most commonly 5 or 6 for H7s at 2048 bps.</Description>
      <Caveats>None</Caveats>
      <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
      <Units>millisecond</Units>
      <ValidMin>50000</ValidMin>
      <ValidMax>550000</ValidMax>
      <FillValue>0</FillValue>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>COSPIN/HET Eight-Sectored Counting Rate H7S</Name>
      <Description>Counts accumulated in each of the 8 sectors of counting rate H7S during the accumulation period starting at the time given in columns 1-4 and with a duration as given in column 5. Each sector contains counts incident from a specific 45° sector of the spin plane. The start of sector 1 (0°) is coincident with the spacecraft-generated Sun-pulse, and the start of each subsequent sector is shifted by 45° with respect to the preceding sector. For example, H7S1 covers the azimuthal range 0° to 45°, H7S2 covers the azimuthal range 45° to 90°, etc. In each sector, counts are registered only when the Axis of the Telescope view cone is within that sector.</Description>
      <Caveats>Because the orbit of the spacecraft about the Sun lies in a plane inclined 80° to the heliographic equator, and because the spacecraft spin Axis (and thus the Axis of the high gain antenna) be pointed at Earth within 2° at all times, determination of the direction in space corresponding to the start of sector 1 can be complex.</Caveats>
      <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
      <Structure>
        <Size>8</Size>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S1</Name>
          <Index>1</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_6</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S2</Name>
          <Index>2</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_7</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S3</Name>
          <Index>3</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_8</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S4</Name>
          <Index>4</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_9</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S5</Name>
          <Index>5</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_10</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S6</Name>
          <Index>6</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_11</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S7</Name>
          <Index>7</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_12</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Name>H7S8</Name>
          <Index>8</Index>
          <ParameterKey>Column_13</ParameterKey>
          <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
          <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
          <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
        </Element>
      </Structure>
      <Particle>
        <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
        <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
        <EnergyRange>
          <Low>5</Low>
          <High>10</High>
          <Units>MeV</Units>
        </EnergyRange>
      </Particle>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
