<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/RSS/Saturn/PT0.00001S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Saturn Radio Occultation Raw data V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                 
                                                                      
    Data Set Overview                                                 
    ================                                                  
      This data set consists of raw data collected during the Saturn  
      radio occultation of Voyager 2 on 26 August 1981, ring          
      scattering data collected during the same time period, test     
      and calibration data collected about 8 hours earlier, and       
      ancillary files that might be useful in analysis of those data. 
      The raw data are sampled voltage outputs from receivers tuned to
      the Voyager carrier frequencies at both S-band and X-band during
      the occultation.  The data have been reduced to give profiles   
      of temperature and pressure as a function of height in the      
      atmosphere [LINDALETAL1985] and to infer magnetic field         
      orientations in the upper ionosphere [HINSON1984].              
                                                                      
      During the Saturn occultation, the Voyager 2 spacecraft         
      provided a coherent, dual-frequency microwave radio signal      
      source.  The signal frequency was derived from a precision,     
      onboard Ultra-Stable Oscillator (USO).  The spacecraft          
      high-gain antenna (HGA) beamed that signal through the          
      atmosphere and rings of Saturn.  As the spacecraft moved on     
      its trajectory, the radio signal probed the atmosphere and      
      rings at different radial positions from the center of mass.    
      An hour later the signals were received using a 64-meter        
      antenna of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) near Canberra      
      (Australia).                                                    
                                                                      
      To keep the refracted radio beam aimed toward the DSN antenna   
      during the atmospheric occultation, the spacecraft attitude     
      was adjusted so that the high-gain antenna (HGA) was pointed    
      at the virtual image of Earth on Saturn&apos;s limb.  This ensured   
      that maximum signal strength would be available from the        
      deepest probing.  During the deepest part of the atmospheric    
      occultation, the HGA was pointed toward the rings to determine  
      whether signals forward scattered by the ring particles could   
      be detected on Earth.                                           
                                                                      
      Related data sets of possible interest include:                 
                                                                      
                DATA_SET_ID                Description                
         -----------------------  --------------------------------    
         VG1-SSA-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0  Titan radio occultation raw data    
         VG1-S-RSS-1-REDR-V1.0*   Saturn Voyager 1 ingress radio      
                                     occultation raw data             
         VG1-S-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0    Saturn Voyager 1 egress radio       
                                     occultation and ring             
                                     scattering raw data              
               *tentative DATA_SET_ID assignment                      
                                                                      
                                                                      
    Parameters                                                        
    ==========                                                        
      The output of each S-band receiver was a sinusoidal carrier     
      signal embedded in noise -- a voltage with bandwidth            
      approximately 50 kHz and sampled at 300000 samples per second.  
      The X-band receiver output was similar; but, because of greater 
      potential for Doppler drift and prediction uncertainty, its     
      bandwidth was 150 kHz and sampling rate was 300000 samples per  
      second.  Voltages typically were in the range +/- 10 volts;     
      but the absolute levels were not calibrated.  In fact, they     
      are generally not needed since it is the frequency (or phase)   
      of the signal (rather than amplitude) that is most useful in    
      inferring properties of a neutral atmosphere or ionosphere,     
      and amplitude calibration for ring observations can be          
      obtained by referencing signals to the background radiothermal  
      noise in the data stream.                                       
                                                                      
      The frequency of the USO was known from monitoring during the   
      Jupiter-Saturn cruise (and from post-Saturn observations).      
      Doppler contributions from motions of the spacecraft, Earth,    
      Saturn, and other bodies of the solar system were determined    
      jointly with the Voyager Navigation Team.  Relativistic         
      Doppler contributions could be estimated from proximity to      
      large masses.  Receiver tuning was recorded in POCA             
      (Programmable Oscillator Control Assembly) files, which are     
      included with this archive.                                     
                                                                      
                                                                      
    Processing                                                        
    ==========                                                        
      No processing per se has been carried out on these data.        
      However, because of the high sampling rate, the 8-bit samples   
      were recorded originally on wide-bandwidth analog video tape.   
      The analog tapes were then replayed later at slower speeds and  
      the digital data were extracted onto computer compatible tapes  
      (CCTs) with each receiver channel on a separate set of tapes.   
      Because the S-band data had been oversampled originally         
      (300 ksps for a 50 kHz bandwidth), only one of every three      
      samples was saved during the transfer of S-band data to CCTs.   
      This process, known as &apos;decimation&apos;, meant that 300 seconds     
      of data could be stored on an S-band CCT whereas only           
      100 seconds of X-band data would fit.                           
                                                                      
      Because analog recording technology was required to save the    
      high data rate digital samples, there are occasional dropouts   
      in the sample stream.  These can be detected by paying special  
      attention to counter fields in data record headers.             
                                                                      
      Two analog recorders (A and B) were available at each DSN       
      complex.   Because a single recorder could not capture the      
      entire set of Saturn occultation activities, the two were run   
      in parallel with staggered start/stop times.  Most data were    
      collected using Recorder A; but Recorder B was used to          
      capture the samples while Recorder A was being reloaded.        
                                                                      
                                                                      
    Data                                                              
    ====                                                              
      Primary data were delivered to Voyager Radio Science Team       
      members in the form of 30 megabyte (MB) CCTs covering           
      300 s (S-band) or 100 s (X-band).  Each tape had  6000          
      records of 5056 bytes (56 bytes of header information           
      and 5000 8-bit samples of receiver output voltage).  Tapes      
      were numbered s</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-S-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-S-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-S-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-S-RSS-1-ROCC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/RSS</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Active</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1981-08-25T20:11:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1981-08-26T08:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT0.00001S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Saturn</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
