<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.3.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://ESA/NumericalData/Cluster-Salsa/FGM/CSA/PT0.045S</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cluster-Salsa Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) Data at the ESA Cluster Science Archive</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Cluster 2 Salsa Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) Data at CAA</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) data products from the Cluster II Salsa spacecraft consist of magnetic field measurements of the Earth's magnetosphere from a few tens of nT in the outer magnetosphere to over 1,000nT at closest approach.  Products are provided at three different time resolutions: full resolution, 5 vectors/second resolution and spin resolution.  Each calibration file is valid for the period of one orbit defined from perigee to perigee.  The full-resolution magnetic field data has no time averaging applied.  If the instrument is in normal mode, the data is at approximately 22 Hz resolution.  If it is in burst mode, the data is at approximately 67 Hz resolution.  The second product is averaged to a time resolution of 5 vectors per second.  The third product is averaged over one spacecraft spin where the spin phase for averaging is the same as that used for the Prime Parameter data.  Each of the three primary data products contain the following: time, magnetic field vector, magnetic field magnitude, spacecraft position, instrument range, and telementary mode.  The magnetic field components and the spacecraft position are in the GSE coordinate system.  In addition to the three primary products, there are five support data products: caveats, calibration field accuracy, calibration files, data missing from processed data set, and data removed by validation process.  Caveat files are produced when the calibration is known to be changing on short timescales near eclipses and for other events when visible effects have been observed in the data.  Calibration accuracy files contain detailed information on the accuracy of the magnetic field data products and can be used to select periods of data.  Calibration files contain the nine elements of the 3x3 calibration matrix and the three offsets for each instrument range. Each file is valid for the period of one orbit for which magnetic field data products have been submitted to the Cluster Active Archive. Data gaps are listed for times at the processing stage when no data were taken, or at the data validation stage where invalid data have been removed.  For more details, see "The Cluster Active Archive: Studying the Earth's Space Plasma Environment", edited by Dr. Harri Laakso, Matthew G. T. T. Taylor, C. Philippe Escoubet, from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Andre Balogh and the Cluster Active Archive</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andre.Balogh</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Melvyn.L.Goldstein</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog listing for Cluster II Salsa Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM)</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041B-04</URL>
        <Description>This site provides information concerning the Cluster II Salsa Fluxgate Magnetometer Instrument.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Cluster Science Archive (CSA) Documentation</Name>
        <URL>https://www.cosmos.esa.int/?project=CLUSTER&amp;page=caa_documentation</URL>
        <Description>CAA Instrument User Guides, Calibration Reports and ICDS.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <Association>
        <AssociationID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Salsa</AssociationID>
        <AssociationType>ObservedBy</AssociationType>
</Association>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Cluster-Salsa/FGM/CSA/PT0.045S</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/CSA</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>Access to files at the Cluster Science Archive (CSA)</Name>
        <URL>https://www.cosmos.esa.int/</URL>
        <Description>Cluster II Salsa Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) data</Description>
</AccessURL>
      <Format>CEF</Format>
</AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Salsa/FGM</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2001-01-30T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
        <RelativeStopDate>-P3M</RelativeStopDate>
</TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT0.045S</Cadence>
</TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.RadiationBelt</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.AuroralRegion</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Plasmasphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.PolarCap</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <Caveats>Data from the extended mission from 2006-01-01 are not validated; use with caution. Spikes and other artifacts that were previously removed during validation of the primary parameters and summary parameters may occur in these files.</Caveats>
</NumericalData>
</Spase>
