<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_1.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.1</Version>
    <NumericalData>
        <ResourceID>spase://VEPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/FullResolution/Rates/Omni1</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Ulysses COSPIN/HET readout by readout counts and accumulation times for spin-averaged counting rates H1-H9</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2009-09-24T00:00:00.000</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>
           A directory containing daily ftp-downloadable files containing readout-by-readout listings of 
           the counts accumulated in the H1-H9 spin-averaged counting rates. These counting rates respond 
           primarily to protons (H1-H5, H9) in the approximate energy ranges 5.4-14, 14-19, 24-31, 34-68,
           68-92, and &gt;92 MeV, respectively, and to electrons (H6-8) in the very approximate energy ranges 
           1-3, 5-10, and 3-5 MeV, respectively.
           The naming convention for the daily files is uly_het_full_rat_omni1_YYYDDD.txt, where YYY 
           indicates the three-digit year since 1900 (e.g. YYY=090 for 1990, and YYY=102 for 2002) and 
           DDD indicates the three digit day of year (Jan. 1 = 1).
           In each file, following a detailed description of the format, the data consist of a
           listing of counts accumulated in the H1-H9 spin-averaged counting  rates during the intervals 
           between successive readouts, organized into columns as described below.
           The first 4 columns give the start time of the counting rate accumulation period as
           fractional year (to 12 decimal places) and as  year since 1900, day of year, and ms
           of day at the start of the accumulation, followed by 1 column giving the duration of
           the accumulation period in milli-seconds (it is the same for all 9 rates), and 9
           columns giving the counts accumulated in that period for each rate.  All fields
           except for the fractional year are in integer format.
           Each line contains data for one single readout of the rates H1-H9, and all readouts
           where at least one of the rates has a non-fill value are included.  Where fill
           does occur it is indicated by -1.
           Since the accumulation period for each readout is forced to include an integral number
           of spacecraft spins in order to produce pure spin-averaged measurements, the lengths of
           the accumulation periods vary in a cyclic manner as the period of the telemetry cycle
           beats with the spacecraft spin period.  All counting rates in this file are read out
           twice per spacecraft format.  At the most common science telemetry bit rate (2048 bps)
           this corresponds to an average interval between readouts of 16 seconds.  Thus, with a
           typical 5 rpm spacecraft spin rate the accumulation intervals vary in a repeating cycle of
           12, 12, 24, 12, 12, 24, 12, etc. seconds.  At lower bit rates the average interval is
           equal to 16x(2048/BR) seconds and the cycle automatically adjusts to produce this average
           accumulation.
           No noise-removal or despiking has been done, so caution must be used in interpreting isolated 
           large increases or decreases in the counting rates.
       </Description>
            <Acknowledgement>
         Please acknowledge the Lead HET Investigator and COSPIN P.I., Dr. R. Bruce McKibben
       </Acknowledgement>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.Bruce.McKibben</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
                <Role>TeamLeader</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Clifford.Lopate</PersonID>
                <Role>DataProducer</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.Connell</PersonID>
                <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>
           The Ulysses cosmic ray and solar particle investigation
         </Name>
                <URL>
          http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments
         </URL>
                <Description>
           Published (J.A. Simpson et al., Astron. Astrophys. v92, pp365-399, 1992) description 
           of the COSPIN Instrumentation.  See especially section 4.3 for a detailed description 
           of the HET.
         </Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>
           COSPIN/HET User Notes
         </Name>
                <URL>
               http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments
         </URL>
                <Description>
           Identification of data channels archived and brief discussion of data structure
         </Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>
           ReadMeHETFullRes.doc
         </Name>
                <URL>
           http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments
         </URL>
                <Description>
           Top Level descriptions of formats and contents of the six file types that make up the
           COSPIN HET Full Resolution Data Set. Detailed descriptions of the formats and contents
           are to found in header lines at the start of each downloaded data file.  The data 
           covered by this spase description are described in the ReadMe under the heading
           rat_omni1.
           (*** Note ***:  During the build-up of this data set, a few errors and omissions have been 
           found in the header lines for some of the file types.  These errors and omissions are listed 
           in this ReadMe file.  Upon completion of the data set, all errors and omissions discovered
           will be corrected in all of the header lines of all of the file types and this note will be 
           removed.)
         </Description>
            </InformationURL>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <AccessInformation>
            <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/ESA/ESAC/UlyssesFinalArchive</RepositoryID>
            <Availability>Online</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>Ulysses COSPIN/HET Full Resolution Spin-Average (Omni1) Counting Rate Data</Name>
                <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#data</URL>
                <Description>
           Parent directory containing daily downloadable files with the format described below
         </Description>
            </AccessURL>
            <Format>Text</Format>
            <Encoding>ASCII</Encoding>
            <Acknowledgement>R.B. McKibben, Space Science Center, University of New Hampshire</Acknowledgement>
        </AccessInformation>
        <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET</InstrumentID>
        <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>1990-10-22T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
                <StopDate>2009-06-29T23:59:59.000</StopDate>
            </TimeSpan>
        </TemporalDescription>
        <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>Interval Start Time</Name>
            <Description>
          Nominal Start Time for the average given in decimal year, 
          integer year, day of year, and milli-secnds of day.
       </Description>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <Structure>
                <Size>4</Size>
                <Element>
                    <Name>Decimal Year</Name>
                    <Index>1</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_1</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0.00000000000</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>year</Name>
                    <Index>2</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_2</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>day</Name>
                    <Index>3</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_3</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>1</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>366</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>msec</Name>
                    <Index>4</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_4</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>86400000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0</FillValue>
                </Element>
            </Structure>
            <Support>
                <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
            </Support>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>Accumulation period</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_5</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Length of the accumulation period in milli-seconds.  
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
          None
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <Units>milliseconds</Units>
            <ValidMin>10000</ValidMin>
            <ValidMax>150000</ValidMax>
            <FillValue>0</FillValue>
            <Support>
                <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
            </Support>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H01</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_6</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H1 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H1 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          protons in the energy interval 5.4-14 MeV (normal incidence).
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Heavier nuclei with similar penetrating power to 5.4-14 MeV protons also produce counts 
           in H1.  However the intensities of such heavier nuclei are usually much lower than the proton
           intensity.  The most significant contributor to such contamination is usually helium.  
           During quiet times the H1 counting rates is dominated by background counts induced by gamma
           rays from the RTG.
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>5.4</Low>
                    <High>14</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H02</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_7</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H2 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H2 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          protons in the energy interval 14-19 MeV (normal incidence). 
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Heavier nuclei with similar penetrating power to 14-19 MeV protons also produce counts 
           in H2.  However the intensities of such heavier nuclei are usually much lower than the proton
           intensity.  The most significant contributor to such contamination is usually helium.
           Use of higher level discriminators on the triggered detectors (D1 and D2) discriminates strongly
           against electrons, and thus also against RTG-induced background.
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>14</Low>
                    <High>19</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H03</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_8</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H3 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H3 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          protons in the energy interval 24-31 MeV (normal incidence). 
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Heavier nuclei with similar penetrating power to 24-31 MeV protons also produce counts 
           in H3.  However the intensities of such heavier nuclei are usually much lower than the proton
           intensity.  The most significant contributor to such contamination is usually helium.  Electrons
           produced by the RTG gammas are excluded by the coincidence requirement, which requires greater 
           range for electrons than that of the maximum energy electrons that RTG gammas can produce.  
           However higher energy electrons of cosmic ray, solar, magnetospheric or other natural origin 
           may in some circumstances make significant contributions to the counting rate.
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>24</Low>
                    <High>31</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H04</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_9</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H4 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H4 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          protons in the energy interval 34-68 MeV (normal incidence). 
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Heavier nuclei with similar penetrating power to 34-68 MeV protons also produce counts 
           in H4.  However the intensities of such heavier nuclei are usually much lower than the proton
           intensity.  The most significant contributor to such contamination is usually helium.  Electrons
           produced by the RTG gammas are excluded by the coincidence requirement, which requires greater 
           range for electrons than that of the maximum energy electrons that RTG gammas can produce.  
           However higher energy electrons of cosmic ray, solar, magnetospheric or other natural origin 
           may in some circumstances make significant contributions to the counting rate.
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>34</Low>
                    <High>68</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H05</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_10</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H5 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H5 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          protons in the energy interval 68-92 MeV (normal incidence). 
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Heavier nuclei with similar penetrating power to 68-92 MeV protons also produce counts 
           in H5.  However the intensities of such heavier nuclei are usually much lower than the proton
           intensity.  The most significant contributor to such contamination is usually helium.  Electrons
           produced by the RTG gammas are excluded by the coincidence requirement, which requires greater 
           range for electrons than that of the maximum energy electrons that RTG gammas can produce.  
           However higher energy electrons of cosmic ray, solar, magnetospheric or other natural origin 
           may in some circumstances make significant contributions to the counting rate.
           During In-Flight-Calibrate (IFC) sequences, two ramps of pulse are fed to the detector 
           amplifiers over several hours.  For part of each sequence, the pulses satisfy the H5 counting
           rate logic.  The H5 counting rate responds to those pulses that are so small that they do not 
           trigger the high level discriminators on the detectors.  This leads to two small spikes separated 
           by several hours (depending on bit rate) in the H5 counting rate.  A clear example of this effect 
           (and of the corresponding effect on H12, which counts the larger pulses) can be found on day 31 
           of 1991.  
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>68</Low>
                    <High>92</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H06</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_11</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H6 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H6 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          electrons in the energy interval ~1-3 MeV (normal incidence). This counting rate 
          discriminates strongly against nuclei by requiring anticoincidence with a discriminator
          set slightly slightly above the energy deposited by minimum ionizing particles in D1, but 
          below the minimum energy deposited by a proton stopping in D2. 
        </Description>
            <Caveats>
	   Because of scattering of the electons in the telescope, the energy range given is very 
           approximate.
           During quiet times, the H6 counting rate is dominated by electrons produced by RTG gamma rays 
           in the telescope. 
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>1</Low>
                    <High>3</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H07</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_12</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H7 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H7 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          electrons in the energy interval ~5-10 MeV (normal incidence). This counting rate 
          discriminates strongly against nuclei by requiring anti-coincidence with discriminators 
          set above the energy deposited by minimum ionizing particles, but below the minimum energy 
          deposited by a proton stopping in the telescope.  
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Because of scattering during propagation of the electons in the telescope, the energy 
           range given is very approximate.
           The coincidence logic for H7 requires a greater penetration depth in the telescope than is
           possible for electrons produced by RTG gamma rays, so no background is induced in this
           counting rate by the presence of the RTG. 
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>5</Low>
                    <High>10</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H08</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_13</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H8 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H8 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          electrons in the energy interval ~3-5 MeV (normal incidence). This counting rate 
          discriminates strongly against nuclei by requiring anti-coincidence with discriminators 
          set above the energy deposited by minimum ionizing particles, but below the minimum energy 
          deposited by a proton stopping in the telescope.  
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
	   Because of scattering during propagation of the electons in the telescope, the energy range 
           given is very approximate.
           The coincidence logic for H8 requires a greater penetration depth in the telescope than is
           possible for electrons produced by RTG gamma rays, so no background is induced in this
           counting rate by the presence of the RTG. 
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>3</Low>
                    <High>5</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET H09</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_14</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
          Counts accumulated by counting rate H9 during the period of coverage (column 5) starting
          at the time defined in columns 1-4.  The H9 counting rate normally responds primarily to 
          protons with energies greater than ~92 MeV, which completely penetrate the telescope
          detector stack.  Thus it provides a measure of the integral intensity of energetic charged
          particles with penetrating power equal or greater to that of 92 MeV protons.  
       </Description>
            <Caveats>
           Because of proximity of the low-level discriminators on several of the detectors to the
           expected energy deposits by minimum ionizing protons, the efficiency of detection decreases
           somewhat for minimum ionizing particles.  Because of the dependence of the detector noise
           on temperature, the decrease in efficiency depends to some extent on the telescope 
           temperature.  
           Since the particles that trigger H9 completely penetrate the telescope, both forward and 
           backward-going particles are counted.  Backward-going particles must also penetrate the
           spacecraft structure and instruments behind the HET before entering the telescope, so 
           the energy threshold for backward-going particles is very poorly known.  Thus this 
           counting rate is more suitable for study of relative variations in the particle intensity 
           than for derivation of an accurate integral flux.  
       </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
            <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>92</Low>
                    <High>1.0E+14</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
    </NumericalData>
</Spase>