<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_1.xsd">
    <Version>2.2.1</Version>
    <NumericalData>
        <ResourceID>spase://VEPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/FullResolution/Rates/Sect1</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Ulysses COSPIN/HET readout by readout counts and accumulation times for the 8-sectored counting rate H7S.</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2009-09-24T00:00:00.000</ReleaseDate>
            <Description>
            A directory containing daily ftp-downloadable files containing readout-by-readout listings 
            of the counts accumulated in each spin-sector of the 8-sectored H7S counting rate.  Aside
            from its division of counts into spin-sectors, H7S is a coincidence counting rate with 
            coincidence logic requirements identical to the spin-averaged counting rate H7. Therefore 
            both the H7 and the H7S counting rates respond primarily to electrons in the very approximate 
            energy range ~5-10 MeV. 
            The naming convention for the daily files is uly_het_full_rat_sect1_YYYDDD.txt, where YYY 
            indicates the three-digit year since 1900 (e.g. YYY=090 for 1990, and YYY=102 for 2002) and 
            DDD indicates the three digit day of year (Jan. 1 = 1). 
            In each file, following a detailed description of the format, the data consist of a
            readout by readout listing of counts accumulated in the eight 45 degree spin sectors
            of the sectored counting rate H7S during the intervals between successive readouts, organized
            into columns as described below.  
            The first 4 columns give the start time of the counting rate accumulation period for
            sector 7 of the rate as fractional year (to 12 decimal places) and as  year since 1900, 
            day of year, and ms of day at the start of the accumulation, followed by 1 column (labeled
            cov) giving the duration of the total accumulation period for all 8 sectors in 
            milli-seconds.  Thus the accumulation period in each of the sectors is the value given
            in the "cov" column divided by 8.  The accumulation in each of the successive sectors 
            7,8,1,2,3,4,5, and 6 starts cov/8 milliseconds after the start of the accumulation in 
            the previous sector.  Columns 6-13 then give the counts accumulated in each of the 
            eight sectors during the accumulation period.
            Each line contains data for one single readout accumulation of the 8 sectors of H7S.
            Since the accumulation period for each readout is forced to include an integral number 
            of spacecraft spins in order to produce equal coverage in all sectors, the lengths of 
            the accumulation periods vary in a cyclic manner as the period of the telemetry cycle 
            beats with the spacecraft spin period.  
            The H7S counting rate is fully read out every 64 seconds at the most common science 
            telemetry bit rate (2048 bps).  Thus, with a typical 5 rpm spacecraft spin rate the 
            accumulation intervals vary in a repeating cycle of  60, 60, 72, 60, 60, 72, 60, etc. 
            seconds.  At lower bit rates the average interval is equal to 64x(2048/BR) seconds 
            and the cycle automatically adjusts to produce this average accumulation. 
            The spin plane of the Ulysses spacecraft, in which the sectors are defined, is
            normal to the spin axis (spacecraft +Z axis), which is maintained within 1-2 degrees 
            of Earth-pointing at all times.  Viewed from Earth the spacecraft spins counter-clockwise.  
            The start of sector 1 is defined by the spacecraft-generated Sun Pulse, which is issued 
            when the sun crosses the +X/+Z quadrant of the X/Z plane.  The HET telescope axis is 
            parallel to the +X axis and normal to the Z axis. 
            No noise-removal or despiking has been done, so caution must be used in
            interpreting isolated large increases or decreases in the counting rates.  
        </Description>
            <Acknowledgement>
          Please acknowledge the Lead HET Investigator and COSPIN P.I., Dr. R. Bruce McKibben
        </Acknowledgement>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.Bruce.McKibben</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
                <Role>TeamLeader</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Clifford.Lopate</PersonID>
                <Role>DataProducer</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.Connell</PersonID>
                <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>
            The Ulysses cosmic ray and solar particle investigation
          </Name>
                <URL>
           http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments
          </URL>
                <Description>
            Published (J.A. Simpson et al., Astron. Astrophys. v92, pp365-399, 1992) description 
            of the COSPIN Instrumentation.  See especially section 4.3 for a detailed description 
            of the HET.
          </Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>
            COSPIN/HET User Notes
          </Name>
                <URL>
           http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments
          </URL>
                <Description>
            Identification of data channels archived and brief discussion of data structure
          </Description>
            </InformationURL>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>
            ReadMeHETFullRes.doc
          </Name>
                <URL>
            http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments
          </URL>
                <Description>
            Top Level descriptions of formats and contents of the six file types that make up the
            COSPIN HET Full Resolution Data Set. Detailed descriptions of the formats and contents
            are to found in header lines at the start of each downloaded data file.  The data 
            covered by this spase description are described in the ReadMe under the heading
            sect1.
            (*** Note ***:  During the build-up of this data set, a few errors and omissions have been 
            found in the header lines for some of the file types.  These errors and omissions are listed 
            in this ReadMe file.  Upon completion of the data set, all errors and omissions discovered
            will be corrected in all of the header lines of all of the file types and this note will be 
            removed.)
          </Description>
            </InformationURL>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <AccessInformation>
            <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/ESA/ESAC/UlyssesFinalArchive</RepositoryID>
            <Availability>Online</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>Ulysses COSPIN/HET Full Resolution 8-Sectored Counting Rate Data for H7S</Name>
                <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#data</URL>
                <Description>
            Parent directory containing daily ftp-downloadable files with the format described below.
          </Description>
            </AccessURL>
            <Format>Text</Format>
            <Encoding>ASCII</Encoding>
            <Acknowledgement>R.B. McKibben, Space Science Center, University of New Hampshire</Acknowledgement>
        </AccessInformation>
        <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET</InstrumentID>
        <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>1990-10-22T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
                <StopDate>2009-06-29T23:59:59.000</StopDate>
            </TimeSpan>
        </TemporalDescription>
        <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>Interval Start Time</Name>
            <Description>
           Nominal Start Time for the accumulation of counts in Sector 7, given in decimal year, 
           integer year, day of year, and milli-secnds of day.
         </Description>
            <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
            <Structure>
                <Size>4</Size>
                <Element>
                    <Name>Decimal Year</Name>
                    <Index>1</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_1</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0.00000000000</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>year</Name>
                    <Index>2</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_2</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>2009</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>day</Name>
                    <Index>3</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_3</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>1</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>366</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>msec</Name>
                    <Index>4</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_4</ParameterKey>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>86400000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>0</FillValue>
                </Element>
            </Structure>
            <Support>
                <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
            </Support>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>Accumulation period</Name>
            <ParameterKey>Column_5</ParameterKey>
            <Description>
           Length of the summed accumulation periods for all 8 sectors in milli-seconds.  This represents
           an integral number of spacecraft spin periods, most commonly 5 or 6 for H7s at 2048 bps.  
         </Description>
            <Caveats>
           None
         </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
            <Units>milliseconds</Units>
            <ValidMin>50000</ValidMin>
            <ValidMax>550000</ValidMax>
            <FillValue>0</FillValue>
            <Support>
                <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
            </Support>
        </Parameter>
        <Parameter>
            <Name>COSPIN/HET 8-Sectored Counting Rate H7S</Name>
            <Description>
            Counts accumulated in each of the 8 sectors of counting rate H7S during the accumulation 
            period starting at the time given in columns 1-4 and with a duration as given in column 5.
            Each sector contains counts incident from a specific 45 degree sector of the spin plane. 
            The start of sector 1 (0 degrees) is coincident with the spacecraft-generated Sun-pulse, 
            and the start of each subsequent sector is shifted by 45 degrees with respect to the preceding
            sector. For example, H7S1 covers the azimuthal range 0-45 degrees, H7S2 covers the azimuthal 
            range 45-90 degrees, etc.  In each sector, counts are registered only when the axis of the 
            telescope view cone is within that sector.
          </Description>
            <Caveats>
            Because the orbit of the spacecraft about the Sun lies in a plane inclined 80 degrees to the
            heliographic equator, and because the spacecraft spin axis (and thus the axis of the high gain 
            antenna) be pointed at Earth within 2 degrees at all times, determination of the direction 
            in space corresponding to the start of sector 1 can be complex.
          </Caveats>
            <Cadence>PT64S</Cadence>
            <Structure>
                <Size>8</Size>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S1</Name>
                    <Index>1</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_6</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S2</Name>
                    <Index>2</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_7</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S3</Name>
                    <Index>3</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_8</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S4</Name>
                    <Index>4</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_9</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S5</Name>
                    <Index>5</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_10</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S6</Name>
                    <Index>6</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_11</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S7</Name>
                    <Index>7</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_12</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
                <Element>
                    <Name>H7S8</Name>
                    <Index>8</Index>
                    <ParameterKey>Column_13</ParameterKey>
                    <Units>counts</Units>
                    <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
                    <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
                    <FillValue>-1</FillValue>
                </Element>
            </Structure>
            <Particle>
                <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
                <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
                <EnergyRange>
                    <Low>5</Low>
                    <High>10</High>
                    <Units>MeV</Units>
                </EnergyRange>
            </Particle>
        </Parameter>
    </NumericalData>
</Spase>