<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_6_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.6.0</Version>
   <NumericalData>
      <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/DE1/PWI/SFC/PT0.25S</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>DE 1 Plasma Wave Instrument (PWI) Step Frequency Correlator Electric and Magnetic Field Spectral Density</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>Dynamics Explorer 1 PWI SFC Spectra</AlternateName>
         <AlternateName>DE-A PWI SFC Spectra</AlternateName>
         <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/cb14-a164</DOI>
         <ReleaseDate>2025-05-02T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:14:31</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-07-30T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Added DOI and PublicationInfo minted by LFB, metadata versioned up to SPASE 2.6.0, reviewed by LFB 20230727</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2023-10-09T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Added complete CDAWeb and HAPI AccessInformation, LFB 20231009</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
			<RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2025-05-02T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Added ObservedRegion. JMW.</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>Two Dynamics Explorer (DE) spacecraft were launched August 3, 1981, and placed into coplanar polar orbits with DE-1 in a highly elliptical orbit and DE-2 in a lower more circular orbit. The primary objective of the DE program was to investigate magnetosphere-ionosphere-atmosphere coupling processes. The DE mission provided a wealth of new information on a wide variety of magnetospheric plasma wave phenomena including auroral kilometric radiation, auroral hiss, Z mode radiation, narrow-band electromagnetic emissions associated with equatorial upper hybrid waves, whistler mode emissions, wave-particle interactions stimulated by ground VLF transmitters, equatorial ion cyclotron emissions, ion Bernstein mode emissions, and electric field turbulence along the auroral field lines. These files contain calibrated, full resolution, data from the DE-1 Plasma Wave Instrument (PWI). This instrument was designed and built by the plasma wave group at The University of Iowa, Department of Physics and Astronomy, in collaboration with investigators at Stanford University&apos;s STAR Laboratory. It measured plasma wave phenomena and quasi-static electric fields using paired combinations of five PWI sensors: a 200m tip-to-tip long wire electric antenna deployed in the spacecraft spin plane, a 9m tip-to-tip tubular electric antenna deployed along the spacecraft spin axis, a short 0.6m electric antenna, mounted on the boom and oriented parallel to the long wire antenna, a magnetic loop antenna mounted on the boom and oriented to measure the component of the magnetic field parallel to the long wire antenna, and a magnetic search coil antenna, also mounted on a boom and oriented to measure the magnetic field parallel to the spacecraft spin axis. The PWI main electronics unit consisted of a Step Frequency Correlator (SFC), a Low Frequency Correlator (LFC), a Wideband Analog Receiver (WBR) and a Linear Wave Receiver (LWR). Only the SFC data are included in these files. The LFC data were provided in a companion fileset. A dataset containing available high rate WBR LWR data may be provided in the future. The SFC consisted of two Step Frequency Receivers (SFR-A and SFR-B) which provided amplitude measurements of the electric and magnetic fields from 100 Hz to 400 kHz and in-phase and quadrature-phase correlations of signals from any selected antenna pair. Phase data are not provided in these datasets.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Users of the DE-1 PWI SFC data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA CDAWeb and The University of Iowa as the source of the data in any publication.</Acknowledgement>
         <PublicationInfo>
            <Authors>Gurnett, Donald, A.</Authors>
            <PublicationDate>2023-01-01T00:00:00</PublicationDate>
            <PublishedBy>NASA Space Physics Data Facility</PublishedBy>
         </PublicationInfo>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jolene.S.Pickett</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.J.Granroth</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Chris.W.Piker</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>The University of Iowa DE-1 PWI Page</Name>
            <URL>https://space.physics.uiowa.edu/plasma-wave/de/home.html</URL>
            <Description>
            </Description>
            <Language>en</Language>
         </InformationURL>
         <PriorID>spase://VWO/NumericalData/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI/SFC.PT0.25S</PriorID>
         <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI/SFC/PT0.25S</PriorID>
         <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/DE1/PWI/SFC/PT0.25S</PriorID>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF/CDAWeb</RepositoryID>
         <Availability>Online</Availability>
         <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
            <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/de/de1/waves_pwi/sfc-spectra_cdaweb/</URL>
            <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_SFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
            <Description>In CDF via ftps from SPDF</Description>
         </AccessURL>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
            <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/de/de1/waves_pwi/sfc-spectra_cdaweb/</URL>
            <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_SFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
            <Description>In CDF via https from SPDF</Description>
         </AccessURL>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>CDAWeb</Name>
            <URL>https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/eval2.cgi?dataset=DE1_PWI_SFC-SPECTRA&amp;index=sp_phys</URL>
            <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_SFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
            <Description>Access to ASCII, CDF, and plots via NASA/GSFC CDAWeb</Description>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>CDF</Format>
         <Encoding>None</Encoding>
         <Acknowledgement>Users of the DE-1 PWI SFC data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA CDAWeb and The University of Iowa as the source of the data in any publication.</Acknowledgement>
      </AccessInformation>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF/CDAWeb</RepositoryID>
         <Availability>Online</Availability>
         <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>CDAWeb HAPI Server</Name>
            <URL>https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/hapi</URL>
            <Style>HAPI</Style>
            <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_SFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
            <Description>Web Service to this product using the HAPI interface</Description>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>CSV</Format>
         <Acknowledgement>Users of the DE-1 PWI SFC data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA CDAWeb and The University of Iowa as the source of the data in any publication.</Acknowledgement>
      </AccessInformation>
      <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
      <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI</InstrumentID>
      <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
      <MeasurementType>Spectrum</MeasurementType>
      <TemporalDescription>
         <TimeSpan>
            <StartDate>1981-09-16T05:21:48</StartDate>
            <StopDate>1984-06-28T20:35:55</StopDate>
            <Note>
            </Note>
         </TimeSpan>
         <Cadence>PT0.25S</Cadence>
      </TemporalDescription>
	  <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
	  <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Plasmasphere</ObservedRegion>
	  <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservedRegion>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Event time for the start of the sweep</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Epoch</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Spacecraft Event Time in UTC for the start of an SFR sweep. To get time offsets within a sweep add the corresponding values in the SubSweepTime array.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>SFC Ex Receiver (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Ex_Receivers</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Step Frequency Correlator has two independent Step Frequency Receivers, labeled &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos;. This variable records which of the SFRs were connected to the Ex antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: &apos;1&apos; if SFR-A was connected to Ex, &apos;2&apos; if SFR-B was connected to Ex, and &apos;3&apos; if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>SFC Es Receiver (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Es_Receivers</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Step Frequency Correlator has two independent Step Frequency Receivers, labeled &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos;. This variable records which of the SFRs were connected to the Es antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: &apos;1&apos; if SFR-A was connected to Es, &apos;2&apos; if SFR-B was connected to Es, and &apos;3&apos; if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>SFC Ez Receiver (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Ez_Receivers</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Step Frequency Correlator has two independent Step Frequency Receivers, labeled &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos;. This variable records which of the SFRs were connected to the Ez antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: &apos;1&apos; if SFR-A was connected to Ez, &apos;2&apos; if SFR-B was connected to Ez, and &apos;3&apos; if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>SFC B Receiver (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
         <ParameterKey>B_Receivers</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Step Frequency Correlator has two independent Step Frequency Receivers, labeled &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos;. This variable records which of the SFRs were connected to the B antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: &apos;1&apos; if SFR-A was connected to B, &apos;2&apos; if SFR-B was connected to B, and &apos;3&apos; if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Integer combining all data quality flags (0 = no issues detected)</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Quality_Flag</ParameterKey>
         <Description>A bitwise OR&apos;ing of all known issue values for this record. The following issue values are defined. (0x2: Attenuation Mode) If this value is present the measurements are less sensitive than normal due to the input being attenuated by 30 dB. Though the data are still calibrated they do not have the same contrast as data collected in the un-attenuated state. (0x1: Gain Toggle Mode) If this value is present it means that the SFC was toggling attenuation states every 1/2 second. Measurements collected in the first half of the second are not attenuated. Measurements collected in the last half were attenuated by 30 dB. To achieve a single calibrated state for a single filter band in a record the attenuated measurements have been dropped. The final quality flag is a bitwise OR&apos;ing of all issue values.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Spin Plane E-Field (SFC Ex) Spectra, 200 meter antenna, 104 Hz to 409 kHz</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Ex_Spectra</ParameterKey>
         <Description>These data are collected via the Long Wire Antenna (Ex) which has a frequency response range of DC to 2 MHz. It is constructed of two 100 meter wires deployed in the spacecraft spin plane held in place by a 5 g tip mass. The conductor is made of BeCu wire with 7 strands of 5-mil diam each. The effective electrical length is 173.1 meters DC and 101.4 meters AC.</Description>
         <Units>V^2 m^-2 Hz^-1</Units>
         <Structure>
            <Size>512</Size>
         </Structure>
         <Wave>
            <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
            <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
            <FrequencyRange>
               <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
               <Low>104</Low>
               <High>409000</High>
               <Units>Hz</Units>
            </FrequencyRange>
         </Wave>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Spin Axis E-Field (SFC Ez) Spectra, 8 meter antenna, 104 Hz to 409 kHz</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Ez_Spectra</ParameterKey>
         <Description>These data are collected via the Tubular Electric Antenna (Ez) which has a frequency response range of DC to 2 MHz. It is constructed of two 4 meter tubes deployed along the spacecraft spin axis. The conductor is silver plated BeCu 2.8 cm diameter elements and has an effective electrical length of 8.0 meters DC and 5.0 meters AC.</Description>
         <Units>V^2 m^-2 Hz^-1</Units>
         <Structure>
            <Size>512</Size>
         </Structure>
         <Wave>
            <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
            <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
            <FrequencyRange>
               <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
               <Low>104</Low>
               <High>409000</High>
               <Units>Hz</Units>
            </FrequencyRange>
         </Wave>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Spin Plane E-Field (SFC Es) Spectra, 0.6 meter antenna, 104 Hz to 100 kHz</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Es_Spectra</ParameterKey>
         <Description>These data are collected via the Short Electric Antenna (Es) which has a response range of 20 Hz to 100 kHz. It&apos;s constructed of two 10 cm diameter wire spheres separated by 0.6 meters with fiberglass booms. It is mounted on the PWI 6 meter boom oriented parallel to the long wire antenna (Ex). It&apos;s effective electrical length is 0.6 meters for AC signals.</Description>
         <Units>V^2 m^-2 Hz^-1</Units>
         <Structure>
            <Size>512</Size>
         </Structure>
         <Wave>
            <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
            <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
            <FrequencyRange>
               <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
               <Low>104</Low>
               <High>100000</High>
               <Units>Hz</Units>
            </FrequencyRange>
         </Wave>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Spin Plane B-Field Spectra (SFC B), 1.0 m^2 loop, 104 Hz to 409 kHz</Name>
         <ParameterKey>B_Spectra</ParameterKey>
         <Description>These data are collected via the Magnetic Loop Antenna (B) which has a frequency response range of 100 Hz to 35 kHz for dB/dt and 35 kHz to 400 kHz response for B. It is constructed of a single loop of aluminum tubing of 0.8 by 1.25 meters in size covering 1.0 m^2 area and is mounted on the PWI 6 meter boom oriented to measure the spin-modulated component of B parallel to the long wire antenna, Ex.</Description>
         <Units>nT^2 Hz^-1</Units>
         <Structure>
            <Size>512</Size>
         </Structure>
         <Wave>
            <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
            <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
            <FrequencyRange>
               <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
               <Low>104</Low>
               <High>409000</High>
               <Units>Hz</Units>
            </FrequencyRange>
         </Wave>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Time offsets from the Epoch time for each spectra measurement in a sweep</Name>
         <ParameterKey>SubSweepTime</ParameterKey>
         <Description>If sub-sweep timing is not important to your application, this value can be ignored. Otherwise for each measurement add this time to the Epoch value for the record. There is one offset in this array for each measurement in the sweep</Description>
         <Units>s</Units>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Channel Frequency Centers (fixed), 512 (104.8 to 409610 Hz)</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Frequencies</ParameterKey>
         <Description>The SFC contained two Filter Receivers, SFR-A and SFR-B; this variable provides frequency channel centers for the two receivers. The same table is used for both SFR-A and SFR-B data.</Description>
         <Units>Hz</Units>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Wideband (waveform) data availability status</Name>
         <ParameterKey>WBR_xmit</ParameterKey>
         <Description>PWI Waveform data were transmitted directly from DE1 without going through the standard telemetry stream. This status field will read 0 if the wideband transmitter was off during this time period and thus waveform data were not transmitted. A 1 in this field indicates the transmitter was on and that waveform data may be available.</Description>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
         </Support>
      </Parameter>
   </NumericalData>
</Spase>
