<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/LECP/Neptune/PT24S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune LECP Resampled Summary Scan Average 24-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                     <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
Description of the PDS LECP Neptune Scan data.                                
                                                                              
     This data consists of resampled data from the Low Energy                 
Charged Particle (LECP) Experiment on the Voyager 2 Spacecraft                
for the period when Voyager 2 was in the vicinity of the planet               
Neptune.  The period covered is 1989-08-24T00:00:00.000 SCET  to              
1989-08-27T00:00:00.000 SCET.  This data approximates a time series           
of charged particle fluxes from a selection of channels available             
from the instrument.  The word approximates is used because                   
the angle scanning modes of the instrument complicates the                    
nature of the data.  At times the instrument mechanically scans,              
and at times it is fixed to look at a specific direction.                     
With the type of data given here, the fluxes are angle averaged               
for those time periods when the instrument is scanning, and are               
time averaged over an arbitrary period (12 or 24 sec, see below)              
for the periods when the detectors are stationary. The angle                  
averaged records represent periods of time equal to 48 or 96                  
sec (see below). This kind of data presentation has been called               
the LECP Scan data. Another form that is also available is                    
the LECP Step data that gives the angle distributions sampled                 
during the scanning periods.                                                  
                                                                              
   Three scanning situations occurred during the time of this                 
data. They are: 1) continuous 48 sec stepping (48 seconds for                 
each of 8 look directions for a total of 6.4 minutes per scan;                
note that sector 8 is shielded with 2 mm Al), 2) a special                    
Neptune scan cyclic with the following sequence: 7, scan, 1, scan,            
7, scan, scan, repeat; where the 7 and the 1 represent 5.2                    
minute periods when the instrument is fixed in sectors 7 or 1,                
respectively, and where the word scan represents a period                     
of scanning (6 sec stepping for a total scan time of 48 sec);                 
and 3) periods when the detectors are fixed for more extended                 
periods in sector 7 (periods bracketing the ring plane crossings).            
For this Neptune Scan data, the 6.4 minute scan records during                
stepping mode (1) have been time averaged to 12.8 minute records.             
Also, during stepping mode (2), the double scans that have no                 
fixed periods between them have been averaged together into                   
a single (96 sec) record.  The single scans represent 48 sec                  
records.  The schedule for the three stepping modes is as                     
follows:                                                                      
                                                                              
       prior to day 236/1600 SCET:     Mode (1)                               
       236/1600 to 237/0239:           Mode (2)                               
       237/0239 to 237/0319:           Mode (3)                               
       237/0319 to 237/0503:           Mode (2)                               
       237/0503 to 237/0554:           Mode (3)                               
       237/0554 to 238/0400:           Mode (2)                               
       after 237/0400:                 Mode (1)                               
                                                                              
Obviously these stepping mode changes, and the angle sample                   
switching that occurs during stepping mode (2), gives the data                
a disjointed appearance.                                                      
                                                                              
     Two channel sample modes also occurred during the Neptune                
encounter.  These two modes affect this data set only by changing             
the primary record time length for the LECP Experiment Data Records           
(EDR&apos;s). These time lengths have, in turn, been utilized for the              
averaging times of this data set for non-stepping periods.  The               
schedule is:                                                                  
                                                                              
      prior to day 237/0200 SCET:  Far Encounter (24 sec records)             
                                                                              
      237/0200 to 237/0551:        Near Encounter (12 sec records)            
                                                                              
      after 237/0551:              Far Encounter (24 sec records)             
                                                                              
     The LECP channels utilized with this data set are:                       
                                                                              
       EB01:          electrons,  22 to  35 keV                               
       EB02:          electrons,  35  to  61 keV                              
       EB03:          electrons,  61 to  112 keV                              
       EB04:          electrons, 112 to 183 keV                               
       EG06-EG07:     electrons, 252 to 480 keV                               
       EG07-EG08:     electrons, 480 to 853 keV                               
       EG08-EG09:     electrons, 853 to 1200 keV                              
       PL01:          ions,       28 to  43  keV                              
       PL02:          ions,       43 to  80  keV                              
       PL03:          ions,       80 to 137  keV                              
       PL04:          ions,      137 to 215  keV                              
       PL05:          ions,      215 to 540  keV                              
       PL06:          ions,      540 to 990  keV                              
       PL07:          ions,      990 to 2140 keV                              
       PL08:          ions,     2140 to 3500 keV                              
                                                                              
Please note that 3 of the electron channels are derived from                  
4 of the instrumental channels by taking differences between                  
adjacent (in energy) channels.                                                
                                                                              
     The channel data is given in units of intensity:                         
counts/(cm^2.sec.str.keV).  For the ions, it has been assumed                 
that they consist only of protons.  Intensity is derived from                 
the raw count rates via the relation:                                         
                                                                              
                    I  =  CR/(eG.(E2-E1),                                     
                                                                              
where eG is geometric factor times detector efficiency, and                   
(E2-E1) is the band pass of the channel in energy.  The proton                
values of these parameters were used in deriving the intensities              
for this data set.  To obtain the Intensities under the assumption            
that some other mass species dominates, one must convert back                 
to count rate (CR) utilizing the proton parameters, and then                  
convert to intensity using the parameters corresponding to the        </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-LECP-4-SUMM-SCAN-24SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-LECP-4-SUMM-SCAN-24SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-LECP-4-SUMM-SCAN-24SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-LECP-4-SUMM-SCAN-24SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/LECP</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-08-24T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-08-27T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT24S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
