<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.4.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.1</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-AMDA/Ulysses/SWICS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>SWICS</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>GLG</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (SWICS) on Ulysses is designed to determine uniquely the elemental and 
        ionic-charge composition, and the temperatures and mean speeds of all major solar-wind ions, from H through Fe, at solar wind 
        speeds ranging from 175 km/s (protons) to 1280 km/s (Fe8+). The instrument, which covers an energy per charge range from 0.16 
        to 59.6 keV/e in ~13 min, combines an electrostatic analyzer with post-acceleration, followed by a time-of-flight and energy measurement. 
        The measurements made by SWICS will have an impact on many areas of solar and heliospheric physics, in particular providing essential 
        and unique information on: (i) conditions and processes in the region of the corona where the solar wind is accelerated; (ii) the 
        location of the source regions of the solar wind in the corona; (iii) coronal heating processes; (iv) the extent and causes of 
        variations in the composition of the solar atmosphere; (v) plasma processes in the solar wind; (vi) the acceleration of energetic 
        particles in the solar wind; (vii) the thermalization and acceleration of interstellar ions in the solar wind, and their composition; 
        and (viii) the composition, charge states and behavior of the plasma in various regions of the Jovian magnetosphere.</Description>
        <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.Gloeckler</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instrument description at ESA's cosmos portal</Name>
        <URL>https://www.cosmos.esa.int/web/ulysses/swics-instrument</URL>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (GLG/SWICS) on Ulysses</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-AMDA/Ulysses</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
