<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.7.0.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/DE1/PWI/LFC/PT0.25S</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>NASA</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>NumericalData</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>DE 1 Plasma Wave Instrument (PWI) Low Frequency Correlator Electric and Magnetic Field Spectral Density</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Dynamics Explorer 1 PWI LFC Spectra</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>DE-A PWI LFC Spectra</AlternateName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/hx4p-3v35</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2025-10-02T15:11:48Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:14:31</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2023-07-30T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added DOI and PublicationInfo minted by LFB, metadata versioned up to SPASE 2.6.0, reviewed by LFB 20230727</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2023-10-09T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added complete CDAWeb and HAPI AccessInformation, LFB 20231009</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-05-02T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added ObservedRegion. JMW.</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-10-02T15:11:48Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Updated PublishedBy name to match ROR Registry. Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Changed http to https in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Fixed version number separator in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Matched version number in schemaLocation attribute to updated value in Version tag. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>Two Dynamics Explorer (DE) spacecraft were launched August 3, 1981, and placed into coplanar polar orbits with DE-1 in a highly elliptical orbit and DE-2 in a lower more circular orbit. The primary objective of the DE program was to investigate magnetosphere-ionosphere-atmosphere coupling processes. The DE mission provided a wealth of new information on a wide variety of magnetospheric plasma wave phenomena including auroral kilometric radiation, auroral hiss, Z mode radiation, narrow-band electromagnetic emissions associated with equatorial upper hybrid waves, whistler mode emissions, wave-particle interactions stimulated by ground VLF transmitters, equatorial ion cyclotron emissions, ion Bernstein mode emissions, and electric field turbulence along the auroral field lines. These files contain calibrated, full resolution, data from the DE-1 Plasma Wave Instrument (PWI). This instrument was designed and built by the plasma wave group at The University of Iowa, Department of Physics and Astronomy, in collaboration with investigators at Stanford University's STAR Laboratory. It measured plasma wave phenomena and quasi-static electric fields using paired combinations of five PWI sensors: a 200m tip-to-tip long wire electric antenna deployed in the spacecraft spin plane, a 9m tip-to-tip tubular electric antenna deployed along the spacecraft spin axis, a short 0.6m electric antenna, mounted on the boom and oriented parallel to the long wire antenna, a magnetic loop antenna mounted on the boom and oriented to measure the component of the magnetic field parallel to the long wire antenna, and a magnetic search coil antenna, also mounted on a boom and oriented to measure the magnetic field parallel to the spacecraft spin axis. The PWI main electronics unit consisted of a Step Frequency Correlator (SFC), a Low Frequency Correlator (LFC), a Wideband Analog Receiver (WBR) and a Linear Wave Receiver (LWR). Only the LFC data are included in these files. The SFC data were provided in a companion fileset. A dataset containing available high rate WBR LWR data may be provided in future archive products. The LFC consisted of two receivers (LFR-A and LFR-B) with 8 analog channels each. The analog channels were centered at 1.78, 3.12, 5.62, 10.0, 17.8, 31.2, 56.2 and 100 Hz. Each channel's band-edge was at +/-15% of the center value. Each LFR in the LFC could be connected to either the Ex, Es, Ez, or H antenna during an 8 second major frame. In addition, the Low Frequency Correlator provided in-phase and quadrature-phase correlations of signals from any selected antenna pair. Phase data are not provided in this file set.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Users of the DE-1 PWI LFC data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA CDAWeb and The University of Iowa as the source of the data in any publication.</Acknowledgement>
      <PublicationInfo>
        <Authors>Gurnett, Donald, A.</Authors>
        <PublicationDate>2023-01-01T00:00:00</PublicationDate>
        <PublishedBy>Space Physics Data Facility</PublishedBy>
      </PublicationInfo>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jolene.S.Pickett</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.J.Granroth</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Chris.W.Piker</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>The University of Iowa DE-1 PWI Page</Name>
        <URL>https://space.physics.uiowa.edu/plasma-wave/de/home.html</URL>
        <Description>
            </Description>
        <Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://VWO/NumericalData/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI/LFC.PT0.25S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI/LFC/PT0.25S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/DE1/PWI/LFC/PT0.25S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF/CDAWeb</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
        <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/de/de1/waves_pwi/lfc-spectra_cdaweb/</URL>
        <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_LFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
        <Description>In CDF via ftps from SPDF</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
        <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/de/de1/waves_pwi/lfc-spectra_cdaweb/</URL>
        <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_LFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
        <Description>In CDF via https from SPDF</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>CDAWeb</Name>
        <URL>https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/cgi-bin/eval2.cgi?dataset=DE1_PWI_LFC-SPECTRA&amp;index=sp_phys</URL>
        <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_LFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
        <Description>Access to ASCII, CDF, and plots via NASA/GSFC CDAWeb</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>CDF</Format>
      <Encoding>None</Encoding>
      <Acknowledgement>Users of the DE-1 PWI LFC data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA CDAWeb and The University of Iowa as the source of the data in any publication.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF/CDAWeb</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>CDAWeb HAPI Server</Name>
        <URL>https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/hapi</URL>
        <Style>HAPI</Style>
        <ProductKey>DE1_PWI_LFC-SPECTRA</ProductKey>
        <Description>Web Service to this product using the HAPI interface</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>CSV</Format>
      <Acknowledgement>Users of the DE-1 PWI LFC data are encouraged to acknowledge NASA CDAWeb and The University of Iowa as the source of the data in any publication.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>Spectrum</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1981-09-16T05:21:48</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1984-06-28T05:53:31</StopDate>
        <Note>
            </Note>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT0.25S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Plasmasphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservedRegion>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Event time for the start of the sweep</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Epoch</ParameterKey>
      <Description>Spacecraft Event Time in UTC for the start of an LFC sweep. To get time offsets within a sweep add the corresponding values in the SubSweepTime array.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>The Filter Receiver used to measure the Ex Antenna output (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Ex_Receivers</ParameterKey>
      <Description>Low Frequency Correlator has two independent Filter Receivers, labeled 'A' and 'B'. This variable records which of the filter receivers were connected to the Ex antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: '1' if FR-A was connected to Ex, '2' if FR-B was connected to Ex, and '3' if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>The Filter Receivers used to measure the Es Antenna output (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Es_Receivers</ParameterKey>
      <Description>Low Frequency Correlator has two independent Filter Receivers, labeled 'A' and 'B'. This variable records which of the filter receivers were connected to the Es antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: '1' if FR-A was connected to Es, '2' if FR-B was connected to Es, and '3' if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>The Filter Receivers used to measure the Ez Antenna output (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Ez_Receivers</ParameterKey>
      <Description>Low Frequency Correlator has two independent Filter Receivers, labeled 'A' and 'B'. This variable records which of the filter receivers were connected to the Ez antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: '1' if FR-A was connected to Ez, '2' if FR-B was connected to Ez, and '3' if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>The Filter Receivers used to measure the H Antenna output (1=A,2=B,3=both)</Name>
      <ParameterKey>H_Receivers</ParameterKey>
      <Description>Low Frequency Correlator has two independent Filter Receivers, labeled 'A' and 'B'. This variable records which of the filter receivers were connected to the H antenna during the collection of each record. This field will read: '1' if FR-A was connected to B, '2' if FR-B was connected to B, and '3' if both were used at different times during the 32 second sweep period.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Integer combining all data quality flags (0 = no issues detected)</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Quality_Flag</ParameterKey>
      <Description>A bitwise OR'ing of all known issue values for this record. At present none are defined so this field should always read 0.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Spin Plane E-Field (LFC Ex) Spectra, 200 meter antenna, 1.78 Hz to 100 Hz</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Ex_Spectra</ParameterKey>
      <Description>These data are collected via the Long Wire Antenna (Ex) which has a frequency response range of DC to 2 MHz. It is constructed of two 100 meter wires deployed in the spacecraft spin plane held in place by a 5 g tip mass. The conductor is made of BeCu wire with 7 strands of 5-mil diam each. The effective electrical length is 173.1 meters DC and 101.4 meters AC.</Description>
      <Units>V^2 m^-2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <Structure>
        <Size>512</Size>
      </Structure>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
          <Low>1.78</Low>
          <High>100</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Spin Axis E-Field (LFC Ez) Spectra, 8 meter antenna, 1.78 Hz to 100 Hz</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Ez_Spectra</ParameterKey>
      <Description>These data are collected via the Tubular Electric Antenna (Ez) which has a frequency response range of DC to 2 MHz. It is constructed of two 4 meter tubes deployed along the spacecraft spin axis. The conductor is silver plated BeCu 2.8 cm diameter elements and has an effective electrical length of 8.0 meters DC and 5.0 meters AC.</Description>
      <Units>V^2 m^-2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <Structure>
        <Size>512</Size>
      </Structure>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
          <Low>1.78</Low>
          <High>100</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Spin Plane E-Field (LFC Es) Spectra, 0.6 meter antenna, 1.78 Hz to 100 Hz</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Es_Spectra</ParameterKey>
      <Description>These data are collected via the Short Electric Antenna (Es) which has a response range of 20 Hz to 100 kHz. It's constructed of two 10 cm diameter wire spheres separated by 0.6 meters with fiberglass booms. It is mounted on the PWI 6 meter boom oriented parallel to the long wire antenna (Ex). It's effective electrical length is 0.6 meters for AC signals.</Description>
      <Units>V^2 m^-2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <Structure>
        <Size>512</Size>
      </Structure>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACElectricField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
          <Low>1.78</Low>
          <High>100</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Spin Axis B-Field Spectra (LFC H), search coil, 1.8 to 100 Hz</Name>
      <ParameterKey>H_Spectra</ParameterKey>
      <Description>These data are collected via the Magnetic Search Coil (H) which has a response range of 1 Hz to 1 kHz. It's constructed of two coils of 5000 turns of #40 copper wire on a 40 cm laminated high-permeability core enclosed in a fiberglass housing and coated with conducting material</Description>
      <Units>nT^2 Hz^-1</Units>
      <Structure>
        <Size>512</Size>
      </Structure>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
          <Low>1.78</Low>
          <High>100</High>
          <Units>Hz</Units>
        </FrequencyRange>
      </Wave>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Time offsets (fixed) from the Epoch time for each spectra measurement in a sweep</Name>
      <ParameterKey>SubSweepTime</ParameterKey>
      <Description>If sub-sweep timing is not important to your application, this value can be ignored. Otherwise for each measurement add this time to the Epoch value for the record. There is one offset in this array for each measurement in the sweep</Description>
      <Units>s</Units>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Channel Frequency Centers (fixed), 512 (1.78 to 100 Hz)</Name>
      <ParameterKey>Frequencies</ParameterKey>
      <Description>The LFC contained two Filter Receivers, FR-A and FR-B; this variable provides frequency channel centers for the two receivers. The same table is used for both FR-A and FR-B data.</Description>
      <Units>Hz</Units>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Wideband (waveform) data availability status</Name>
      <ParameterKey>WBR_xmit</ParameterKey>
      <Description>PWI Waveform data were transmitted directly from DE1 without going through the standard telemetry stream. This status field will read 0 if the wideband transmitter was off during this time period and thus waveform data were not transmitted. A 1 in this field indicates the transmitter was on and that waveform data may be available.</Description>
      <Support>
        <SupportQuantity>Other</SupportQuantity>
      </Support>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
