<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <Version>2.3.0</Version>
    <NumericalData>
        <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/PioneerVenusOrbiter/OMAG/PT1H</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>Pioneer Venus Orbiter(PVO) hourly averaged magnetic field data</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2021-03-11T18:39:11Z</ReleaseDate> 
<Description>This data set includes hourly averages of the interplanetary magnetic field magnitude and vector components measured by the Pioneer Venus Orbiter. The magnetic field data and spacecraft coordinates are provided in the Venus Solar Observer (VSO) system. Data collection periods inside the Venusian bow shock have been removed and hour averages have computed for those data points. Note that the BT values are computed from magnitudes of high resolution (1/4 sec.) vectors and are actually overlapped two-hour averages computed every hour to avoid potential aliasing effects from non-overlapping averages. The vector component averages are also overlapped in the same manner. Also note that BT will generally be higher than the magnitude of the hour-average field vector, so the latter should not be used to compute magnitude. Data records for hours 8-10 of July 3, 1979 have been removed since the data values are erroneous. Two-minute overlapping averages without the bow shock cuts were previously archived at NSSDC as dataset 78-051A-12G for data from 1978-12-06 through 1984-09-30 (this data set now extends through 1992-10-08, the end of the PVO mission). Detailed questions on the removal procedure should be directed to Chris Russell. This data was supplied by Janet Luhmann (now at UC-Berkeley) and Muriel Kniffen of the UCLA PVO magnetometer team in support of PVO data archiving and the COHO program. A transformed version of this data set in heliographic &amp; RTN coordinates may be found in COHO directory PIONEER_VENUS/MERGED and can also be plotted on-line using the COHOWeb system.</Description>
            <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the Principal Investigator, Dr. Christopher Russell, and SPDF.</Acknowledgement>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.T.Russell</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
                <Name>Readme file from SPDF</Name>
                <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/pioneer/pioneer_venus/mag/hour/pvomaghr_fmt.txt</URL>
            </InformationURL>
            <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Pioneer_Venus/MAG/PT1H</PriorID>
            <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/PioneerVenusOrbiter/OMAG/PT1H</PriorID>
        </ResourceHeader>
     <AccessInformation>
            <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF</RepositoryID>
            <Availability>Online</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
                <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/pioneer/pioneer_venus/mag/hour/</URL>
                <Description>for hourly data via ftp</Description>
            </AccessURL>
         <AccessURL>
                <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
                <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/pioneer/pioneer_venus/mag/hour/</URL>
                <Description>for hourly data via http</Description>
            </AccessURL>
            <Format>Text</Format>
     </AccessInformation>
          <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/PioneerVenusOrbiter/OMAG</InstrumentID>
        <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>1978-12-06T00:00:00</StartDate>
                <StopDate>1988-08-07T00:00:00</StopDate>
            </TimeSpan>
            <Cadence>PT1H</Cadence>
        </TemporalDescription>
        <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservedRegion>
     </NumericalData>
 </Spase>