<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/NumericalData/CDPP-Archive/PSP/Ephemeris/PARKERSP_ATTITUDE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>PARKER SOLAR PROBE Attitude and Ephemeris Data (CDF)</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/b27s-7rd8</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-07-04T15:46:59Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This data sets contains spacecraft attitude (roll and offpointing from SPICE kernels), distance from Sun in AU and RTN coordinates. 
 The RTN frame is defined as follows :
    R axis points from the Sun to the spacecraft.
    T = Omega x R, where Omega is the Sun's rotation axis.
    N = R x T.
The XYZ or spacecraft frame (also referred to as SC) is defined as follows for Parker Solar Probe :
    Z axis corresponds to the satellite axis (and its arm) and points towards the Sun. When PSP is facing the Sun, Z = -R.
    X is normally included in the ecliptic plane, with X = Z x Omega, when PSP is facing the Sun.
    Y is normally perpendicular to the ecliptic plane, pointing towards the South. PSP's solar panels are oriented along the Y axis.

The data file with position is in CDF format. Records are arranged chronologically, with 1 min time resolution. One record contains :
Epoch (Y-m-d H:M:S.000000000 format), cos_roll, cos_offpointing, rad_AU (AU), R value (m), T value (m), N value (m)
with :
    Epoch : Time of the record in TT2000 format, exactly in the kernels. This time corresponds to nanoseconds since 1 Jan 2000 12:00:00 with leap seconds included.
    cos_roll : Cosine of roll angle, i.e. angle between X and T axis (from (XYZ) and (RTN) frames). This angle mainly varies during satellite roll operations, which are carried out several times per orbit to calibrate the MAG fluxgates.
    cos_offpointing : Cosine of offpointing angle, i.e. angle between Z and R axis. This angle is important for determining when the instruments on the boom are sunlit. Off-pointing primarily occurs when the spacecraft is away from the Sun.
    rad_AU : Parker Solar Probe-Sun distance in AU.
    R, T and N values (in m) of Parker Solar Probe in (RTN) frame.

Attitude data, PSP-Sun distance and PSP ephemeris are computed from SPICE kernels (see the CDAWEB Data Center  https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/psp/ephemeris/spice/).</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
        In publications, we recommend to add the following sentence in the acknowledgments:  
The authors acknowledge LPC2E (Laboratoire Physique et Chimie de l'Environnement et de l'Espace), CNRS (Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique) and CNES (Centre National d Etudes Spatiales) for support for production of these data and CDPP (Centre de Donnees de la Physique des Plasmas) for their archiving and provision.	  
	  </Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Thierry.Dudok.De.Wit</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://regards.cnes.fr/user/cdpp/modules/1777?sp=DatasetName;q=DatasetName:PARKERSP_ATTITUDE</URL>
        <Description>Access via CNES Data Archive for CDPP</Description>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>CDF</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/PSP/Ephemeris</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Ephemeris</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2018-08-14T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2021-12-31T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Sun.Corona</ObservedRegion>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
