<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_9.xsd">
  <Version>2.3.0</Version>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Neptune/PT48S</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune Plasma Wave Spectrometer (PWS) Resampled Spectrum Analyzer, Version 1.0, 48 s Summary Data</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2018-11-27T18:09:04Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>* Data Set Overview
* =================

This Data Set consists of 48 s calibrated, averaged Wave Electric Field Intensities from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver Spectrum Analyzer obtained in the Vicinity of the Neptunian Magnetosphere. For each 48 s Interval, a geometric average Field Strength is determined for each of the sixteen Spectrum Analyzer Channels whose Center Frequencies range from 10 Hz to 56.2 kHz and which are logarithmically spaced in Frequency, four Channels per Decade. The Time associated with each Set of Averages is the Beginning of the Averaging Interval. Averages are stored in Units of V/m. During Data Gaps where complete 48 s Intervals are missing, no Entries exist in the File, that is, the Gaps are not Zero-filled or Tagged in any other way. Additional Information about this Data Set and the Instrument which produced it can be found elsewhere in this Catalog. An Overview of the Data in this Data Set can be found in (Gurnett et al., 1989) and a complete Instrument Description can be found in (Scarf and Gurnett, 1977).

* Parameters
* ==========

* Derived Parameters
* ==================

+------------------------------------------------------------------+
| Parameter Characteristics           | Value                      |
--------------------------------------------------------------------
| Sampling Parameter Name             | TIME                       |
| Sampling Parameter Resolution       | 48.0 SECONDS               |
| Minimum Sampling Parameter          | N/A (1977-08-20T15:53:00Z) |
| Maximum Sampling Parameter          | N/A                        |
| Sampling Parameter Interval         | 48.0 SECONDS               |
| Minimum Available Sampling Interval | 4.0 SECONDS                |
| Data Set Parameter Name             | PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM       |
| Noise Level                         | 0.000005 V/M               |
| Data Set Parameter Unit             | VOLTS/METER                |
+------------------------------------------------------------------+

Plasma Wave Spectrum: A Set of derived Parameters consisting of Wave Electric Field Intensities or Electric Field Spectral Densities at various contiguous Frequencies over a Range of Frequencies. The MKS Units are: V/m or V^2/(Hz m^2), respectively.

* Measured Parameters
* ===================

Electric Field Component: A measured Parameter equaling the Electric Field Strength (e.g. in mV/m) along a particular Axis Direction.

Wave Magnetic Field Intensity: A measured Parameter equaling the Magnetic Field Strength in a specific Frequency Passband (in MKS Unit: V/m) measured in a single Sensor or Antenna.

Wave Electric Field Intensity: A measured Parameter equaling the Electric Field Strength in a specific Frequency Passband (in MKS Unit: V/m) measured in a single Sensor or Antenna.

* Processing
* ==========

The Data Files in this Data Set were created from the SA 4 s Data Set (VG2-N-PWS-2-EDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0), using the V2U48 Software.

* Software V2U48
* ==============

+------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+
| Software V2U48 Characteristics | Value                                             |
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
| Software Name                  | V2U48                                             |
| Software Type                  | N/A                                               |
| Software Release Date          | 1988-08-01                                        |
| Node ID                        | PPI-IOWA                                          |
| Cognizant Engineer             | LARRY J. GRANROTH                                 |
| Software Access Description    | NOT ACCESSIBLE THROUGH PDS CATALOG - CONTACT NODE |
+------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+

V2U48 is a specialized, hard-coded Routine to process a specific Interval of Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Spectrometer (PWS) Spectrum Analyzer Data around Uranus Encounter. Input is from MSF or CD Data Sets produced and stored at the University of Iowa, and Output is to ASCII Text Files which are compatible with PDS Data loading Procedures. These Files contain Information corresponding to the VG2-N-PWS-4-SUMM-SA-48SEC-V1.0 and VG2-U-PWS-4-SUMM-SA-48SEC Data Set.

Note: The Software is not available for Public Use.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>VG2-N-PWS-4-SUMM-SA-48SEC-V1.0</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-PWS-4-SUMM-SA-48SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
        <Description>The Document describing the Contents of the Collection.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PWS/Neptune/PT48S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-PWS-4-SUMM-SA-48SEC-V1.0</URL>
        <ProductKey>VG2-N-PWS-4-SUMM-SA-48SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
        <Description>This Collection is archived with NASA Planetary Data System.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
      <Acknowledgement>NASA Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the Principal Investigator for the Data.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PWS</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1989-08-21T00:00:00.00</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1989-08-31T00:00:00.00</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT48S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
