<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_5_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.5.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://IUGONET/Instrument/RISH/misc/BDG/Radiosonde</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Radiosonde sounding at Bandung</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2016-07-21T16:23:00</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The radiosonde balloon sounding system at Bandung, Indonesia (6.89S, 107.59E, 740m MSL) measures the vertical profiles of pressure, temperature, humidity and horizontal wind in the lower atmosphere from the troposphere to lower stratosphere. The type of radiosonde used in this system is the Vaisala Radiosonde RS80 with an automatic signal processor (DigiCORA MW11). The TA1000 or TX1000 type of balloons made by the TOTEX corporation was used to obtain the vertical structure of the atmosphere up to ~30 km. In the observations using the Vaisala Radiosonde RS80 as a transmitter, the horizontal location of the balloons was measured by means of the GPS navigation. Then, the horizontal wind velocity is calculated from time derivative of the horizontal displacement of the balloon. In the CADRE campaign, the 411 balloons were released four times a day at 5, 11, 16, and 23 h (LT) during November 16, 1992 and April 10, 1993. After this campaign observation, about 900 balloons was continuously launched once a day from October 19, 1993 to March 11, 1996.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/Toshitaka.Tsuda</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://IUGONET/Person/RISH.Metadata.Management.Group</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>CADRE (Coupling and Dynamics in Regions Equatorial)</InvestigationName>
      <InvestigationName>MLTCS (Mesosphere Lower Thermoshere Coupling Study)</InvestigationName>
      <InvestigationName>RISH Radiosonde and Rawinsonde at Bandung (regular operation)</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://IUGONET/Observatory/RISH/misc/BDG</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
