<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_3.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.3</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Learmonth/Magnetometer</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Learmonth Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2020-11-13T20:35:01Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Learmonth Magnetometer station in Learmonth, WA, Australia, has a digital Magnetometer since March 1995. Up to today, there are four magnetometers monitored or still are monitoring in the staion. According to the station log files.

March 1995
----------
an AGSO Magnetometer located at Learmonth and the IPS data acquisition system was setup by John Kennewell (station code lem). Data is recorded on 3.5" floppy disks and sent to head office every 2 weeks. This data source should have a data type "b" as the data output from the instrument has no offset, but as the data is from the same instrument for which another data stream (lea) is given an offset during acquisition, the same data type code was used for this data stream. Data type: "c"

18 September, 1998
----------------
Data type: "b"
Magnetometer is a STEL instrument located at Learmonth and the IPS data acquisition system is handled by Maurice McMullan. Data is sent monthly to the  ASFC on zip disk. Some months missing due to cyclone.

8 February, 1999
----------------
Data ceased:
The AGSO instrument failed on February 11 and the last floppy disk sent had data up to and including February 8. 

28 October, 1999
----------------
Data type: "e"
Software upgraded to use separate resolution parameters for each magnetometer
component.

25 February, 2003
-----------------
Data stream re-started, however, the data is now from the STEL instrument and is received via ftp across the IPS network. The data acquisition system is the same
as used at other IPS magnetometer sites. Data type:  e
(RAM)

16 Feb, 2006
------------
Data commenced being FTP'd from Geoscience Australia to IPS. The sensor and data acquisition systems are GA owned and operated. The incoming files to IPS are in IAGA-2002 format and are GA's preliminary format. The incoming data files  total field values and are converted to IPS format. Data type: G.
 
*Note:  There were several streams of data from Learmonth from 2 different magnetometers. One magnetometer was an AGSO instrument and the other was a STEL instrument. Different station abreviations were used as the data streams had different sample frequencies or resolutions, although at times the data streams were redundant but sent for comparisons. The AGSO instrument provided data which was sent hourly via phone to the ASFC (lea) and more rapidly sampled data was sent on floppy disks to the ASFC on a fortnightly basis (lem). The floppy disks ceased being sent to the ASFC following the failure of the AGSO instrument on 11th  February, 1999. The AGSO instrument was replaced on 19 February, 1999 and continued to send "lea" data however, the rapidly sampled data from Learmonth was then received only from the STEL instrument on a monthly basis on zip disks (lth). Pulsation indices were also generated from the STEL magnetometer locally and sent to the ASFC via phone on an hourly basis (lmt).
(RAM - 11/11/99)
     
For more information, please read its log file.     
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ASWS Learmonth Instrument Fluxgate Magenetometer (ICSWSE) Log File</Name>
	<URL>ftp://ftp-out.sws.bom.gov.au/wdc/wdc_mag/data/lem/stn.log</URL>
	<Description>includes Learmonth magnetometer log file.</Description>
	<Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/Learmonth/Magnetometer</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/IAGA/Learmonth/Magnetometer</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Learmonth Magnetometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Learmonth</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
