<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.7.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <MetadataRightsList>
    <Rights>
      <SchemeURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/</SchemeURI>
      <RightsIdentifierScheme>SPDX</RightsIdentifierScheme>
      <RightsIdentifier>CC0-1.0</RightsIdentifier>
      <RightsURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC0-1.0.html</RightsURI>
      <RightsName>Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal</RightsName>
      <Note>CC0 1.0 Universal is the Creative Commons license applicable to all publicly available SPASE metadata descriptions</Note>
    </Rights>
  </MetadataRightsList>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/SDO/HMI/Synoptic/LOS_Magnetic_Field_Small</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>NASA</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>NumericalData</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Small Synoptic Charts of the Line-of-Sight Component of the Photospheric Magnetic Field</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.48322/sjvb-rb76</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:31:26Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2024-11-01T00:08:46</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Metadata created by SY</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2024-11-18T00:08:46</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added DOI by SY</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-09-18T11:27:09Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Changed http to https in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Fixed version number separator in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Matched version number in schemaLocation attribute to updated value in Version tag. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-09-30T14:25:18Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Updated PublishedBy name to match ROR Registry. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:31:26Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added MetadataRightsList. Updated to 2.7.1. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>This map is produced by applying a boxcar average to the high-resolution line-of-sight synoptic map, hmi.Synoptic_Ml_720s.

Synoptic charts are maps of the entire Sun produced in Carrington coordinates. Synoptic maps are constructed by merging together solar observations taken over many days. Magnetic-field synoptic charts are produced using central meridian data from HMI full-disk magnetograms.

Synoptic maps are constructed from HMI 720s line-of-sight Magnetograms collected over a 27-day solar rotation. Near-central-meridian data from 20 magnetograms contribute to each point in the final map.

HMI 720s line-of-sight magnetograms are first converted to 'radial field magnetograms' by dividing by the cosine of the angle from disk center, i.e. for this purpose we assume that HMI measures the line-of-sight component of a purely radial magnetic field. Individual 'radial' magnetograms are then remapped and interpolated onto a very high-resolution Carrington coordinate grid. For each Carrington longitude the values from the 20 magnetograms obtained closest in time to the central meridian passage (CMP) of that longitude are averaged. By using a constant number of contributing magnetograms, the variation of the noise over the entire map is minimized. Generally all data are taken within about 2 degrees of CMP. The effective temporal width of the HMI synoptic map contribution is about three hours, i.e. 20 720-s magnetograms are obtained within about 90 minutes of central meridian passage. The final HMI synoptic maps have a size of 3600 x 1440, which means the resolution is lower than the disk-center resolution of a single HMI magnetogram. A two-dimensional Gaussian function is applied to high-resolution remapped data to reduce the spatial resolution before generating the 3600*1440 synoptic maps. The width of the Gaussian is 3 pixels. The upper limit of the noise is 2.3 Mx cm2.</Description>
      <PublicationInfo>
        <Authors>The HMI Consortium: Stanford University (USA); NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (USA); Lockheed Martin Solar and Astrophysics Laboratory (USA); National Center for Atmospheric Research (USA)</Authors>
        <PublicationDate>2011-01-21T00:00:00</PublicationDate>
        <PublishedBy>Stanford University</PublishedBy>
      </PublicationInfo>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Philip.H.Scherrer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Rick.Bogart</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>The HMI website at Stanford</Name>
        <URL>http://hmi.stanford.edu/</URL>
      </InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>The SDO/HMI Instrument paper</Name>
        <URL>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11207-011-9834-2</URL>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/Stanford/HMI-AIA.JSOC</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>JSOC Data Center</Name>
        <URL>http://jsoc.stanford.edu/ajax/lookdata.html?ds=hmi.mrsynop_small_720s</URL>
        <Style>Search</Style>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>FITS</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/SDO/HMI</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Magnetogram</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>2010-05-19T23:59:06</StartDate>
        <RelativeStopDate>-P28D</RelativeStopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>P27D</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Sun</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Sun.Photosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <InputResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/SDO/HMI/LOS_Magnetogram/PT720S</InputResourceID>
    <InputResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/SDO/HMI/Synoptic/LOS_Magnetic_Field</InputResourceID>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>FITS Data Array</Name>
      <Description>Line-Of-Sight component of the photospheric magnetic field for an observer located at the solar equator</Description>
      <Units>gauss</Units>
      <Field>
        <FieldQuantity>Magnetic</FieldQuantity>
      </Field>
      <SpatialCoverage>
        <CoordinateSystem>
          <CoordinateRepresentation>Cartesian</CoordinateRepresentation>
          <CoordinateSystemName>Carrington</CoordinateSystemName>
        </CoordinateSystem>
        <Description>The maps are 720 points in Carrington longitude by 360 points equally spaced in sine latitude.</Description>
      </SpatialCoverage>
    </Parameter>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
