<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PRA/Uranus/PT0.60S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Uranus PRA Edited RDR High Rate 60-ms V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
This data set (VG2-U-PRA-2-RDR-HIGHRATE-60MS-V1.0) contains data              
acquired by the Voyager-2 Planetary Radio Astronomy (PRA) instrument          
during the Uranus encounter.  Since the PRA instrument is able to             
observe planetary phenomenon at much larger ranges than other fields          
and particles experiments, thus the PRA data cover a variable and             
longer encounter period. PRA lowband data provided here cover the             
entire Uranus Encounter Phase (1985-10-24 to 1988-07-14).                     
                                                                              
Each file within the dataset represents a single PRA high rate frame,         
of duration 48 seconds. Each file contains a 28 octet header, followed        
by 1280000 octets of data.                                                    
                                                                              
The header format is described as below:                                      
--------------------------------------------------------------------          
Length (bytes) Name            Contents                                       
--------------------------------------------------------------------          
2              Year            Year A.D.                                      
2              Day             Day of year (1 Jan == 1)                       
1              Hour            Hour of day (midnight == 0)                    
1              Minute          Minute of hour (o&apos;clock = 0)                   
1              Second          Second of Minute                               
                                 (exact minute == 0)                          
1              Spacecraft      1 == V1, 2 == V2                               
2              Integral FDS    Integer part of FDS count                      
1              Fractional FDS  Fractional part of FDS count                   
4              Freq. 1         Frequency of 1st channel (Hz)                  
4              Freq. 2         Frequency of 2nd channel (Hz)                  
4              Freq. 3         Frequency of 3rd channel (Hz)                  
4              Freq. 4         Frequency of 4th channel (Hz)                  
1              Bandwidth       Bandwidth (kHz)                                
--------------------------------------------------------------------          
where all values are unsigned, and multi-octet values are presented           
with the most significant byte first.                                         
                                                                              
The data are 16 bit numbers, most significant byte first, with 0              
indicating unavailable data. The data are presented as a single               
stream of 16 bit numbers. The frame is logically divided into lines           
(although there is no indication of the lines within the file). This          
terminology comes from the fact that in this high rate mode, the PRA          
data are treated exactly as if they were imaging data, and a 48 second        
image comprises 800 horizontal scan lines. Similarly, there are 800           
logical lines within a PRA frame. Each line comprises 800 values,             
representing 400 data pairs. In the high rate mode, the PRA measures          
the flux at two frequencies _simultaneously_ and returns these two data       
sequentially. A sample pair is acquired every (actually every 138.88...       
microseconds), through an RC filter with a 100 microsecond time constant.     
A single line comprises 60 milliseconds of data. Lines are NOT contiguous     
in time. There is a 4444.44... microsecond gap between the ending of one      
line and the start of the succeeding line.                                    
                                                                              
The PRA samples a frequency pair in this manner for 24 seconds. It then       
has the option of switching to a second pair for the final 24 seconds.        
These frequencies are designated Freq. 1 through Freq. 4 in the header.       
The data are presented such that the higher of the relevant frequency         
pair is presented first.                                                    
                                                                              
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_NAME        = TIME
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_RESOLUTION  = N/A
    MINIMUM_SAMPLING_PARAMETER     = N/A
    MAXIMUM_SAMPLING_PARAMETER     = N/A
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_INTERVAL    = 138.8
    MINIMUM_AVAILABLE_SAMPLING_INT = 138.8
    SAMPLING_PARAMETER_UNIT        = MICROSECOND
    DATA_SET_PARAMETER_NAME        = RADIO WAVE SPECTRUM
    NOISE_LEVEL                    = 2400
    DATA_SET_PARAMETER_UNIT        = MILLIBEL</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-U-PRA-2-RDR-HIGHRATE-60MS-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-U-PRA-2-RDR-HIGHRATE-60MS-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-U-PRA-2-RDR-HIGHRATE-60MS-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-U-PRA-2-RDR-HIGHRATE-60MS-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PRA</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1985-10-24T23:23:12.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1988-07-14T07:43:09.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT0.60S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Uranus</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
