<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <Version>2.2.6</Version>
    <NumericalData>
        <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/STPSat1/SHIMMER/OH/PT1D</ResourceID>
        <ResourceHeader>
            <ResourceName>STPSat-1 SHIMMER OH Data</ResourceName>
            <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:15:23Z</ReleaseDate>
            <Description> This dataset contains daily averaged mesospheric hydroxyl (OH) radiance profiles of solar resonance fluorescence measured near 309 nm by the Spatial Heterodyne Imager for MEsospheric Radicals (SHIMMER) onboard STPSat-1. OH data were obtained by imaging the limb every 20 s between 58°N and 58°S. These radiance profiles were inverted to retrieve daily averaged mesospheric OH densities between 60 and 90 km in 2 km increments. A total of 1816 OH profiles are available, 881 from the ascending (A) portion of the orbit and 935 from the descending (D) portion of the orbit. Because the satellite is moving eastward at latitudes between 50°N and 58°N, the profiles from the A portion are about 3 hours earlier in local solar time than the D portion in this latitude band. The OH number density profile data are stored in directories for the tropics ("0_to_15N") and for the mid-latitudes ("50N_to_58N"). See SHIMMER Data Manual for a list of missing days. They are available in ASCII format in 5 columns: altitude, OH densities, uncertainty in the OH densities (1 &#x3c3;), OH radiances (uninverted intensities along the line of sight), and uncertainty in the OH radiances. 

In addition, there are "showstat" summary plots, in postscript files, with relevant viewing conditions for each of the six data periods (either tropics or mid-latitudes for each of the three years). Each of the figures has 6 panels that include a) Number of spectra obtained on each day, b) Solar zenith angle (SZA), c) Solar scattering angle (SSA), d) Latitude of the limb tangent point, e) Local solar time (LST) at the tangent point, and f) Altitude range of the limb observation (nominally 35-100 km, on occasion as high as 65-130 km).</Description>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christoph.Englert</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            </Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.E.Siskind</PersonID>
                <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
            </Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>Users Guide to Data from the Spatial Heterodyne Imager for MEsospheric Radicals (SHIMMER)</Name>
                <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/shimmer/shimmer_data_manual.pdf</URL>
            </InformationURL>
            <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/STPSat1/SHIMMER/OH/PT1D</PriorID>
        </ResourceHeader>
        <AccessInformation>
            <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF</RepositoryID>
            <Availability>Online</Availability>
            <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>FTPS from SPDF (not with most browsers)</Name>
                <URL>ftps://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/shimmer/oh_data/</URL>
                <Description>In ASCII via ftp at SPDF</Description>
            </AccessURL>
            <AccessURL>
                <Name>HTTPS from SPDF</Name>
                <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/data/shimmer/oh_data/</URL>
                <Description>In ASCII via HTTP at SPDF</Description>
            </AccessURL>
            <Format>Text</Format>
            <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the PI and NASA GSFC SPDF.</Acknowledgement>
        </AccessInformation>
        <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
        <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/STPSat1/SHIMMER</InstrumentID>
        <MeasurementType>Radiance</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>2007-04-05T00:00:00</StartDate>
                <StopDate>2009-09-24T00:00:00</StopDate>
            </TimeSpan>
            <Cadence>PT24H</Cadence>
        </TemporalDescription>
        <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Mesosphere</ObservedRegion>
    </NumericalData>
</Spase>
