<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/Wind/WAVES</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Wind WAVES</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-04-26T09:29:49Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The WAVES experiment exploits instrumentation developed joinlty by the Observatoire de Paris-Meudon, the University of Minnesota, and the Goddard Space Flight Center. The Radio and Plasma WAVES investigation on the WIND spacecraft provides comprehensive coverage of radio and plasma wave phenomena in the frequency range from a fraction of a Hertz up to about 14 MHz for the electric field and 3 kHz for the magnetic field. This package permits several kinds of measurements all of which are essential to understanding the Earth's environment - the Geospace - and its response to varying solar wind conditions. In situ measurements of different modes of plasma waves give information on local processes and couplings in different regions and boundaries of the Geospace leading to plasma instabilities: magneto-acoustic waves, ion cyclotron waves, whistler waves, electron plasma oscillations, electron burst noise and other types of electrostatic or electromagnetic waves.

The sensors are:

-    three electric dipolar antenna systems supplied by Fairchild Space (two are coplanar, orthogonal wire dipole antennas in the spin-plane, the other a rigid spin-axis dipole), and

-    three magnetic search coils mounted orthogonally (designed and built by the University of Iowa).

After preamplification, the sensor outputs are routed to the analysis electronics, consisting of a low frequency (DC - 10 kHz) FFT receiver, a broadband (4 kHz - 256 kHz) multi-channel analyzer designed principally to study the electron thermal noise, two dual radio receivers covering the band 20 kHz to 13.825 MHz, and a time-domain waveform sampler (sampling to 120,000/s).

The experiment is controlled by a central microprocessor (DPU) which is used in flight to reconfigure the sensor outputs and to maximize the science return for the bit rate and power allotments that are available. A DC/DC power converter is also part of the electronics stack.

WAVES is divided into five subsystems:

-    Low Frequency FFT Receiver (FFT),

-    Thermal Noise Receiver (TNR),

-    Radio Receiver Band 1 (RAD1),

-    Radio Receiver Band 2 (RAD2),

-    Time Domain Sampler (TDS).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Karine.Issautier</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Sang.Hoang</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Keith.Goetz</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Keith.Goetz</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Xavier.Bonnin</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>WaveformReceiver</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma and Radio Waves (WAVES) on Wind</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/Wind</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
