<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Instrument>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/ROSETTA/RPC_MIP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Rosetta Plasma Consortium- Mutual Impedance Probe</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-06-02T15:00:58Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Instrument Overview

The Mutual Impedance Probe instrument (RPC-MIP) is part of the set of Rosetta orbiter instruments known as the Rosetta Plasma Consortium (RPC).
The purpose of the RPC-MIP instrument is to provide several plasma parameters, derived from measurements, such as the electron plasma density.
RPC-MIP is composed of an electric antenna and a HF analyser. The RPC-MIP antenna comprises two receivers and two transmitters, supported by a conductive bar. This antenna is mounted on the upper boom of the spacecraft.
Scientific Objectives

The RPC-MIP instrument measures the electrical coupling between a transmitting antenna and a receiving antenna. From the on-ground analysis of the mutual impedance frequency spectra acquires on-board and depending on plasma conditions, one may retrieve the electron plasma density and potentially the electron temperature. In its passive mode, this instrument has also the capability of a plasma wave analyser. It is therefore used to detect the electric fields of electrostatic and electromagnetic waves.

Combining measurements from different instruments, for instance RPC-MIP and RPC-LAP enables to better constrain bulk plasma parameters such as the electron temperature and, under certains hypothesis, the ion bulk velocity.
Measured Parameters

An alternating current, I, with a frequency lying in a programmed or pre-defined frequency range hopefully containing the plasma frequency, is driven through a transmitting electrode. The induced difference in voltage, V, measured on open circuit between two receiving electrodes is fed into a high input impedance amplifier.
The mutual impedance, Z, is equal to the ratio of V to I. As Z depends essentially on the properties of the surrounding plasma, the frequency response of the mutual impedance probe may be used for plasma diagnosis. Due to the resistive, capacitive, and/or inductive nature of the plasma, the frequency response has both real and imaginary components that provide valuable insights into the plasma characteristics. In the active mode, the electron density of the ionized outflowing atmosphere can be determined from the shapes of the real and imaginary parts of the RPC-MIP frequency response. In the passive mode, when no current is injected through the transmitting electrode, the sensor is actually a receiving electric antenna. It detects natural waves, and impulsive signals, generated in the surrounding plasma by external phenomena (not associated to any transmission from the RPC-MIP experiment). 

References
RPC-MIP: the Mutual Impedance Probe of the Rosetta Plasma Consortium, Space Science Reviews, Volume 128, Issue 1-4, pp.713-728, doi:10.1007/s11214-006-9005-1
The MIP Experiment of the Rosetta Orbiter: a Mutual Impedance Probe for Waves and Plasmas Diagnosis, Advances in Geosciences. Volume 15: Planetary Science (PS). Published by World Scientific. ISBN #978-981-2836-22-9, 2009, pp.323-341, doi:10.1142/9789812836229_0020</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Pierre.Henri</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Rosetta Plasma Consortium- Mutual Impedance Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/ROSETTA</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument>
</Spase>
