<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.4.0</Version>
   <NumericalData>
      <ResourceID>spase://GBO/NumericalData/RadioJOVE/AJ4CO/TFD-TWB/PT0.0002S</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Radio JOVE AJ4CO TFD Array and Tunable Wideband Receiver Spectrograph Data</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2022-02-19T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2022-02-19T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>RadioJOVE: Resource Header Description reformated, One URL corrected for // typo in some files. Metadata submitted by J.M. Weygand on 2021-11-08, reviewed by LFB</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>This dataset consists of 2 MHz wide very-high time resolution spectrograms in Right or Left Circular Polarization tunable from 16-32 MHz. These observations were made at the AJ4CO Observatory using a Terminated Folded Dipole (TFD) Array and a Tunable Wideband Receiver system. The system provides either Right Circularly Polarized (RCP) or Left Circularly Polarized (LCP) data. These data are generated using the Radio-Sky Spectrograph Software.

These data may include observations of Solar Radio Bursts, Jupiter decametric radio emission, or Galactic Background radio emission. In particular these data enable studies of fine-structure in Jovian decametric S-bursts.

The Radio-SkyPipe produced datafiles consist of a fixed length header and a variable length note. The data portion of the file for one channel of data consists of an 8 byte timestamp using the VisualBasic 6 date format (days since 1 Jan 1900) followed by one 8 byte data value (Channel 1), this pattern repeats until the end of file. More details on the format of Radio-Sky Spectrograph datafiles can be found in the Data File Structure document on the Radio-SkyPipe help page (see Information URL).</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.Typinski</PersonID>
            <Role>DataProducer</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jim.Sky</PersonID>
            <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Leonard.N.Garcia</PersonID>
            <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Radio Jove Spectrograph Users Group (SUG)</Name>
            <URL>http://radiojove.org/SUG/</URL>
            <Description>Available at this site is a description of the Observatory facilities, a manual for the Dual Dipole antenna, and a guide to reading the binary data file produced by the Radio-SkyPipe software.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Radio Sky Publishing Radio-SkyPipe Help Page</Name>
            <URL>http://radiosky.com/skypipehelp/V2/datastructure.html</URL>
            <Description>The page &quot;Radio-SkyPipe data file structure&quot; describes the file standard.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>An Overview of the Radio JOVE Project</Name>
            <URL>https://radiojove.gsfc.nasa.gov/library/pubs/docs/RadioJoveSummary2014.pdf</URL>
            <Description>An Overview of the Radio JOVE Project–Summer 2014, Chuck Higgins, Middle Tennessee State University</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>AJ4CO Radio Astronomy Publications</Name>
            <URL>https://www.aj4co.org/Publications/Publications.html</URL>
            <Description>This site provides descriptions of radio receiver systems at AJ4CO as well as other radio astronomy-related documentation</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>AJ4CO Miscellaneous Data</Name>
            <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/radiojove/radiojove-aj4co/radiojove-aj4co-misc-data/</URL>
            <Description>This site provides descriptions of radio receiver systems at AJ4CO, observation logs and other documentation. The radiojove-aj4co-twb also contains subdirectories with additional observation logs.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/RadioJOVE</RepositoryID>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>Radio JOVE Data Archive</Name>
            <URL>http://radiojove.org/archive.html</URL>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>Binary</Format>
      </AccessInformation>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>Tunable Wideband Receiver AJ4CO Radio-Sky Spectrograph data held at the Planetary Plasma Interactions node of the Planetary Data System</Name>
            <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/radiojove/radiojove-aj4co/radiojove-aj4co-twb/</URL>
         </AccessURL>
         <Format>Binary</Format>
      </AccessInformation>
      <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/AJ4CO/TFD-TWB</InstrumentID>
      <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
      <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
   </NumericalData>
</Spase>
