<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <DisplayData>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/DisplayData/CDPP-Archive/Ulysses/URAP/ULS_URAP_RAR_G2_PIT</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ulysses/URAP daily intensity time profiles (Postscript)</ResourceName>
      <DOI>https://doi.org/10.24400/802406/apga-s25m</DOI>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-05-09T16:26:08Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This  dataset contains daily plots of the URAP radio data (intensity time profiles) in the whole nominal range of 76 frequencies, from 1.25 to 940 kHz. They are produced from the 192-s averaged data measured in SFU (solar flux units) : 1 SFU = 10^-22 W/m2/Hz.
There exist data gaps caused by missing data, telemetry errors, or by in-flight internal calibrations or URAP Sounder operations. Those with a duration less than 5 data will be filled up by linear interpolation. This results in a better identification of solar radio activity.
In some occasions, changes in the receiver mode or frequency list may lead to a lesser number (than 76) of observing frequencies. Missing consecutive frequencies, when less than 3, will be filled up by linear interpolation in the dynamic spectra. But they will not be plotted for the Intensity Time Profiles.
*Background Subtractions
One important item to be considered in the plots is the background level and subtraction from the data. For each frequency, the background level used is the lowest 1% of the data within the time interval considered (1 day, 7 days or 27 days).
In the plots  using a logarithmic scale, the data are displayed in units of log10 (total power/background power) with power in SFU.
Each frequency level is presented above a (dotted) horizontal line, indicated by the frequency in kHz and the background level in SFU.
It is worth noting that this type of background determination and subtraction will nearly remove any signal at a given frequency that is constant throughout the plot, e.g., 1 day. Examples are the plasma thermal noise background and onboard radio frequency interference levels.
*Spacecraft Location
In the plots, at the lower left, the spacecraft location at the start time of the plot is given, from left to right, as heliodistance in AU, heliolatitude (positive for North) and heliolongitude (with respect to Earth, positive for West) in degrees. In addition, for the periods around the close (8 Feb. 1992) and far (5 Feb. 2004) encounters with Jupiter, it is also given in Jovian coordinates, as jovidistance in AU and latitude in degrees (positive for North) with respect to Jupiter's magnetic dipole.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Robert.MacDowall</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Sang.Hoang</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Karine.Issautier</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/CDPP.general.contact</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://CNES/Repository/CDPP-Archive/REGARDS-CDPP</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>REGARDS</Name>
        <URL>https://cdpp-archive.cnes.fr</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Postscript</Format>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://CNES/Instrument/CDPP-Archive/Ulysses/URAP</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>ElectricField</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1990-11-03T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
        <StopDate>2007-11-26T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Sun.Corona</ObservedRegion>
  </DisplayData>
</Spase>
