<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_9.xsd">
   <Version>2.2.9</Version>
   <NumericalData>
      <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sectored/PT10M</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Ulysses Cosmic Ray and Solar Particle Investigation (COSPIN) High Energy Telescope (HET) Ion and Electron Eight-Sectored Coincidence Counting Rates in ASCII Format, 10 min Data</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>COSPIN-HET-SECTORED-RATES-PT10M</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:15:40Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>This Data Set contains 10 min Average Ion and Electron Eight-Sectored Coincidence Counting Rates from the COSPIN High Energy Telescope (HET). These Data provide a Measure of the Anisotropy of Particle Arrival Directions in the Spacecraft Spin Plane</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge R. Bruce McKibben, Space Science Center, University of New Hampshire</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/R.Bruce.McKibben</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
            <Role>DataProducer</Role>
</Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.Connell</PersonID>
            <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ming.Zhang</PersonID>
            <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Cecil.Tranquille</PersonID>
            <Role>ArchiveSpecialist</Role>
</Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>The Ulysses Cosmic Ray and Solar Particle Investigation, COSPIN</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#instruments</URL>
            <Description>Published Description of the COSPIN Instrumentation, J.A. Simpson et al., Astron. Astrophys. Suppl. Ser. 92, 365-399, 1992. See especially Section 4.3 for a detailed Description of the High Energy Telescopes, HET. An electronic Copy of this Paper is available at http://adsbit.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-iarticle_query?1992A%26AS...92..365S&amp;defaultprint=YES&amp;filetype=.pdf.</Description>
</InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>User Notes for the COSPIN/HET Data Files</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa-sl-server/data-action?PROTOCOL=HTTP&amp;PRODUCT_TYPE=ALL&amp;FILE_NAME=het_usernotes.pdf&amp;FILE_PATH=/ufa/HiRes/doc/cospin</URL>
            <Description>The User Notes File at the Ulysses Final Archive (UFA) describes the Format of the ASCII Data Files for the COSPIN High Energy Telescope, HET, 10 min Average Ion and Electron Eight-Sectored Counting Rates</Description>
</InformationURL>
         <Association>
            <AssociationID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/SpinAveraged/PT10M</AssociationID>
            <AssociationType>PartOf</AssociationType>
</Association>
         <PriorID>spase://VEPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Sectored-Rates/PT10M</PriorID>
          <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET/Rates/Sectored/PT10M</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
      <AccessInformation>
         <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/ESA/ESAC/UlyssesFinalArchive</RepositoryID>
         <Availability>Online</Availability>
         <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
         <AccessURL>
            <Name>Ulysses Final Archive Access to COSPIN/HET 10 min Average Ion and Electron Eight-Sectored Coincidence Counting Rates</Name>
            <URL>http://ufa.esac.esa.int/ufa/#data</URL>
            <Description>Parent Directory containing compressed Archives with Naming Convention coshetaYY.zip, where YY indicates the two digit Year corresponding to the Data in the File. Each Archive contains Daily ASCII Files with Naming Convention ucoshetrYYDDD.uly where YY and DOY are the two digit Year and the three digit Day of Year (January 1 = 1) containing COSPIN/HET nominally 10 min Averages of the Eight-Sectored Counting Rates H45S and H7S, which, as described in individual Description Fields, respond primarily to Protons (H45S) in the Energy Range 34-92 MeV and to Electrons (H7S) in the approximate Energy Range 5-10 MeV. The actual Accumulation Intervals contributing to an Average consist of an Integral Number of Telemetry Subcomm Sequences, and correspond to all Subcomm Sequences which start in the nominal 10 min reporting Interval. The minimum Time corresponding to one Subcomm Sequence is 256 s at 1024 bps, the most Common Science Telemetry Rate. Thus the actual Start Time of the Accumulation may be up to 256 s later than the Start Time of the Nominal Interval. Similarly, the End Time of the Accumulation may extend up to 256 s beyond the End of the Nominal Interval. These Data are therefore not useful for highly accurate Timing Studies.</Description>
</AccessURL>
         <Format>Text</Format>
         <Encoding>ZIP</Encoding>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge R. Bruce McKibben, Space Science Center, University of New Hampshire</Acknowledgement>
</AccessInformation>
      <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ulysses/COSPIN/HET</InstrumentID>
      <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
      <TemporalDescription>
         <TimeSpan>
            <StartDate>1990-10-22T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
            <StopDate>2009-06-10T23:59:59.999</StopDate>
</TimeSpan>
         <Cadence>PT10M</Cadence>
</TemporalDescription>
      <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.Outer</ObservedRegion>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Time for the record</Name>
         <ParameterKey>Time_PG1</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Nominal Start Time for the average given in Year, Day of Year, Hour, Minute, and Seconds.</Description>
         <Cadence>PT10M</Cadence>
         <Structure>
            <Size>5</Size>
            <Element>
               <Name>Year</Name>
               <Index>1</Index>
               <ValidMin>1990</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>2008</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Day of Year</Name>
               <Index>2</Index>
               <ValidMin>1</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>366</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Hour of Day</Name>
               <Index>3</Index>
               <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>23</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Minute of Hour</Name>
               <Index>4</Index>
               <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>59</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>Seconds of Minute</Name>
               <Index>5</Index>
               <ValidMin>0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>59</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
</Structure>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
</Support>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET 10-Minute Average Proton Counting Rate H45S</Name>
         <ParameterKey>H45S</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Nominal 10-minute average HET counting rate normally responding primarily to protons between 34 and 92 MeV in spin sectors 1-8. The rate has 8 elements, each corresponding to a 45&#176; range of the spacecraft spin plane. The start of sector 1 (0&#176;) is coincident with the spacecraft-generated Sun-pulse, and the start of each subsequent sector is shifted by 45&#176; with respect to the preceding sector. For example, H45S1 covers the azimuthal range 0&#176; to 45&#176;, H45S2 covers the azimuthal range 45&#176; to 90&#176;, etc. In each sector, counts are registered only when the Axis of the Telescope view cone is within that sector. Rate channel H45S is a coincidence counting rate requiring coincident signals in detectors at least as deep in the stack as K1 (D7), and no signals from detectors deeper in the stack than K6 (D12). Data from multiple spacecraft spins contribute to the counting rates recorded for each sector, and the total accumulation time for the set of H45S1-H45S8 rates is required to be an integral number of spacecraft spins. Therefore the total accumulation time in each of the 8 sectors is 1/8 of the total time interval for the average.</Description>
         <Caveats>Since counts are registered based only on energy loss exceeding a certain threshold, there may in addition from time to time be significant contamination from high fluxes of high energy electrons. Nuclei with Z&gt;1 with equivalent penetrating power to the protons in the nominal energy range are also counted, but rarely make significant contributions to the rate. The timing of the accumulation intervals is not commensurate with the nominal 10 minute grid. Counting rates reported here have a minimum time resolution of one telemetry subcomm sequence (256 s at 1024 bps, the most common science telemetry rate). The actual start time of the accumulation may therefore be up to 255 s later than the start time of the nominal interval. Similarly, the end time of the accumulation may extend up to 255 s beyond the end of the nominal interval.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT10M</Cadence>
         <Structure>
            <Size>8</Size>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S1</Name>
               <Index>1</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S2</Name>
               <Index>2</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S3</Name>
               <Index>3</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S4</Name>
               <Index>4</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S5</Name>
               <Index>5</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S6</Name>
               <Index>6</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S7</Name>
               <Index>7</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H45S8</Name>
               <Index>8</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
</Structure>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Proton</ParticleType>
            <Qualifier>Average</Qualifier>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>34</Low>
               <High>92</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>COSPIN/HET 10-Minute Average Proton Counting Rate H7S</Name>
         <ParameterKey>H7S</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Nominal 10-minute average HET counting rate normally responding primarily to electrons between 5 and 10 MeV in spin sectors 1-8. The start of sector 1 (0&#176;) is coincident with the spacecraft-generated Sun-pulse, and the start of each subsequent sector is shifted by 45&#176; with respect to the preceding sector. For example, H45S1 covers the azimuthal range 0&#176; to 45&#176;, H45S2 covers the azimuthal range 45&#176; to 90&#176;, etc. In each sector, counts are registered only when the Axis of the Telescope view cone is within that sector. Counting rate H7S requires coincident but small signals in D1 and D2, as well as energy losses in detectors at least as deep in the stack as K1 (D7), with no losses registered in K4 (D10) or detectors deeper in the stack. Electrons are identified by requiring low energy losses, consistent with a minimum ionizing particle, in the front detectors, D1 and D2, of the HET, and, at the same time, a limited range in the detector stack. The counting rate logic thus strongly discriminates against contamination from nuclei of any charge. Data from multiple spacecraft spins contribute to the counting rates recorded for each sector, and the total accumulation time for the set of H7S1-H7S8 rates is required to be an integral number of spacecraft spins. Therefore the total accumulation time in each of the 8 sectors is 1/8 of the total time interval for the average.</Description>
         <Caveats>The timing of the accumulation intervals is not commensurate with the nominal 10 minute grid. Counting rates reported here have a minimum time resolution of one telemetry subcomm sequence (256 s at 1024 bps, the most common science telemetry rate). The actual start time of the accumulation may therefore be up to 255 s later than the start time of the nominal interval. Similarly, the end time of the accumulation may extend up to 255 s beyond the end of the nominal interval.</Caveats>
         <Cadence>PT10M</Cadence>
         <Structure>
            <Size>8</Size>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S1</Name>
               <Index>1</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S2</Name>
               <Index>2</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S3</Name>
               <Index>3</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S4</Name>
               <Index>4</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S5</Name>
               <Index>5</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S6</Name>
               <Index>6</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S7</Name>
               <Index>7</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>H7S8</Name>
               <Index>8</Index>
               <Units></Units>
               <ValidMin>0.0</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>1000000</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>-1.000E+00</FillValue>
</Element>
</Structure>
         <Particle>
            <ParticleType>Electron</ParticleType>
            <Qualifier>Average</Qualifier>
            <ParticleQuantity>Counts</ParticleQuantity>
            <EnergyRange>
               <Low>5</Low>
               <High>10</High>
               <Units>MeV</Units>
</EnergyRange>
</Particle>
</Parameter>
      <Parameter>
         <Name>Floating Point Time for the record</Name>
         <ParameterKey>FP_Time</ParameterKey>
         <Description>Time for the record given as Floating Point Year since 1900 and Floating point Day of Year. The given time represents the beginning of the nominal averaging interval.</Description>
         <Cadence>PT10M</Cadence>
         <Structure>
            <Size>2</Size>
            <Element>
               <Name>FP Year</Name>
               <Index>1</Index>
               <ValidMin>90.800</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>108.99999</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
            <Element>
               <Name>FP Day of Year</Name>
               <Index>2</Index>
               <ValidMin>1</ValidMin>
               <ValidMax>366.999</ValidMax>
               <FillValue>Null</FillValue>
</Element>
</Structure>
         <Support>
            <SupportQuantity>Temporal</SupportQuantity>
</Support>
</Parameter>
</NumericalData>
</Spase>
