<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema https://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2.7.1.xsd">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <MetadataRightsList>
    <Rights>
      <SchemeURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/</SchemeURI>
      <RightsIdentifierScheme>SPDX</RightsIdentifierScheme>
      <RightsIdentifier>CC0-1.0</RightsIdentifier>
      <RightsURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC0-1.0.html</RightsURI>
      <RightsName>Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal</RightsName>
      <Note>CC0 1.0 Universal is the Creative Commons license applicable to all publicly available SPASE metadata descriptions</Note>
    </Rights>
  </MetadataRightsList>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Jupiter/IonMoments/PT96S</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>NASA</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>NumericalData</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Jupiter Plasma Science (PLS) Derived Ion Moments, Version 1.1, 96 s Data</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:32:40Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:16:00Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:32:40Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added MetadataRightsList. Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Updated to 2.7.1. Changed http to https in top-level schemaLocation attribute. Fixed version number separator in top-level schemaLocation attribute. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>* Data Set Overview
* =================

* Version 1.1
* ===========

This Version 1.1 Data Set replaces the Version 1.0 Data Set (DATA_SET_ID = VG2-J-PLS-5-ION-MOM-96.0SEC) previously archived with the PDS. The old Version of the Data Set was given a new DATA_SET_ID and intentionally marked as V1.0.

* Data Set Description
* ====================

This Data Set contains the best Estimates of the total Ion Density from Voyager 2 at Jupiter in the PLS Voltage Range (10 eV/Q to 5950 eV/Q). It is calculated using the Method of (McNutt et al., 1981) which to first order consists of taking the total measured Current and dividing by the Collector Area and Plasma Bulk Velocity. This Method is only accurate for high Mach Number Flows directly into the Detector, and may result in Underestimates of the total Density of a Factor of 2 in the outer Magnetosphere. Thus absolute Densities should be treated with caution, but Density Variations in the Data Set can be trusted. The low resolution Mode Density is used at all times except Day 190 at 2100-2200 when the Larger of the high and low resolution Mode Densities in a 96 s period is used. Corotation is assumed inside L=17.5, and a constant Velocity Component of 200 km/s into the D Cup is used outside of this. These are the Densities given in the (McNutt et al., 1981) Paper corrected by a Factor of 1.209 (0.9617) for Densities obtained from the Side (Main) Sensor. This Correction is due to a better Calculation of the effective Area of the Sensors. Data Format: Column 1 is Time (yyyy-mm-ddThh:mm:ss.sssZ), Column 2 is the Moment Density in cm^-3. Each Row has Format (a24,1x,1pe9.2). Values of -9.99e+10 indicate that the Parameter could not be obtained from the Data using the standard Analysis Technique. Additional Information about this Data Set and the Instrument which produced it can be found elsewhere in this Catalog. An Overview of the Data in this Data Set can be found in (McNutt et al., 1981) and a complete Instrument Description can be found in (Bridge et al., 1977).

+----------------------------------+
| Data Set Characteristics | Value |
------------------------------------
| Processing Level ID      | 5     |
| Software Flag            | Y     |
+----------------------------------+

* Parameters
* ==========

* Ion Density
* ===========

+----------------------------------------------+
| Parameter Characteristics      | Value       |
------------------------------------------------
| Sampling Parameter Name        | TIME        |
| Data Set Parameter Name        | ION DENSITY |
| Sampling Parameter Resolution  | 96.000000   |
| Sampling Parameter Interval    | 96.000000   |
| Minimum Available Sampling Int | 96.000000   |
| Data Set Parameter Unit        | CM^-3       |
| Sampling Parameter Unit        | SECOND      |
+----------------------------------------------+

A derived Parameter equaling the Number of Ions per Unit Volume over a specified Range of Ion Energy, Energy per Charge, or Energy per Nucleon. Discrimination with regard to Mass and or Charge State is necessary to obtain this Quantity, however, Mass and Charge State are often assumed due to Instrument Limitations.

Many different Forms of Ion Density are derived. Some are distinguished by their Composition (N+, Proton, Ion, etc.) or their Method of Derivation (Maxwellian Fit, Method of Moments). In some cases, more than one Type of Density will be provided in a single Data Set. In general, if more than one Ion Species is analyzed, either by Moment or Fit, a total Density will be provided which is the Sum of the Ion Densities. If a Plasma Component does not have a Maxwellian Distribution the actual Distribution can be represented as the Sum of several Maxwellians, in which case the Density of each Maxwellian is given.

* Source Instrument Parameters
* ============================

+------------------------------------------------------------------+
| Source Instrument Characteristics | Value                        |
--------------------------------------------------------------------
| Instrument Host ID                | VG2                          |
| Data Set Parameter Name           | ION DENSITY                  |
| Instrument Parameter Name         | ION RATE                     |
|                                   | ION CURRENT                  |
|                                   | MULTIPLE PARTICLE PARAMETERS |
| Important Instrument Parameters   | 1 (for all Parameters)       |
+------------------------------------------------------------------+

* Processing
* ==========

* Processing History
* ==================</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
        <Description>The Document describing the Contents of the Collection.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Jupiter/PT96.0S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Jupiter/MMode/PT96S</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/Voyager2/PLS/Jupiter/IonMoments/PT96S</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
        <URL>https://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0</URL>
        <ProductKey>VG2-J-PLS-5-SUMM-ION-MOM-96.0SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
        <Description>This Collection is archived with NASA Planetary Data System.</Description>
        <Language>En</Language>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
      <Acknowledgement>NASA Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the Principal Investigator for the Data.</Acknowledgement>
    </AccessInformation>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/PLS</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1979-07-04T12:02:47.82</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1979-07-10T11:59:35.44</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT96S</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Jupiter</ObservedRegion>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
