<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
  <Version>2.7.1</Version>
  <MetadataRightsList>
    <Rights>
      <SchemeURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/</SchemeURI>
      <RightsIdentifierScheme>SPDX</RightsIdentifierScheme>
      <RightsIdentifier>CC0-1.0</RightsIdentifier>
      <RightsURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC0-1.0.html</RightsURI>
      <RightsName>Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal</RightsName>
      <Note>CC0 1.0 Universal is the Creative Commons license applicable to all publicly available SPASE metadata descriptions</Note>
    </Rights>
  </MetadataRightsList>
  <NumericalData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/NumericalData/ISEE1/DATA/PT1M</ResourceID>
    <NamingAuthority>NASA</NamingAuthority>
    <ResourceType>NumericalData</ResourceType>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE 1 Data Pool Set, offline at NSSDC</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:29:37Z</ReleaseDate>
      <RevisionHistory>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T21:14:39Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Only known prior ReleaseDate of the metadata</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
        <RevisionEvent>
          <ReleaseDate>2025-12-04T13:29:37Z</ReleaseDate>
          <Note>Added MetadataRightsList and RightsList(s). Added ResourceType and NamingAuthority. Updated to 2.7.1. ZCB</Note>
        </RevisionEvent>
      </RevisionHistory>
      <Description>This quick-look data pool data set contains selected physical parameters computed centrally for each instrument at resolutions between one and five minutes, using quick-look, PI-provided algorithms.  It was created in binary IBM 360 representation with unblocked, 3240-byte records. The first record of each file is a data pool file label containing satellite ID number; year, day of year, and seconds of day for the start and end of file; spacecraft clock; telemetry group number; minimum and maximum value of spin period found in this file; shadow times; and bit rate. The label record is followed by a number of data records containing day of year and seconds of day; s/c clock; bit rate; housekeeping and engineering items; spin period average; satellite position vector in GSE coordinates; and outputs of the investigators' quick-look data-processing algorithms for selected parameters from ten of the onboard experiments.  The fast plasma data (Gosling/LANL) include four-level electron spectra, ion pseudondensities, average energies, and solar wind peak speeds and pseudodensities, at 5-minute resolution.  The hot plasma (Frank, U. Iowa) algorithm outputs include proton densities, 10 keV electron fluxes, and energy range indicators, at 5-minute resolution.  The fluxgate magnetometer data (Russell, UCLA) include 25 hourly parameters, plus the components of the magnetic field in spacecraft coordinates, at 1-minute resolution.  The low-energy cosmic ray data (Hovestadt, MPI) include count rates of protons in three energy intervals between 0.17 and 20 MeV, plus those of alpha particles from 0.12 to 0.25 MeV and of Z&gt;2 particles above 0.1 MeV, at 15-second resolution.  The quasi-static electric field (Mozer, UCB) algorithm outputs indicate whether the experiment's electron guns were on or off during each 64-second interval.  The plasma wave data (Gurnett, U. Iowa) include instantaneous samples from the 562 Hz filter channels of the electron and magnetic spectrum analysers, at 5-minute resolution.  The plasma density data (Harvey, CESR) include indicators of the activity of the sounder and the propagation transmitters during each 64-second period.  The energetic electron and proton algorithm outputs (Williams, APL) include both electron and proton differential fluxes in the 32 to 50 keV and the 80 to 126 keV energy ranges. These fluxes are taken in or near the spin-normal (nominally ecliptic) plane, at 5-minute resolution.  The electron and proton experiment (K.Anderson, UCB) algorithm outputs include both electron and proton fluxes in the energy range 8 to 200 keV, at 5-minute resolution.  The ion composition data (Sharp, Lockheed) include the cold plasma density and flags indicating the presence of high ion temperatures and bulk flow in the plasma, at 5-minute resolution.  The Pool Tape Documentation (GSFC document X-692-77-129) (B29494 in NSSDC's Publications database) includes brief descriptions of the instruments, sometimes quite detailed, and also descriptions of the quick-look algorithms, also sometimes quite detailed.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/dataset/display.action?id=SPMS-00147</URL>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/SPMS-00147</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://VSPO/NumericalData/ISEE1/DATA/PT1M</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/NASA/GSFC/SPDF</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Offline</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <RightsList>
        <Rights>
          <SchemeURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/</SchemeURI>
          <RightsIdentifierScheme>SPDX</RightsIdentifierScheme>
          <RightsIdentifier>CC0-1.0</RightsIdentifier>
          <RightsURI>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC0-1.0.html</RightsURI>
          <RightsName>Creative Commons Zero v1.0 Universal</RightsName>
          <Note>CC0 1.0 Universal is the Creative Commons license applicable to all publicly available NASA Heliophysics data products</Note>
        </Rights>
      </RightsList>
      <AccessURL>
        <Name>NSSDC</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nssdc/obtaining_data.html</URL>
      </AccessURL>
      <Format>Binary</Format>
      <DataExtent>
        <Quantity>1</Quantity>
        <Units>GB</Units>
      </DataExtent>
    </AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/FPE</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/LEPEDEA</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/MAG</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/LFEF</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/UCB</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>ElectricField</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>EnergeticParticles</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>IonComposition</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>ThermalPlasma</MeasurementType>
    <TemporalDescription>
      <TimeSpan>
        <StartDate>1977-10-22T00:00:00</StartDate>
        <StopDate>1987-11-26T00:00:00</StopDate>
      </TimeSpan>
      <Cadence>PT1M</Cadence>
    </TemporalDescription>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <Caveats>These are preliminary data, typically recommended for event finding</Caveats>
  </NumericalData>
</Spase>
