<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager1/MAG/Saturn/PT48.0S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 1 Saturn Mag Resampled Heliographic (RTN) Coords 48.0-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
    Data Set Overview                                                         
    =================                                                         
                                                                              
    This data set includes calibrated magnetic field data acquired by         
    the Voyager 1 Low Field Magnetometer (LFM) during the Saturn              
    encounter. Coverage begins in the solar wind inbound to Saturn and        
    continues past the last outbound bowshock crossing. The data are in       
    Heliographic (RTN) coordinates and have been averaged from the 9.6        
    second summary rate to a 48 second sample rate. All magnetic field        
    measurements are given in nanoTesla (nT). The magnetic field data         
    are calibrated (see the calibration description included in the           
    Voyager 1 Magnetometer instrument catalog file for details).              
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Parameters                                                                
    ==========                                                                
                                                                              
    The full LFM instrument sample rate is 1 sample per 0.06 seconds.         
    Full telemetry resolution &apos;detail&apos; data must be obtained from the         
    instrument team. For this data set, the data have been resampled to       
    48 seconds from 9.6 second averages. The 9.6 second data were             
    resampled from 1.92 second averages which were in turn resampled          
    from the detail data.                                                     
                                                                              
    The LFM has eight dynamic ranges. The instrument is designed switch       
    between dynamic ranges automatically depending upon the observed          
    magnetic field magnitude and fluctuations. Instrument digitization        
    uncertainty depends upon dynamic range as indicated in the following      
    table (from [BEHANNONETAL1977]).                                          
                                                                              
    -----------------------------------------------                           
    LFM Dynamic ranges and quantization uncertainty                           
    -----------------------------------------------                           
    Range (nT)               Quantization (nT)                                
    -----------------------------------------------                           
    1.  +/- 8.8                    +/- .0022                                  
    2.  +/- 26                     +/- .0063                                  
    3.  +/- 79                     +/- .019                                   
    4.  +/- 240                    +/- .059                                   
    5.  +/- 710                    +/- .173                                   
    6.  +/- 2100                   +/- .513                                   
    7.  +/- 6400                   +/- 1.56                                   
    8.  +/- 50,000                 +/- 12.2                                   
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Processing                                                                
    ==========                                                                
                                                                              
    Voyager EDR&apos;s undergo the following processing in order to produce        
    these 48 second averaged summary data:                                    
                                                                              
      * Read EDR                                                              
      * Unpack header block (rec. id, s/c id, tel. mode, FDS counts,          
        data flags)                                                           
      * Convert selected time tags to integer time (yy/ddd/hh:mm:ss.fff)      
      * Unpack sub-header block (MAG status words, plasma data)               
      * Unpack science block (MAG counts)                                     
      * Convert counts to gammas                                              
      * Apply sensor and boom alignment matrices                              
      * Rotate (optional) 1.92 second averages while averaging detail         
        gammas to create 1.92 second averages                                 
      * Average 1.92 second data to 9.6 seconds, then 9.6 second data to      
        48 seconds                                                            
      * Write Summary record                                                  
                                                                              
    Counts are measured onboard using 12 bit words that may represent         
    values ranging from 0-4096. Integer counts are converted to magnetic      
    field units (gammas) by subtracting a zero offset, from the measured      
    MAG value and multiplying this difference by the sensitivity of the       
    instrument.                                                               
                                                                              
                                                                              
    Data                                                                      
    ====                                                                      
                                                                              
    The data files are given in ASCII, fixed field width, comma               
    delimited tables. The record structure is described in the following      
    table:                                                                    
                                                                              
    --------------------------------------------------------------------      
    48 Second Heliographic (RTN) Coordinates                                  
    --------------------------------------------------------------------      
    Column   Type    Description &lt;units&gt;                                      
    --------------------------------------------------------------------      
    time     a23     spacecraft event time (UT) of the sample in the          
                     format: yyyy-mm-ddThh:mm:ss.sss                          
    sclk     a12     spacecraft clock in the format:                          
                     MOD65536:MOD60:FDS-LINE                                  
    mag_id   i1      magnetometer ID (1 = LFM, 2 = HFM)                       
    Br       f9.3    average of detail magnetic field R component in nT       
    Bt       f9.3    average of detail magnetic field T component in nT       
    Bn       f9.3    average of detail magnetic field N component in nT       
    Bmag     f9.3    magnitude of the averaged magnetic field components      
                     in nT                                                    
    avg_Bmag f9.3    average of the magnetic field magnitude over the         
                     averaging interval in nT                                 
    Delta    f7.3    spacecraft centered heliographic magnetic field          
                     latitude in degrees: Delta = asin(Bn/Bmag)               
    Lambda   f7.3    spacecraft centered heliographic magnetic field          
                     longitude in degrees: Lambda = atan(Bt/Br)               
    rms_Br   f8.3    root-mean-square deviation of Br over the averagi</Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG1-S-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48.0SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG1-S-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48.0SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG1-S-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48.0SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG1-S-MAG-4-SUMM-HGCOORDS-48.0SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager1/MAG</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1980-11-10T00:00:34.92</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1980-11-20T23:59:47.06</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT48.0S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Saturn</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
