<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema  http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_7_0.xsd">
   <Version>2.7.0</Version>
   <Instrument>
      <ResourceID>spase://HamSCI/Instrument/PSWS/Magnetometer/AB4EJ_G1DRF</ResourceID>
      <NamingAuthority>HamSCI</NamingAuthority>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>HamSCI PSWS Magnetometer (RM3100-based 3-axis Sensor) at AB4EJ G1DRF station</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>Magnetometer at AB4EJ G1DRF station</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2025-07-30T12:00:00</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The HamSCI PSWS Magnetometer is a low-cost, three-axis magnetic field instrument developed as part of the Personal Space Weather Station (PSWS) project. Based on commercial off-the-shelf magneto-inductive sensor technology such as the RM3100, the system is designed to provide continuous ground-based measurements of geomagnetic field strength and direction with a resolution better than 10 nT at a 1 Hz sample rate. The magnetometer network aims to enhance spatial coverage at mid- and high-latitudes for monitoring space weather effects, including large-scale ionospheric currents and geomagnetically induced currents (GICs). Deployed in a densely spaced configuration (target spacing ~50–100 miles), the PSWS magnetometers complement HF radio observations and provide new scientific capabilities for studying ionospheric responses to solar and atmospheric drivers. The system operates on Raspberry Pi platforms using open-source data acquisition software and contributes to both operational and scientific space weather monitoring.
             
The AB4EJ G1DRF station is located at 33.375ºN, 87.538ºW. Instrument type is Magnetometer.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nathaniel.Frissell</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.Engelke</PersonID>
            <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Kornyanat.Hozumi</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Experiment</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>HamSCI Personal Space Weather Station (PSWS)</InvestigationName>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>2022-11-22T00:00:00</StartDate>
         <Note>Data were stopped on 2023-11-29.</Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://HamSCI/Observatory/HamSCI</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument>
</Spase>
