<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/DoubleStar</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>DoubleStar</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-10-08T10:47:08Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This description has been obtained from Section 3.13 of the Users Guide to the Double Star Science Data System, DSP-IWF-TN-0002. 

The collaboration between the National Commission of Science and Technology of the People's Republic of China and ESA started in 1980 when the first agreement to exchange scientific and technical information on space programme and projects of mutual interest was signed. In 1992, the Chinese Academy of Science signed an agreement with ESA to collaborate on the Cluster mission. In September 1999, the ESA Director-General was invited by the Administrator of the China National Space Administration (CNSA) to discuss the collaboration on the Double Star programme. In May 2001, ESA approved funding for collaboration and recommended the co-operation with China. Finally, on 9 July 2001, an agreement to develop a joint mission - designated 'Double Star' - between ESA and CNSA was signed at ESA Headquarters in Paris, France, by the ESA Director General, Antonio Rodotà, and Luan Enjie, Administrator of CNSA.
Double Star follows in the footsteps of ESA's Cluster mission by studying the effects of the Sun on the Earth's environment. Conducting joint studies with Cluster and Double Star should increase the overall scientific return from both missions. A key aspect of Europe's participation in the Double Star project is the inclusion of eight instruments, seven of which are identical to those currently flying on the four Cluster spacecraft. This reuse of instruments has many advantages for both European and Chinese scientists. A further eight experiments are provided by Chinese institutes. The schedule of Double Star will allow a considerable period of simultaneous operations with ESA's Cluster mission.
Double Star is the first mission launched by China to explore the Earth's magnetosphere.
As its name suggests, Double Star involves two satellites - each designed, developed, launched, and operated by the Chinese National Space Administration.
The first of the two spacecraft (TC-1), the 'equatorial' one, was launched on 29 December 2003 at 19:06 UT. The second, 'polar', spacecraft (TC-2) was launched on 25 July 2004 at 07:05 UT. The acronym 'TC' stands for 'Tan Ce' in Pinyin and means 'exploration measurement'.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Christophe.Philippe.Escoubet</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
    <OperatingSpan>
      <StartDate>2003-12-29T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
    </OperatingSpan>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
