<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/GEOS-Ground-mobile-station</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GEOS ground mobile station</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-06-09T16:56:58Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Ground based measurements: Ultra low frequency magnetic field components (0.05 - 11.5 Hz), auroral fluctuations and DC magnetic field in coordination with GEOS-1 and GEOS-2.

A mobile station was developed under a contract with the National Institute of Astronomy and Geophysics. One of the main objectives was to provide a complete set of ground data in relation to experiments based on satellites, rockets or balloons. In particular, the station could be placed at the foot of the line of force crossing a geostationary satellite such as GEOS. To do this, the station was equipped with basic optical and magnetic instruments necessary for magnetospheric and ionospheric studies. 
The mobile station was equiped with basic optical and magnetic instruments required for magnetospheric and ionospheric studies:
* DC/AC photometer (5577 Å- field of view 6°x6°)
* Riometer operating at 30.1 MHz
* Fluxgate magnetometer
* Fluxmeters 0.003 - 1 Hz and 0.1 - 10 Hz
* ELF receiver 30-600 Hz
* VLF receiver 0.3 - 10 kHz
Several campaigns have taken place at different locations (geographic coordinates):
    HUSAFELL (Lat: 64.40 N, Lon: 20.80 W) - data started July 4, 1977, and finished September 22, 1977.
    KITDALEN  (Lat: 69.21 N, Lon: 20.18 E)  - data cover two periods: from January 29, 1980, to March 21, 1980, and from January 31, 1981, to March 28, 1981.
    SKIBOTN   (Lat: 69.35 N, Lon: 20.36 E)  - data started January 15, 1982, to March 07, 1982.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Nicole.Cornilleau-Wehrlin</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/CDPP.general.contact</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
    <OperatingSpan>
      <StartDate>1977-07-04T00:00:00</StartDate>
      <StopDate>1982-03-07T00:00:00</StopDate>
    </OperatingSpan>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
