<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/Interball-Tail</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Interball-Tail</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2022-04-28T17:46:51Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The TAIL PROBE with its subsatellite was launched on 3 August 1995 to the elongated elliptical orbit with the inclination of 65 degrees and apogee of 200 000 km. These satellites study the interactions of the Solar Wind with the Magnetopause and the outer regions of the magnetosphere. Specific aims is to study the active plasma processes within the tail where powerful currents, substorms and other large-scale non-linear magnetospheric phenomena originate. The separation in this pair will change from less than 100 km, allowing to study the small-scale wave and plasma structures at the boundaries, till about 1-2 RE (the Earth's radii) to study large plasma structures in the tail. 

Interball Tail Probe : On-board Experiments

PLASMA

SKA-1
a) Measurements of three-dimensional distribution of ions in the energy range 50 รท 5000 eV/Q
b) Measurements of energy spectra of ions with M/Q selection (M = 1, 2, 4, 16) in the energy range 5-40 ke V/Q in the antisolar direction
O.VAISBERG, A.LEIBOV, L.AVANOV, IKI Moscow Russia

ELECTRON
3-D measurements of the electron component of the plasma (10 eV - 26 keV)
J.A.SAUVAUD, CESR Toulouse France  - O.VAISBERG, N.BORODKOVA, IKI Moscow, Russia

PROMICS-3
Ion composition (M = 1-32) and 3-D energy distribution (0.01-30 ke V/Q)
I.SANDAHL, IRF, Kiruna, Sweden - N.PISSARENKO, E.DUBININ IKI, Moscow, Russia - H.KOSKINEN, T.PULKKINEN, FMI Helsinki, Finland

VDP
Omnidirectional fast measurements of integral ion or electron fluxes and their direction
Ya.SAFRANKOVA, Z.NEMECEK Charles Univ., Prague Czech. Republic - G.ZASTENKER, A.FEDOROV IKI, Moscow, Russia

AMEI-2
Energy spectra of H+, He+, He++ O+ and heavier ion in the range 0.1-8 ke V/Q at all directions.
R.KOLEVA STIL, Sofia, Bulgaria - V.SMIRNOV IKI, Moscow, Russia

MONITOR-3
Measurements of the solar wind ion fluxes and energy-angular distributions of H+ and He++ around the Sun direction with high time resolution.
Z.NEMECEK, Ya.SAFRANKOVA, Charles Univ., Prague, Czech. Republic - A.FEDOROV, G.ZASTENKER IKI, Moscow, Russia

CORAL
Angular/energy ion distributions at all directions in energy range 0.05-25 ke V/Q
R.JIMENEZ INTERCOSMOS, Havana, Cuba - O.VAISBERG, Yu.YERMOLAEV IKI, Moscow, Russia

ALPHA-3
Thermal plasma ion flux E &lt; 25 eV/Q
V.BEZRUKIKH IKI, Moscow, Russia

WAVES AND FIELDS

ASPI
Fields and waves consortium (Analysis of Spectra of Plasma waves and Instabilities, including MIF-M, OPERA, ADS, IFPE, FGM-I, KEM-3, PRAM).
S.KLIMOV, S.ROMANOV IKI, Moscow, Russia

OPERA
Three-component electric field fluctuations in the range 0-50 kHz including spectral analysis. 
FGM-1 magnetic field data acquisition and processing.
E.AMATA CNR/IFSI, Frascati, Italy - S.SAVIN IKI, Moscow, Russia - R.GRARD SSD/ESTEC, ESA - J.L.RAUCH LPCE (now LPC2E), Orleans, France

MIF-M
DC/AC magnetic field, 3 components, 0-64 Hz, 1 component, 1 Hz - 40 kHz. Data are processed for SSNI by PRAM.
S.ROMANOV, M.NOZDRACHEV IKI, Moscow, Russia - V.KOREPANOV SDD ASU, Lvov, Ukraine

IFPE
Measurements of ion and electron flux fluctuations in the range 0.1 Hz - 1 kHz, the data are processed for SSNI by PRAM.
J.BUCHNER MPE-A, Berlin, Germany - S.ROMANOV IKI, Moscow, Russia

ADS
Nine-channel spectra-analyzer and cross-correlator, two-component measurements of current fluctuations, 0.1 Hz - 40 kHz.
J.JUCHNIEWICZ Space Res. Center, Warsaw, Poland - L.WOOLLISCROFT Departm. of Contr. Engineering Sheffield Univ, Sheffield, UK - S.KLIMOV IKI, Moscow, Russia - V.KOREPANOV SDD ASU, Lvov, Ukraine

FGM-1
Measurements of 3D magnetic field 0-25 Hz in the range 0.25-256 nT. OPERA acquires and processes the data for SSNI.
J.RUSTENBACH MPE-A Berlin, Germany - S.SAVIN IKI, Moscow, Russia

KEM-3 (aboard subsatellite)
Electric (0.1 Hz - 400 kHz) and magnetic (1-50 kHz) fields, two-component measurements of current fluctuations 0.1 Hz - 40 kHz.
P.TRISKA, F.JIRICEK Inst. Atm. Phys. CAS, Prague, Czech., Republic - S.KLIMOV IKI, Moscow, Russia

PRAM
DC/AC magnetic field from MIF-M, ion and electron flux from IFPE data processor and RF-15-1 data processor.
S.ROMANOV (ASPI), O.LIKIN (RF-15-I) IKI, Moscow, Russia - F.FARNIK Astr. Inst. CAS, Ondrejov, Czech. Republic.

FM-3I
Magnetic field (three components). Range : 0.2-200 nT,  0.5-1000nT. Band : 0-10 Hz
M.NOZDRACHEV IKI, Moscow, Russia - V.STYAZHKIN IZMIRAN, Troitsk, Russia

AKR-X
Radioemission in the range 100 kHz - 1.5 MHz
L.FISCHER Komensky University, Bratislava, Slovakia - V.GRIGORIEVA Astron. Inst. of Moscow University, Moscow, Russia

ENERGETIC PARTICLES

SKA-2
Charged energetic particles (Ee = 40-200 keV, Ei = 0.05-150 keV) composition and anizotropy
E.MOROZOVA, E.BUDNIK, IKI, Moscow, Russia - S.FISCHER Astronomical Institute, Prague, Czech. Republic - E.SARRIS University of Thrace, Xanthi, Greece

DOK-2
Energy spectra, angular distributions and time variations of electrons (E = 15-400 keV) and ions (E = 20-1000 keV)
K.KUDELA Institute of Experim. Physics. SAS, Kosice, Slovakia - V.LUTSENKO IKI, Moscow, Russia - E.SARRIS, University of Thrace, Xanthi, Greece

RF-15-I
Solar X-ray burst spectra and time profile measurements in the range 2-240 keV, The data are processed by PRAM.
O.LIKIN IKI, Moscow, Russia - F.FARNIK Astr. Inst. CAS, Ondrejov, Czech. Republic - J.SYLVESTER Space Res. Center, Wroclaw, Poland

SOSNA-3
Dosimetric measurements
V.BENGIN, V.PETROV IMBP, Moscow, Russia - S.KUZNETSOV Moscow University, Moscow, Russia

RKI-2
Ionizing radiation (5, 15, 40, 100, 500 MeV) and UV radiation from the Sun.
T.KAZACHEVSKAYA IPG, Moscow, Russia

SERVICE SYSTEMS

BNK, BNTR, BNTS
Commutation blocks
T.LESSINA IKI, Moscow, Russia

SSNI
Telemetry system
L.CHESALIN IKI, Moscow, Russia

STO
Transmitter for the interferometric measurements
J.VOITA Inst. Atm. Phys. CAS, Prague, Czech. Republic - G.TEREKHIN IKI, Moscow, Russia

BNS
Attitude processor
J.KLAS Inst. Atm. Phys. CAS, Prague, Czech. Republic - N.EISMONT, Yu.LISSAKOV IKI, Moscow, Russia</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Lev.Zelenyi</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/Interball</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
    <OperatingSpan>
      <StartDate>1995-08-03T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
	  <StopDate>2000-10-16T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
    </OperatingSpan>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
