<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_4_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.4.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://CNES/Observatory/CDPP-Archive/ISEE1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE1</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-10-08T10:47:08Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>ISEE-1 and ISEE-2 Mission

The ISEE program (International Sun Earth Explorer) was a joint mission between NASA and ESA, part of the IMS (International Magnetospheric Study). It was based on 3 spacecrafts and aiming at a better understanding of the Solar Wind-Earth Magnetosphere interaction. ISEE-1 built by NASA, and ISEE-2, built by ESA, were launched simultaneously on October 22, 1977 on the same Earth orbit with a close and controlled separation distance between the two spacecrafts, ranging from about 50 and 5000 km. This allowed for the first time to discriminate between space and time ambiguities induced by single spacecraft observations of thin and moving magnetospheric boundaries such as the bow shock, the magnetopause and the tail current sheet. The ISEE-3 spacecraft, built by NASA and launched on August 12, 1978 was placed at the L1 Lagrange Point, where it provided the characteristics of the Solar Wind, 235 Earth Radii upstream of the Earth, about one hour before it impacts the Earth Magnetosphere studied by the ISEE-1-2 pair.
ISEE-1 (340 kg) et ISEE-2 ( 166 kg ), both spin stabilized, were inserted in a 763 km - 137500 km (22Re) orbit, with an inclination of -30,38B0 with respect to the equatorial plane and an orbital period of 57h. This allowed to their suite of complementary instruments, to frequently sample the various magnetospheric regions and boundaries plasmasphere, magnetopause, bow shock, magnetospheric tail, study their formation, characteristics, dynamic, and plasma mechanisms which operate and study the structure of the solar wind close to the Earth.

This mission was the first one to provide an estimation of the magnetopause width. ISEE-1 scientific payload comprised a suite of 13 instruments, down linking their data through 2 telemetry modes,

    High at 16384 bit/s (about one orbit over 5)
    low at 4096 bit/s

whereas ISEE-2 payload included 8 instruments with high and low downlink rates of 8192 and 2048 bit/s respectively. Initially designed for a 3 years lifetime, the ISEE-1&amp;2 mission ended almost 10 years after its launch, when both spacecraft re-entered the atmosphere on September 26, 1987. 

References :
   NASA
   Durney, A. C., and K. W. Ogilvie, Introduction to the ISEE mission, Space Sci. Rev., 22, 679, Sept. 1978
   Ogilvie, K. W., T. von Rosenvinge and A. C. Durney, International Sun Earth Explorer-A three spacecraft program, Science, 198, No. 4313, 131-138, Oct. 1977
   Ogilvie, K. W., T. von Rosenvinge and A. C. Durney, Descriptions of Experimental Investigations and Instruments for the ISEE Spacecraft, IEEE Trans. Geosci. Electr. GE-16, 151</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://CNES/Person/CDPP-Archive/Keith.Ogilvie</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
    </Location>
    <OperatingSpan>
      <StartDate>1977-10-22T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
      <StopDate>1987-09-26T00:00:00Z</StopDate>
    </OperatingSpan>
  </Observatory>
</Spase>
