<Spase xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_8.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.8</Version>
  <DisplayData>
    <ResourceID>spase://NASA/DisplayData/MMS/FIELDS/MagneticField/QL.PNG.PT120M</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>MMS Fields 2 hour Combined Magnetic Field QuickLook plots</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>fields_mms_bfield</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2020-07-07T19:48:34Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
This dataset contains PNG format plots of 2 hour duration Magnetic Field QuickLook time series (Btot, and Bx, By, Bz in GSM-DMPA coordinates and Bx, By, Bz in DMPA coordinates*) and 3-component survey spectrograms for MMS1, MMS2, MMS3, MMS4 from the Fields suite on the MMS spacecraft.

Also available within the same directory are 6-hour, 12-hour, and 24-hour plots. Magnetic field quicklook spectrograms also appear in the individual spacecraft summary plots all_mms1_summ,  all_mms2_summ, all_mms3_summ, and all_mms4_summ.   

At the top of each image is a title and a status bar indicating operational status for Fast and Burst mode over the time period of the plots. Immediately above the time labels on the horizontal axis are ephemeris data: Cartesian GSE coordinates and radial distance of the MMS1 spacecraft in units of Earth radii.
-------
(*)From the FGM Data Products Guide:

Quicklook data have the best available calibration at the time of downlink applied and are not intended for scientific analysis.

Quicklook provides time series plots in .png format of FGM data, which is derived from either DFG or AFG.

Magnetic field data is provided in Despun Major Principal Axis of inertia (DMPA) coordinates, which is considered to be a ‘near-GSE’ coordinate system. That is, no attitude data has been applied, other than to despin using the on-board sun pulse times. The DMPA Z-axis is the aligned with the Major Principal Axis (MPA). In nominal operations, the MPA is maintained to be within 3 degrees of the GSE Z-axis (ecliptic normal). Thus, within the Region of Interest (ROI), DMPA should be within 3 degrees of alignment with true GSE coordinates. The MPA can
be assumed to fixed in inertial space and aligned with the Angular Momentum vector, except in the presence of nutation. For the first year since launch, nutation has been observed to be minimal, and generally damped within hours after spacecraft maneuvers.
In addition, a GSE to GSM transformation is applied to the DMPA data to yield data in what is termed GSM-DMPA coordinates. For a formal discussion of coordinate systems, see the MMS Project Coordinate System and Alignment Document (461-SYS-SPEC-0115C, or most recent version).

</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>The terms for distribution and use of the MMS data products are specified in the NASA Heliophysics Science Data Management Policy document, and are summarized here in terms of the MMS mission. These guidelines govern both the production and distribution of scientific data sets by the MMS program, and also use of the MMS data by the science community and general public, and are summarized below.

Users should use QuickLook data plots for event browsing, and not for scientific analysis or publication without express consent of the PI and relevant Lead Co-Investigators.

1. MMS-SMART data products are open to all scientists and the public (Users).

2. There are no proprietary periods associated with any of the MMS-SMART data products.

3. Users shall have timely access to the scientifically useful data and analysis tools that are equivalent to the level that the MMS-SMART science working team uses.

4. Users should contact the MMS-SMART Principal Investigator (PI) and the relevant lead co-investigators of the instrument or modeling group early in an analysis project to consult on the appropriate use of instrument data or model results.

5. Users who wish to publish results derived from MMS data should directly involve the MMS-SMART PI and/or Instrument Leads and team members as appropriate in the analysis and are encouraged to offer co-authorship. Co-authorship may be declined.

6. Users should heed the caveats of investigators as to the interpretation and limitations of data or model results. All important caveats should be included in the publication, even if co-authorship is declined. Data and model version numbers should also be specified.

7. Users should acknowledge the sources of data used in all publications, presentations, and reports. Appropriate acknowledgement to institutions, personnel, and funding agencies should be given.

8. Users should provide the MMS-SMART PI and/or instrument Lead CoIs a copy of each manuscript that uses MMS-SMART data upon submission of that manuscript for consideration of publication. Upon publication, the citation should be transmitted to the PI and any other providers of data.

9. Users should widely distribute, to interested parties, their conference abstracts, presentations, and publications.

10. Users should make tools of general utility and/or value-added data products widely available to the community, and to notify the MMS-SMART PI of such utilities or products, having clearly labeled the product as being different from an original MMS-SMART produced data product.

References:

NASA Heliophysics Science Data Management Policy, version 1.1, April 12, 2009,
https://hpde.gsfc.nasa.gov/Heliophysics_Data_Policy_2009Apr12.pdf

NASA MMS Science Data Management Plan: SwRI Document 10160.18-PDMP-01
</Acknowledgement>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.L.Burch</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.Ergun</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Olivier.Le.Contel</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.T.Russell</PersonID>
                <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
            <Contact>
                <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Leonard.N.Garcia</PersonID>
                <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
            <InformationURL>
                <Name>The Magnetospheric Multiscale (MMS) Mission home page at Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC)</Name>
                <URL>https://mms.gsfc.nasa.gov/</URL>
                <Description>The Magnetospheric Multiscale (MMS) Mission Home Page hosted by the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC).</Description>
</InformationURL>
        <PriorID>spase://VSPO/DisplayData/MMS/FIELDS/MagneticField/QL.PNG.PT120M</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/UCOLO/LASP/MMS_SDC</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
 <Name>MMS Science Data Center QuickLook Plots</Name>
 <URL>https://lasp.colorado.edu/mms/sdc/public/plots/#/quicklook/</URL>
 <ProductKey>fields_mms_bfield</ProductKey>
 <Description>Web interface to plot viewer. Interface allows choice of plot type, date, plot duraction (24 hour, 12 hour, 2 hour) and the ability to step through the plots. There is also a direct download link.</Description>
</AccessURL>
      <Format>PNG</Format>
      <Encoding>None</Encoding>
</AccessInformation>
    <AccessInformation>
      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/UCOLO/LASP/MMS_SDC</RepositoryID>
      <Availability>Online</Availability>
      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
      <AccessURL>
 <Name>MMS Science Data Center File Browser</Name>
 <URL>https://lasp.colorado.edu/mms/sdc/public/about/browse-wrapper/</URL>
 <ProductKey>/mms/sdc/public/data/sdc/ql/fields_mms_bfield</ProductKey>
 <Description>Interface to the MMS SDC directory tree.</Description>
</AccessURL>
      <Format>PNG</Format>
      <Encoding>None</Encoding>
</AccessInformation>
    <ProcessingLevel>Calibrated</ProcessingLevel>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/1/FIELDS/ADP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/1/FIELDS/DSP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/1/FIELDS/SDP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/1/FIELDS/SCM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/1/FIELDS/FGM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/2/FIELDS/ADP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/2/FIELDS/DSP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/2/FIELDS/SDP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/2/FIELDS/SCM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/2/FIELDS/FGM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/3/FIELDS/ADP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/3/FIELDS/DSP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/3/FIELDS/SDP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/3/FIELDS/SCM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/3/FIELDS/FGM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/4/FIELDS/ADP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/4/FIELDS/DSP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/4/FIELDS/SDP</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/4/FIELDS/SCM</InstrumentID>
    <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/MMS/4/FIELDS/FGM</InstrumentID>
    <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>Waves.Passive</MeasurementType>
    <MeasurementType>Spectrum</MeasurementType>
        <TemporalDescription>
            <TimeSpan>
                <StartDate>2015-03-17T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
                <RelativeStopDate>-P2D</RelativeStopDate>
</TimeSpan>
</TemporalDescription>
    <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
    <DisplayCadence>PT120M</DisplayCadence>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Magnetotail</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.RadiationBelt</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.EquatorialRegion</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Plasmasphere</ObservedRegion>
    <ObservedRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservedRegion>
    <Caveats>Users should use QuickLook data plots for event browsing, and not for scientific analysis or publication without express consent of the PI and relevant Lead Co-Investigators.</Caveats>
    <!-- Keywords pertaining to the data presentation -->
    <Keyword>Dynamic Spectrogram</Keyword>
    <Keyword>Spectrogram</Keyword>
    <Parameter>
      <Name>Power Spectral Density</Name>
      <Description>Spectrograms for each of the 4 MMS spacecraft. Displayed frequency is in units of Hz.</Description>
      <Caveats/>
      <Units>nT^2*Hz^-1</Units>
      <Wave>
        <WaveType>PlasmaWaves</WaveType>
        <WaveQuantity>ACMagneticField</WaveQuantity>
        <FrequencyRange>
          <SpectralRange>RadioFrequency</SpectralRange>
          <Low>0.0</Low>
          <High>6</High>
          <Units>kHz</Units>
</FrequencyRange>
</Wave>
</Parameter>
    <Extension/>
</DisplayData>
</Spase>
