<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema file:/C:/Projects/Voyager/spase-2_2_2.xsd">
<Version>2.2.2</Version>
<NumericalData>
               <ResourceID>spase://VMO/NumericalData/Voyager2/MAG/Neptune/PT12S</ResourceID>
               <ResourceHeader>
                      <ResourceName>Voyager 2 Neptune Mag Resampled Summary NLS Coords 12-s V1.0</ResourceName>
                      <ReleaseDate>2017-01-19T10:00:00.00</ReleaseDate>
                      <Description>                                        
                                                                              
  Data Set Overview                                                           
  =================                                                           
    The Voyager magnetometer investigation (P.I.- Norman F. Ness) makes       
    available archival data through the National Space Science Data Center    
    (NSSDC) located at NASA/GSFC as well as through the Planetary Data System 
    (PDS) and other channels. The primary archive format, referred to as a    
    &apos;summary tape&apos; or &apos;conjoint summary tape&apos; has been used consistently      
    since the beginning of the Voyager mission to the outer planets (1977).   
    This format makes available magnetometer observations, supplementary      
    engineering and ephemeris data in one data file, and it is one product    
    of Voyager magnetometer routine data processing. Users are referred to    
    the summary format data for all data requirements with one exception:     
    Neptune encounter high field observations. Neptune close approach         
    observations are archived separately and in a different format from       
    that with which many are familiar. This high-field archive is             
    described here.                                                           
                                                                              
    The special demands of the Neptune encounter flyby exceeded (finally)     
    the capabilities of the routine data processing system conceived and      
    implemented in the mid 1970&apos;s. As a result, it was necessary to implement 
    an additional data processing system with which the near-encounter, high  
    field magnetometer observations were processed. The data products avail-  
    able with this new data processing system are not available in the same   
    format as the standard Voyager magnetometer observations; thus the need   
    for a separate archive and a new format description. We appreciate the    
    desirability of a consistent archive format, but find no reasonable       
    alternative to the present solution. We expect, however, that users       
    interested in near encounter observations will find this new format both  
    useful and easy to assimilate.                                            
                                                                              
    The magnetic fields investigation on Voyager carries a total of four      
    tri-axial ring core fluxgate magnetometers: two identical high field      
    magnetometers mounted on the spacecraft body (HFM&apos;s) and two identical    
    low field magnetometers (LFM&apos;s) arranged on a 13 m boom (Behannon et      
    al., 1977). The two LFM&apos;s automatically step through a total of eight     
    dynamic ranges (ranges 0 through 7) in response to changes in the         
    measured field, starting with a nominal dynamic range of  8 nT, and       
    increasing to a nominal dynamic range of  50,000 nT. The two HFM&apos;s each   
    operate in two dynamic ranges (ranges 0 and 1) with nominal values of     
    50,000 nT and  200,000 nT. In the Neptune encounter mode, each            
    magnetometer was sampled periodically with a temporal resolution of       
    between 0.600 s and 0.060 s, and analog-to-digital converted with 12 bit  
    resolution for subsequent telemetry. The magnitude of the maximum         
    observed field at Neptune (approximately 10,000 nT) was sufficiently      
    large that data from all four of the magnetometers proved useful.         
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Parameters                                                                  
  ==========                                                                  
                                                                              
    Derived Parameters                                                        
    ------------------                                                        
      Sampling Parameter Name             : time                              
      Sampling Parameter Resolution       : 12.0 seconds                      
      Minimum Sampling Parameter          : 19770820120000.000000             
      Maximum Sampling Parameter          : UNK                               
      Sampling Parameter Interval         : 12.0 seconds                      
      Minimum Available Sampling Interval : 0.060000 seconds                  
      Data Set Parameter Name             : magnetic field vector             
      Noise Level                         : 0.006000 nT                       
      Data Set Parameter Unit             : nanotesla                         
                                                                              
      Magentic field vector: A derived parameter which combines the 3         
      orthogonal magnetic field component measurements.                       
                                                                              
    Measured Parameters                                                       
    -------------------                                                       
      Magentic field component: A measured parameter equaling the             
      magnetic field strength (e.g. in nanoteslas) along a particular         
      axis direction. Usually the three orthogonal axis components are        
      measured by three different sensors.                                    
                                                                              
                                                                              
  Data                                                                        
  ====                                                                        
 1) MAGNETOMETER DATA PRODUCT                                                 
                                                                              
  ctime - Decimal seconds past 1966-01-02T00:00:00 (an internal time format)  
  SCET  - Spacecraft event time PDS/ISO standard time format.                 
    B_R - Magnetic field vector radial component in units of nanotesla;       
          planetocentric right-handed spherical coordinate system.            
B_THETA - Magnetic field vector theta component, units nanotesla.             
  B_PHI - Magnetic field vector phi component, units nanotesla.               
                                                                              
    The vector magnetic field is rendered in a right handed spherical         
    coordinate system in which the angles THETA and PHI are the usual         
    polar angles, with THETA (colatitude) measured from the axis of           
    rotation and PHI increasing in the direction of rotation. The             
    orientation of Neptune&apos;s pole is specified by a right ascension           
    of 298.90 and declination of 42.84 at the time of the encounter, as       
    given in the Jet Propulsion Laboratory&apos;s distribution of physical         
    constants dated 11/06/89. Planetary longitudes are based on a             
    16.11 hour rotation period (Warwick et al., 1989) adopted by the          
    Voyager Project shortly after the encounter. The zero longitude is        
    defined by the requirement that the West Longitude of the spacecraft      
    at 0356 SCET day 237 (near closest approach) be 167.7 NLS; West           
    Longitudes of the Neptune Longitude System (NLS) are simply related       
    to the angle PHI:                                                         
                                                                              
                      WLONG = 360. - PHI   (degrees)                          
                                                                      </Description>
                      <Contact>
                             <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Todd.A.King</PersonID>
                             <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
                     </Contact>
                      <InformationURL>
                             <Name>VG2-N-MAG-4-SUMM-NLSCOORDS-12SEC-V1.0</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/data/VG2-N-MAG-4-SUMM-NLSCOORDS-12SEC-V1.0/AAREADME.TXT</URL>
                             <Description>The document describing the contents of the collection.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </InformationURL>
              </ResourceHeader>
               <AccessInformation>
                      <RepositoryID>spase://SMWG/Repository/PDS/PPI</RepositoryID>
                      <Availability>Online</Availability>
                      <AccessRights>Open</AccessRights>
                      <AccessURL>
                             <Name>PDS/PPI</Name>
                             <URL>http://pds-ppi.igpp.ucla.edu/search/view/?f=yes&amp;id=pds://PPI/VG2-N-MAG-4-SUMM-NLSCOORDS-12SEC-V1.0</URL>
                             <ProductKey>VG2-N-MAG-4-SUMM-NLSCOORDS-12SEC-V1.0</ProductKey>
                             <Description>This collection is archived with NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System.</Description>
                             <Language>En</Language>
                     </AccessURL>
                      <Format>Text.ASCII</Format>
                      <Acknowledgement>NASA&apos;s Planetary Plasma Interactions (PPI) Node of the Planetary Data System (PDS) and the P.I. for the data.</Acknowledgement>
              </AccessInformation>
               <InstrumentID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Voyager2/MAG</InstrumentID>
               <MeasurementType>MagneticField</MeasurementType>
               <TemporalDescription>
                      <TimeSpan>
                             <StartDate>1989-08-24T18:00:00.00</StartDate>
                             <StopDate>1989-08-26T08:19:48.00</StopDate>
                     </TimeSpan>
                      <Cadence>PT12S</Cadence>
              </TemporalDescription>
               <ObservedRegion>Neptune</ObservedRegion>
       </NumericalData>
</Spase>
